<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Deep Dives on Ruchil Sharma</title>
    <link>/tags/deep-dives/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Deep Dives on Ruchil Sharma</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/deep-dives/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Retro App Breakdown</title>
      <link>/posts/retro-app-breakdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/retro-app-breakdown/</guid>
      <description>I have started to breakdown mobile apps and make sense of why something exists within an app and what could have been better. Last weekend, I went through Retro App. You can go through the breakdown here . If you want to go through the onboarding experience, you can do so here.
A couple of interesting observations that I came across while going through the app:
Unlike Instagram’s social graph, Retro app has purposefully focused on restricting what you can see and share with your friends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ID by amoamo Breakdown</title>
      <link>/posts/id-by-amo-amo-breakdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/id-by-amo-amo-breakdown/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been keeping track of the new app in town ID by amoamo and found its onboarding and user experience really refreshing as compared to most other social media apps. I even Tweeted about it which was caught up by some of their team members.
This was quite innovative by @amoamoamo app. Explaining why you should invite your friends while humanising the experience . Felt refreshing pic.twitter.com/MqwuzeIwWF
&amp;mdash; @roohchill (@roohchill) January 14, 2024 You can see the breakdown here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Dives - Spotify</title>
      <link>/posts/spotify-deep-dive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/spotify-deep-dive/</guid>
      <description>Turn up the music - Spotify’s Teardown</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Dives - Maker DAO</title>
      <link>/posts/maker-dao-deep-dive/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/maker-dao-deep-dive/</guid>
      <description>Maker DAO is a well-known protocol that has been a pioneer in the decentralized finance (DeFi) space. In 2021, Maker Foundation took a significant step towards decentralization by dissolving itself and spinning up a DAO. As someone who has delved deep into the inner workings of Maker DAO over the past two weeks, I&amp;rsquo;ve gathered valuable insights and resources that will help anyone start contributing to Maker DAO.
Major Events</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
