<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Web3 on Ruchil Sharma</title>
    <link>/categories/web3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Web3 on Ruchil Sharma</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/categories/web3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What’s wrong with voting only decision making in DAO&#39;s</title>
      <link>/posts/whats-wrong-with-voting-only-decision-making-in-daos/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/whats-wrong-with-voting-only-decision-making-in-daos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Grant programs are one of the best ways to attract high-quality contributors to your ecosystem. There’s no denying their potential impact. However, many ecosystems fail to realize that if not implemented well, these programs can lead to the loss of key contributors. In an attention scare World, where abundant opportunities exist, it is crucial for ecosystems to provide the best experience in order to attract and retain high-quality contributors. I’ve personally faced the following problems as a DAO contributor:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deep Dives - Maker DAO</title>
      <link>/posts/deep-dives---maker-dao-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/deep-dives---maker-dao-copy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dabblish.substack.com/p/deep-dives-maker-dao&#34;&gt;Deep Dives - Maker DAO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deep Dives - Spotify</title>
      <link>/posts/deep-dives---spotify/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/deep-dives---spotify/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dabblish.substack.com/p/turn-up-the-music-spotifys-teardown&#34;&gt;Deep Dives - Spotify&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Magic of Airdrops : Earn While Your Learn</title>
      <link>/posts/the-magic-of-airdrops--earn-while-your-learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/the-magic-of-airdrops--earn-while-your-learn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Airdrops, in my opinion, are the fastest way to educate users about your product and get user adoption. For me, the starting point was ENS. Seeing my close friends earning ~ $10k through the ENS airdrop piqued my interest into ENS and that eventually led me to buying my own ENS domain.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Simply put, an airdrop is a distribution of a crypto token or coin, usually for free, to numerous wallet addresses. But it is not as trivial as it sounds. The caveat here is that an airdrop comes with the price. For one to be eligible for receiving an airdrop, one needs to use a protocol and interact with it in a manner prescribed by the protocol. Hence, as a user, you might end up spending at least the gas price in order to be eligible for a token airdrop. As I did not own an ENS domain when ENS announced the airdrop, I was not eligible for the same.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
