<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Ruchil Sharma</title>
    <link>/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Ruchil Sharma</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Book I Keep Coming Back To</title>
      <link>/posts/scott-adams---book-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/scott-adams---book-summary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently revisited one of my favorite books: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.in/How-Fail-Almost-Everything-Still/dp/0241003709&#34;&gt;How to Fail at Almost Everything and Still Win Big&lt;/a&gt; that profoundly shaped my worldview back in 2016. Reading it again with a few more years of experience under my belt, I found myself coming across insights I had completely missed the first time around. I strongly recommend reading it. But if you’re short on time, I’ve shared my notes below, written as lifelong advice to myself, and hopefully valuable to you too.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dabbling with AI</title>
      <link>/posts/dabbling-with-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/dabbling-with-ai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A friend and I have started building AI products on the weekends to get used to the latest AI tools and their capabilities. Even though we’re just a few weeks into this (while also managing our day jobs), I’m really impressed by how advanced these tools are. Back in 2019, I dreamed of building products on my own, without relying on developers. Thanks to ser Musk and Altman, that dream is now a reality. I no longer need developers or even designers to launch the first version.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shifting Tides in Investments</title>
      <link>/posts/shifting-tides-in-investments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/shifting-tides-in-investments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;US stocks are at an all-time high, and a comparison between Big Tech P/E ratios and the S&amp;amp;P 500 does indicate that stocks might be overvalued. Both Warren Buffett and Michael Burry have started reallocating their investments from US markets to Chinese and other markets. While I&amp;rsquo;m still evaluating new positions, I&amp;rsquo;ve already started reducing my exposure to US stocks, Indian small and mid-cap stocks, which appear significantly overvalued relative to the broader index.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Things I Will Consider Before Working With Someone...</title>
      <link>/posts/things-i-will-consider-before-working-with-someone.../</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/things-i-will-consider-before-working-with-someone.../</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A short piece  on things that I will consider before working with a company or a group of individuals going forward. There are a number of additonal considerations which I&amp;rsquo;ll try to add later to this post. You may find this helpful.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leadership Quality&lt;/strong&gt;:&#xA;When joining a company, carefully evaluate the authenticity of leadership. Many founders are driven by wealth, status, need to earn respect,  or personal gain rather than genuine mission. While these motivations aren&amp;rsquo;t  wrong, ensure they align with your values. Ser Elon creates markets through conviction, but yeah, such leaders are rare.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Growth Potential&lt;/strong&gt;:&#xA;There are about 400 million companies globally. Be selective about your environment. Avoid toxic founders who run away from accountability and mistreat others. Their treatment of close associates often reveals their true character. Pay attention to patterns of blame-shifting and how they handle difficult questions.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Balancing Risk Reward&lt;/strong&gt;:&#xA;Time and energy are your most finite resources - more valuable than monetary compensation. Don&amp;rsquo;t let high salary blind you to red flags about toxic environments. Choose energizing workplaces with competent leadership over higher-paying but demoralizing situations. I would personally prefer working  with talented, well-intentioned colleagues over working with self-proclaimed, narcissistic leaders&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intentionality&lt;/strong&gt;:&#xA;Match opportunities to your current priorities. Keep your &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.paulgraham.com/identity.html&#34;&gt;identity small&lt;/a&gt; to avoid over-attachment to any role. If financial stability is your goal, consider big tech or well-funded startups. For rapid learning, early-stage startups or VC funds might be more suitable. Above all, prioritize working with trustworthy colleagues who energize rather than drain you.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s Okay to Leave Early&lt;/strong&gt;:&#xA;Treat the initial period as mutual evaluation. Despite the current employer-favored dynamic, don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to leave toxic companies early. While a formal 14-day trial period would be ideal, use your early days to assess the environment&amp;rsquo;s compatibility with your goals and values. Your potential growth in the next 6-12 months is more valuable than enduring a poor fit.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Feel free to DM me on &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/roohchill&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; if you have any thoughts on this topic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025 Personal Focus Areas </title>
      <link>/posts/2025-focus-areas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/2025-focus-areas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My key learning from recent years has been the power of focus rather than broad diversification. After some reflection, I&amp;rsquo;ve moved away from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ruchilsharma.com/posts/personal-okrs-2020/&#34;&gt;OKR framework&lt;/a&gt; in favor of defining targeted focus areas for growth. I also came up with a personal mission statement that captures my core drive. While this remains open to change, it encapsulates what pushes me forward each day. It currently stands at:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;lsquo;To inspire others and myself by challenging the status quo and create new useful things.’&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; This isn&amp;rsquo;t something to complete or check off – it&amp;rsquo;s a compass that I intend to use to guide my decisions and keep me focused during challenging times. This blog is one such attempt towards the mission statement.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 Reflections and Looking Ahead</title>
      <link>/posts/2024-reflections/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/2024-reflections/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;2024 has been a year of significant transitions and self-discovery. One of the major changes was my decision to move on from Questbook and Reclaim protocol to take time for reflection. After my longest professional stint (~4 years) as the first employee, saying goodbye wasn&amp;rsquo;t easy. I had poured everything into my role at Questbook, and remain hopeful about our funding round. I&amp;rsquo;ve now started a new chapter at Uber, and I&amp;rsquo;m excited about what lies ahead. Through these experiences, I&amp;rsquo;ve gathered several insights that I want to share - most of them advice to myself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Back to the Keyboard</title>
      <link>/posts/back-to-the-keyboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/back-to-the-keyboard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After a six-month pause filled with questions and conversations, a bit of travel, and a renewed focus on physical well-being, I’m back at the keyboard. 2024 has been that year that has made me realise that we truly live in unprecedented times. Each day brings a new reminder of just how uncertain the future is.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I will share a detailed reflection post soon. For now, I’m simply glad to be back in front of the screen. Stay tuned for more regular posts ahead. Hope you have a good time with your family during this break.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Memecoins as a way to consume news</title>
      <link>/posts/memecoins-as-a-way-to-consume-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/memecoins-as-a-way-to-consume-news/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Publicly admiting, I dismissed memecoins before the term even existed. But I am also acknowledging the fact that the recent surge in Solana memecoin activity has undeniably contributed to the current bull market. In fact, most of my friends outside the crypto sphere are now asking me which memecoin they should invest in, highlighting the significant impact memecoins have had on the crypto landscape.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Trading and investing in memecoins will become a normalized and acceptable practice, much like betting has been for years. Just as Warren Buffet made his fortune by identifying high ROI stocks early in his career, the next Warren Buffet is likely sitting behind a laptop, building the framework and developing the playbook for investing in memecoins. By the time this playbook becomes public, he/she will have already amassed a fortune. Crypto drastically accelerates the realization cycle.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Business of Selling Fear</title>
      <link>/posts/the-business-of-selling-fear/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/the-business-of-selling-fear/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“AI will take all jobs.” “You shouldn’t be in your job if you do not know y”. I see these posts everyday on X from various Twitter gurus. These statements seem to do nothing but scare folks. It feels like they’re more into fear-mongering than anything truly insightful, similar to a street-corner astrologer warning of dire consequences just to make a quick buck. Despite that, why do these gurus have massive popularity? Because tech workers already feel insecure about their futures.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retro App Breakdown</title>
      <link>/posts/retro-app-breakdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/retro-app-breakdown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On most weekends, I try to breakdown mobile apps and make sense of why something exists within an app and what could have been done better. Last week, I went through Retro App. You can go through the breakdown &lt;a href=&#34;https://notability.com/n/218p0go6p7xQHPXSip4OBJ&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; . If you want to go through the onboarding experience, you’d an do so &lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1gfdLnRxKVAYMpi4eEfIaftMN6WZiFLB_/view?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A couple of interesting things:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Unlike Instagram’s social graph, Retro app has purposefully focused on restricting what you see and share with your friends. Not any random stranger on the internet&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It pushes the users to create content or share their pictures and discourages passive viewing weeding out lurkers early in their user journey.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Should We Be More Direct?</title>
      <link>/posts/should-we-be-more-direct/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/should-we-be-more-direct/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most young folks at the start of their careers want to take up as much as they can. Time isn’t a concern at all. Well, why not? We are taught to “learn and work hard” and everything will fall in place by itself. It has to … Twitter gurus preach to prioritise long term over short term without telling you what long term means.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, what if there’s an alternative approach? By focusing on short-term objectives, we might be able to find our long-term objectives. Most individuals do not know what they want out of their lives in the long term. Figuring it out takes multiple iteration. It is a continuous exercise which easily takes a few years. Meanwhile, we spend countless hours working on things that realistically, won’t drastically change our lives. Then why do most people grind on their first jobs? They primarily want enough to pay their bills while at the same time convincing themselves that whatever they are working on is their long term goal. This usually isn’t the case. I’m excluding the very few who genuinely love their work and pursue it passionately for its own sake.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>So you want to setup your own blog</title>
      <link>/posts/so-you-want-to-setup-your-own-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/so-you-want-to-setup-your-own-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If a cool blogpost template is stopping you from writing more, the problem is most definitely not that cool template. Writing more requires writing a lot in the initial phases. Same goes with writing well. It’s about turning on your mental faucet to let the ideas flow freely, which in turn, leads to quality content. If you really think a cool blog website will help you cross your motivation barrier and push you to start writing more, then maybe this post can help. I greatly admire Tomasz Tunguz’s writings , and my website draws inspiration from his. Here’s a breakdown of how I launched my blog:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reddit May Define the Future of IPOs</title>
      <link>/posts/reddit-may-define-the-future-of-ipos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/reddit-may-define-the-future-of-ipos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reddit, founded in 2005, has filed for an IPO. If you missed out on other indicators of this bull market, this is definitely one of the most glaring ones. Markets have opened up, tech stocks and top crypto tokens such as Bitcoin and Ethereum are ripping. But there’s one thing special about Reddit IPO’s that is not talked about enough - stock allocation to it users&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From Stratechery:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; &#xA;    src=&#34;https://axiomatic-diver-1c4.notion.site/image/https%3A%2F%2Fprod-files-secure.s3.us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2Fc6a62786-f859-45a8-8419-fae4370cf6f4%2F017ae6ec-30ca-467b-aa86-513aff84c359%2FIMG_0224.jpeg?table=block&amp;amp;id=17423d13-e6cf-44e6-ab6e-3ce885f444f8&amp;amp;spaceId=c6a62786-f859-45a8-8419-fae4370cf6f4&amp;amp;width=1420&amp;amp;userId=&amp;amp;cache=v2&#34; &#xA;    alt=&#34;image&#34; &#xA;     /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Excerpts from Man&#39;s Search for Meaning</title>
      <link>/posts/excerpts-from-mans-search-for-meaning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/excerpts-from-mans-search-for-meaning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently finished the Man’s Search for Meaning which was long kept on my digital bookshelf. I found the following excerpts the most interesting that I’ll keep with me.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-love&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;#on-love&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;svg class=&#34;icon&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; focusable=&#34;false&#34; height=&#34;16&#34; version=&#34;1.1&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 16 16&#34; width=&#34;16&#34;&gt;&#xA;            &lt;path fill-rule=&#34;evenodd&#34;&#xA;                d=&#34;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&#34;&gt;&#xA;            &lt;/path&gt;&#xA;        &lt;/svg&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;    On love&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; &#xA;    src=&#34;https://axiomatic-diver-1c4.notion.site/image/https%3A%2F%2Fprod-files-secure.s3.us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2Fc6a62786-f859-45a8-8419-fae4370cf6f4%2Fb3374d9c-4834-4887-937b-9c399605dd89%2FScreenshot_2024-03-04_at_1.54.51_PM.png?table=block&amp;amp;id=0d92ad00-1bd7-4d20-b0e4-0f65d08e45eb&amp;amp;spaceId=c6a62786-f859-45a8-8419-fae4370cf6f4&amp;amp;width=1420&amp;amp;userId=&amp;amp;cache=v2&#34; &#xA;    alt=&#34;image&#34; &#xA;     /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pausing Monthly Reads</title>
      <link>/posts/pausing-monthy-reads/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/pausing-monthy-reads/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I tried to share the best of what I read each month through my previous posts. While it helped me to push myself write a post each month, it was coming in the way of meditating on what I read. I will try to write (reming me if I don’t) a post on what meditation on what you’ve read means, but it definitely does not mean completing your reading backlog for the sake of it. I will be pausing these monthly posts, and will instead try to share a list of interesting reads once I have meditated over them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ID by amoamo Breakdown</title>
      <link>/posts/id-by-amoamo-breakdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/id-by-amoamo-breakdown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been keeping track of the new app in town ID by amoamo and found its onboarding and user experience really refreshing as compared to most other social media apps. I even Tweeted about it which was caught up by some of their team members.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;This was quite innovative by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/amoamoamo?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@amoamoamo&lt;/a&gt;  app. Explaining why you should invite your friends while humanising the experience . Felt refreshing &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/MqwuzeIwWF&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/MqwuzeIwWF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; @roohchill (@roohchill) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/roohchill/status/1746512527213965704?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;January 14, 2024&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can see the breakdown here&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I Read in January</title>
      <link>/posts/what-i-read-in-january/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/what-i-read-in-january/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lennysnewsletter.com/p/what-to-do-if-your-product-isnt-taking&#34;&gt;What to do if your product isn’t taking off&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lennysnewsletter.com/p/how-gong-builds-product&#34;&gt;How Gong builds product&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lennysnewsletter.com/p/adding-a-work-trial-to-your-interview&#34;&gt;Adding a work trial to your interview process&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-pulse-75&#34;&gt;The Pulse #75: Will US companies hire fewer engineers due to Section 174?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-pulse-77-will-ems-and-pms-take&#34;&gt;The Pulse #77: Will EMs and PMs take over TPM roles in a post-ZIRP world?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/zirp-software-engineers&#34;&gt;The end of 0% interest rates: what the new normal means for software engineers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-pulse-79-is-it-fair-for-profitable&#34;&gt;The Pulse #79: Is it fair for profitable companies to fire staff to make more money?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://governance.substack.com/p/this-week-in-governance-feb-1-community&#34;&gt;This Week in Governance - Feb 1: Community, Collaboration, and Financial Frontiers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dydx.forum/t/drc-dydx-foundation-fundraising-proposal/2152&#34;&gt;dYdX Foundation Fundraising Proposal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://stratechery.com/2024/intels-humbling/&#34;&gt;Intel’s Humbling&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://stratechery.com/2024/the-apple-vision-pros-missing-apps/&#34;&gt;The Apple Vision Pro’s Missing Apps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://stratechery.com/2024/the-new-york-times-ai-opportunity/&#34;&gt;The New York Times’ AI Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://notboring.mirror.xyz/XxQuGjzusNj8uVs6louEkOYBxps4GlRLzEwSIFKwQhU&#34;&gt;Framing the Future of the Internet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.decentralised.co/p/the-solana-ecosystem&#34;&gt;The Solana Ecosystem&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Podcast&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Opportunity Spotters vs Squatters</title>
      <link>/posts/opportunity-spotters-vs-squatters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/opportunity-spotters-vs-squatters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my experience working across various sectors and stages of startups, I’ve learned that successful companies need a balance of visionaries who can conceive new ideas and track industry trends, as well as doers who can execute these ideas. Have too many visionaries who think of imaginative ideas every hour, you’ll end up with a company that has a longer list of ideas than the number of users for a long time. Conversely, a team dominated by executors might find itself fixated on a minor or irrelevant problem for an extended period.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Perplexity Initial Thoughts</title>
      <link>/posts/perplexity-initial-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/perplexity-initial-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently tried out the Perplexity app and was quite impressed with the results. While I’ve not spent enough time to come to a conclusion yet, what really delighted me was the time it took to answer my question. Searching through Perplextiy felt like speaking to a friend who knows what exactly you are looking for and spoon feeding the response.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I searched for &lt;em&gt;how should I select an uploaded image on Notability&lt;/em&gt; inside Perplexity &lt;em&gt;search&lt;/em&gt;. Without clicking a single link, Perplexity walked me through the image selection process whereas Google showed an answer to a different question altogether. Perplexity not only understood this simple question correctly, it shared a step by step process to resolve my query instead of an incorrect response as a summary. See screenshots below.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Writing Well and Writing More</title>
      <link>/posts/on-writing-well-and-writing-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/on-writing-well-and-writing-more/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have written the most in 2023 as compared to the previous years. While I’m proud of my consistency in 2023, the journey from “On writing more” to “On writing well” is indeed a long one. My goal for 2024 is to improve the quality and depth of my writings. If my writing resonates with even just one person (apart from myself), helping them in their personal or professional journey, I’ll consider it a great achievement.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I Read in December</title>
      <link>/posts/what-i-read-in-december/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/what-i-read-in-december/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lennysnewsletter.com/p/lessons-from-going-freemium-a-decision&#34;&gt;Lessons from going freemium: a decision that broke our business&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/inside-openai-how-does-chatgpt-ship&#34;&gt;Inside OpenAI: How does ChatGPT Ship So Quickly?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-pulse-71-the-tech-behind-stripes&#34;&gt;The Pulse #71: The Tech Behind Stripe’s Realtime Cyber Monday Dashboard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://every.to/p/how-to-build-a-better-social-network&#34;&gt;How to Build a Better Social Network&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://every.to/p/how-to-mourn-omegle&#34;&gt;How to Mourn Omegle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-pulse-74&#34;&gt;The Pulse #74: Adobe Can’t buy Figma: the Impact of this on the Tech Industry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lennysnewsletter.com/p/first-principles-thinking&#34;&gt;First-principles thinking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://every.to/p/why-you-should-build-in-deep-tech&#34;&gt;Why You Should Build in Deep Tech&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://governance.substack.com/p/this-week-in-governance-december-bf0&#34;&gt;This Week in Governance - December 14: Distributed Robustness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Podcast&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Truth Seekers Win</title>
      <link>/posts/truth-seekers-win/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/truth-seekers-win/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a World full of influencers, and wannabe influencers begging for people’s attention (nothing wrong with that), I was questioning myself who wins in the long run. I am defining winning as companies that not only survive, but thrive for over atleast 5 - 10 decades.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Based on my conversation with multiple friends, I’ve observed that most early stage company founders’, employees’ fall into the trap of celebrating milestones that do not contribute to revenue, or creating shareholder’s value. Especially for VC funded companies, a company needs to grow fast to give an exit to its early backers. It surprises me when people in the driving seat of the company push for reaching or celebrating milestones that have nothing to do with revenue growth. I do not know of any business that has survived over a decade and has not earned a substantial market share and revenue.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learnings from 2023</title>
      <link>/posts/learnings-from-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/learnings-from-2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;2023 has been a relatively good year for me as compared to 2022. As we step into 2024, I want to share some of the most impactful lessons I’ve learned, some of which date back even further.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1.&lt;strong&gt;Remove things as much as you can aka &lt;em&gt;focus is critical for success&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I dabbled in too many things before 2023 with a generalist mindset and couldn’t really find time to double down on what is needed from me at a particular time or what I want from myself. In 2023, I cut down a lot of things even when I wanted to do them badly to prioritise top level company and personal goals. Till date, this has been one of my best decisions. The takeaway? Directly pursue what you genuinely want, not just what others suggest. The direct route is often the fastest route. Focus on that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Starting up vs Formal Degree</title>
      <link>/posts/starting-up-vs-formal-degree/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/starting-up-vs-formal-degree/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, I had this discussion with a friend that brought to light the old age dilemma: the choice between pursuing a college degree, and the path of entrepreneurship or joining an early-stage startup. Traditionally, society, &lt;strong&gt;including my own family&lt;/strong&gt;, has leaned heavily towards academic glory, valuing the potential for increased earnings and the prestige it brings. In contrast, the entrepreneurial route, while riskier and with uncertain success rates, offers great learning opportunities and a chance to go deep into the real-world challenges.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I Read in November</title>
      <link>/posts/what-i-read-in-november/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/what-i-read-in-november/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;read&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;#read&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;svg class=&#34;icon&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; focusable=&#34;false&#34; height=&#34;16&#34; version=&#34;1.1&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 16 16&#34; width=&#34;16&#34;&gt;&#xA;            &lt;path fill-rule=&#34;evenodd&#34;&#xA;                d=&#34;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&#34;&gt;&#xA;            &lt;/path&gt;&#xA;        &lt;/svg&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;    &lt;strong&gt;Read&lt;/strong&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lennysnewsletter.com/p/lessons-from-going-freemium-a-decision&#34;&gt;Lessons from going freemium: a decision that broke our business&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/inside-openai-how-does-chatgpt-ship&#34;&gt;Inside OpenAI: How does ChatGPT Ship So Quickly?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-pulse-71-the-tech-behind-stripes&#34;&gt;The Pulse #71: The Tech Behind Stripe’s Realtime Cyber Monday Dashboard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://every.to/p/how-to-build-a-better-social-network&#34;&gt;How to Build a Better Social Network&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://every.to/p/how-to-mourn-omegle&#34;&gt;How to Mourn Omegle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;podcast&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;#podcast&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;svg class=&#34;icon&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; focusable=&#34;false&#34; height=&#34;16&#34; version=&#34;1.1&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 16 16&#34; width=&#34;16&#34;&gt;&#xA;            &lt;path fill-rule=&#34;evenodd&#34;&#xA;                d=&#34;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&#34;&gt;&#xA;            &lt;/path&gt;&#xA;        &lt;/svg&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;    &lt;strong&gt;Podcast&lt;/strong&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/episode/0hZnn7rEmWTxLaB4l5xWXg?si=a69a959254224f43&#34;&gt;Control Pain and Heal Faster with your Brain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/episode/0xTNW1QaM50FFiSVlcPLDP?si=b69a356827c44bf0&#34;&gt;Sam Altman Back at OpenAI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/episode/4i4lKsKevNSGEUnuu7Jzn6?si=31f55ec92b644183&#34;&gt;Satya Nadella on OpenAI Debacle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2BfMuHDfGJI&#34;&gt;Elon Musk Dealbook Summit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;book&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;#book&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;svg class=&#34;icon&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; focusable=&#34;false&#34; height=&#34;16&#34; version=&#34;1.1&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 16 16&#34; width=&#34;16&#34;&gt;&#xA;            &lt;path fill-rule=&#34;evenodd&#34;&#xA;                d=&#34;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&#34;&gt;&#xA;            &lt;/path&gt;&#xA;        &lt;/svg&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;    &lt;strong&gt;Book&lt;/strong&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://fs.blog/clear/&#34;&gt;Clear Thinking by Shane Parrish&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I Read in October</title>
      <link>/posts/what-i-read-in-october/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/what-i-read-in-october/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/stacked-diffs&#34;&gt;Stacked Diffs (and why you should know about them)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lennysnewsletter.com/p/how-to-build-a-killer-sales-pitch&#34;&gt;How to build a killer sales pitch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lennysnewsletter.com/p/how-to-validate-your-b2b-startup?utm_source=%2Fsearch%2Fb2b&amp;amp;utm_medium=reader2&#34;&gt;How to validate your B2B startup idea&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://every.to/no-small-plans/the-power-of-designing-for-a-single-user&#34;&gt;The Power of Designing for a Single User&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://governance.substack.com/p/this-week-in-governance-october-5&#34;&gt;This Week in Governance - October 5: Councils, Gardeners, and Robots&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://governance.substack.com/p/this-week-in-governance-october-12&#34;&gt;This Week in Governance - October 12: Grants, Loans, and Longevity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://every.to/superorganizers/how-to-make-yourself-into-a-learning-machine&#34;&gt;How to Make Yourself Into a Learning Machine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lennysnewsletter.com/p/how-to-win-your-first-10-b2b-customers&#34;&gt;How to win and find your first 10 B2B Customers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/manu&#34;&gt;The Man Behind the Big Tech Comics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gov.optimism.io/t/draft-proposed-grants-council-charter-season-5/6942&#34;&gt;DRAFT: Proposed Grants Council Charter - Season 5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;ve Started Shipping Code</title>
      <link>/posts/ive-started-shipping-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/ive-started-shipping-code/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;ive-started-shipping-codeoctober-2-2023-2-minutes-projectshttpswwwruchilsharmacomcategoriesprojects&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;#ive-started-shipping-codeoctober-2-2023-2-minutes-projectshttpswwwruchilsharmacomcategoriesprojects&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;svg class=&#34;icon&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; focusable=&#34;false&#34; height=&#34;16&#34; version=&#34;1.1&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 16 16&#34; width=&#34;16&#34;&gt;&#xA;            &lt;path fill-rule=&#34;evenodd&#34;&#xA;                d=&#34;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&#34;&gt;&#xA;            &lt;/path&gt;&#xA;        &lt;/svg&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;    &lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve started shipping code&lt;/strong&gt;October 2, 2023 | 2 minutes | &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ruchilsharma.com/categories/projects&#34;&gt;Projects&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Not too long ago, I used to introduce myself as someone who didn’t write code. Well, things have changed! With the rise of AI, especially since the introduction of ChatGPT, I am absolutely amazed by the capabilities of AI in assisting me with coding and building projects. I had a strong desire to create my own website after successfully launching one using Jekyll in 2020, but I was struggling with customizing it to my liking. Scouring through endless Google search results was not only time-consuming but also incredibly frustrating. This led me to postpone working on my blog post, repeatedly putting it off until I had enough time to dedicate to it. But with the advent of ChatGPT, I came to a realization – I didn’t need more time; I simply needed to ask questions, and it would provide me with the precise answers I required to customize my blog post.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I Read in September</title>
      <link>/posts/what-i-read-in-september/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/what-i-read-in-september/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hivemind.vc/nostr/&#34;&gt;Why I’m Betting Big on Nostr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-pulse-63&#34;&gt;The Pulse #63: Working at a Startup vs in Big Tech&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://forum.arbitrum.foundation/t/arbitrums-short-term-incentive-program-arbitrum-improvement-proposal/16131/1&#34;&gt;Arbitrum’s Short-Term Incentive Program&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://every.to/napkin-math/the-double-bind-theory-or-why-sensationalism-unfortunately-works&#34;&gt;The Double Bind Theory—Or Why Sensationalism Works&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lennysnewsletter.com/p/how-to-identify-your-ideal-customer&#34;&gt;How the most successful B2B startups came up with their original idea&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Books&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.in/Alchemist-Paulo-Coelho/dp/8172234988&#34;&gt;The Alchemist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Videos&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Dg-rKXi9XYg&#34;&gt;AI SAFETY PANEL | Elon Musk, Max Tegmark, Greg Brockman, Benjamin Netanyahu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MVYrJJNdrEg&#34;&gt;Mark Zuckerberg: First Interview in the Metaverse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ykY69lSpDdo&#34;&gt;Ray Kurzweil: Singularity, Superintelligence, and Immortality&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I Read in August</title>
      <link>/posts/what-i-read-in-august/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/what-i-read-in-august/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-pulse-60-tech-ipos-are-back&#34;&gt;The Pulse #60: Tech IPOs are back!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-pulse-58-zoom-an-rto-turning&#34;&gt;The Pulse #58: Zoom; An RTO Turning Point?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://every.to/chain-of-thought/how-to-develop-your-taste-for-new-technologies&#34;&gt;How to Develop Your Taste for New Technologies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://digitalnative.substack.com/p/follow-the-money-categories-of-consumer?utm_source=www.homescreen.news&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_campaign=meta-s-fresh-ai-heat&#34;&gt;Follow the Money: Categories of Consumer Spend&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lennysnewsletter.com/p/how-to-identify-your-ideal-customer&#34;&gt;How to identify your ideal customer profile (ICP)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Books&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.in/Obviously-Awesome-Product-Positioning-Customers/dp/1999023005&#34;&gt;Obviously Awesome: How to Nail Product Positioning so Customers Get It, Buy It, Love It&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.in/Cant-Hurt-Me-Master-Your/dp/1544512287&#34;&gt;Can’t Hurt Me: Master Your Mind and Defy the Odds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Videos&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0oEqVIPd008&#34;&gt;Design and make money with Vision Pro! | Spatial Design EP 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=K5kZPb8faEs&amp;amp;t=2534s&#34;&gt;Critiquing Startup Mobile Apps with Glide CEO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5tSTk1083VY&#34;&gt;Joe Rogan Experience - David Goggins&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I was too early to Shark Tank?</title>
      <link>/posts/why-i-was-too-early-to-shark-tank/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/why-i-was-too-early-to-shark-tank/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my final year of college, a friend recommended Shark Tank US to me, and from the moment I watched the first episode, I was completely hooked. I binge-watched the first 5 seasons that year and quickly caught up on the remaining ones.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During my final year internship in Mumbai, I couldn’t help but wonder why there wasn’t something like Shark Tank in India. With a population of over a billion, I was convinced that it could be a huge success. I’ve always been passionate about celebrating entrepreneurs and shifting the spotlight away from Bollywood stars. Visuals of Indian entrepreneurs pitching their ideas to Lakshmi Mittal kept me up at night. Determined to take action, I approached one of the popular Indian TV series directors via Facebook DM, and to my surprise, he responded after a few follow-ups. He invited us (my room mate joined me) to his flat in Mumbai, where I presented my idea of launching Shark Tank in India. My roommate also saw the potential and joined me. Looking back, our Prezi presentation was far from perfect, but we went ahead and pitched the idea to our potential business partner.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I Read in June and July</title>
      <link>/posts/what-i-read-in-june-and-july/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/what-i-read-in-june-and-july/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.decentralised.co/p/after-the-merge&#34;&gt;After The Merge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eugenewei.com/blog/2023/7/6/how-to-blow-up-a-timeline&#34;&gt;How to blow up a timeline&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.paulgraham.com/greatwork.html&#34;&gt;How to do great work&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gitcoin.co/blog/successful-grants-programs-in-web3-history&#34;&gt;Successful grants program in Web 3 history&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://stack.optimism.io/&#34;&gt;OP Stack Docs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.swyx.io/create-luck/&#34;&gt;How to create luck&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.matthewball.vc/all/bigtechbiggestbets&#34;&gt;Big Tech Biggest Bets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.notion.so/Blog-d52017d7b1d04567955c89605e7e88d1?pvs=21&#34;&gt;Fundraising Advice&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I religiously read and listen to Stratechery, The Daily Gwei, The Pragmatic Engineer, The Chopping Block Podcast, Lenny’s Newsletter, and Every on a daily/weekly basis&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Podcast and Books&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sharptech.fm/member/episode/the-threads-episode-how-we-got-here-meta-obstacles-and-advantages-everyone-hates-twitter-and-uses-it-every-day&#34;&gt;The Threads Episode: How We Got Here, Meta Obstacles and Advantages, Everyone Hates Twitter (And Uses It Every Day)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://growth.eladgil.com/&#34;&gt;High Growth Handbook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.in/Never-Split-Difference-Negotiating-Depended/dp/0062407805&#34;&gt;Never Split The Difference&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Talented Tech Players Need to Stay in the Game</title>
      <link>/posts/why-talented-tech-players-need-to-stay-in-the-gamejune-11-2023-2-minutes-copy-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/why-talented-tech-players-need-to-stay-in-the-gamejune-11-2023-2-minutes-copy-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every week, big tech and startups produce something remarkable that takes everyone by surprise. These remarkable advancements quickly become the household talks and spark discussions among tech pundits who are eager to delve into the intricacies of these technologies and launches.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Back in 2006, when I was in 6th grade, I loved watching &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/b007t9y1&#34;&gt;Match of The Day&lt;/a&gt;, a show where all football pundits got together and talked about managerial decisions, controversial moments in the game, and transfers. It’s fascinating to observe a similar phenomenon emerging within the realm of Big Tech and startups, albeit with different players and pundits.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I Read in May</title>
      <link>/posts/what-i-read-in-may/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/what-i-read-in-may/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://messari.io/report/state-of-dao-funding&#34;&gt;State of DAO Funding&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://research.lido.fi/t/ldo-steth-dual-governance/2382&#34;&gt;LIDO Dual Governance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://forum.makerdao.com/t/the-5-phases-of-endgame/20830&#34;&gt;5 Phases of End Game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.pragmaticengineer.com/an-educational-side-project/&#34;&gt;An Education Side Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Scaling solutions on &lt;a href=&#34;http://ethereum.org/&#34;&gt;Ethereum.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://stonecoldpat.substack.com/p/how-proof-of-stake-ethereum-works&#34;&gt;Ethereum PoS Series&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://investors.spotify.com/financials/default.aspx&#34;&gt;Spotify Financial Reports&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pyo50QGmH_s&#34;&gt;Shreyas Doshi’s Product Sense Workshop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/nathanbarry/status/1659566137179537408?s=20&#34;&gt;Scaling to $100k MRR by Nathan Barry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.in/Banker-Poor-Micro-Lending-Against-Poverty/dp/1586481983&#34;&gt;Book - Banker to the Poor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://stevejobsarchive.com/book&#34;&gt;Book - Make Something Wonderful&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What’s wrong with voting only decision making in DAO&#39;s</title>
      <link>/posts/whats-wrong-with-voting-only-decision-making-in-daos/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/whats-wrong-with-voting-only-decision-making-in-daos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Grant programs are one of the best ways to attract high-quality contributors to your ecosystem. There’s no denying their potential impact. However, many ecosystems fail to realize that if not implemented well, these programs can lead to the loss of key contributors. In an attention scare World, where abundant opportunities exist, it is crucial for ecosystems to provide the best experience in order to attract and retain high-quality contributors. I’ve personally faced the following problems as a DAO contributor:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deep Dives - Maker DAO</title>
      <link>/posts/deep-dives---maker-dao-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/deep-dives---maker-dao-copy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dabblish.substack.com/p/deep-dives-maker-dao&#34;&gt;Deep Dives - Maker DAO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deep Dives - Spotify</title>
      <link>/posts/deep-dives---spotify/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/deep-dives---spotify/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dabblish.substack.com/p/turn-up-the-music-spotifys-teardown&#34;&gt;Deep Dives - Spotify&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Balaji is right, but he may lose the bet</title>
      <link>/posts/balaji-is-right-but-he-may-lose-the-bet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/balaji-is-right-but-he-may-lose-the-bet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;I will take that bet.&lt;br&gt;You buy 1 BTC.&lt;br&gt;I will send $1M USD.&lt;br&gt;This is ~40:1 odds as 1 BTC is worth ~$26k.&lt;br&gt;The term is 90 days.&lt;br&gt;All we need is a mutually agreed custodian who will still be there to settle this in the event of digital dollar devaluation.&lt;br&gt;If someone knows how to do this… &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/hhPr522PQu&#34;&gt;https://t.co/hhPr522PQu&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/6Aav9KeJpe&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/6Aav9KeJpe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Balaji (@balajis) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/balajis/status/1636797265317867520?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;March 17, 2023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA; &lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&#xA; &#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Having reviewed this tweet’s contents in detail, I find Balaji’s argument about inflation being a significant threat to the American economy quite persuasive. However, I remain unconvinced that the average citizien has the time to go into these complex details and subsequently exit to Bitcoin. The majority of people will likely accept the Federal Reserve’s explanation, which will be disseminated through various channels, and will continue to invest their money in the fiat system. Although the average American may have lost faith in the Fed, they are yet to reach the point of taking their hard-earned dollars out of the fiat system. They may have exited their trust, they will not exit thier $$’s right now.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revamping My Blog Post Theme</title>
      <link>/posts/revamping-my-blog-post-theme-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/revamping-my-blog-post-theme-copy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am currently working on migrating and enhancing my blog’s theme and will not be posting for sometime. I intent to start posting again next year and port all the previous posts as soon as the new theme design and migration is done. Till then, you can reach out to me on Twitter(pinned above) DM. Have a great year ahead! 🤝&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Personal OKRs 2022</title>
      <link>/posts/personal-okrs-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/personal-okrs-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://axiomatic-diver-1c4.notion.site/6506f40d988e426590ee8abe5ae12bea?v=e5de44c28ea540f6a45c98fea43a80e3&#34;&gt;Personal OKRs 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Magic of Airdrops : Earn While Your Learn</title>
      <link>/posts/the-magic-of-airdrops--earn-while-your-learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/the-magic-of-airdrops--earn-while-your-learn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Airdrops, in my opinion, are the fastest way to educate users about your product and get user adoption. For me, the starting point was ENS. Seeing my close friends earning ~ $10k through the ENS airdrop piqued my interest into ENS and that eventually led me to buying my own ENS domain.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Simply put, an airdrop is a distribution of a crypto token or coin, usually for free, to numerous wallet addresses. But it is not as trivial as it sounds. The caveat here is that an airdrop comes with the price. For one to be eligible for receiving an airdrop, one needs to use a protocol and interact with it in a manner prescribed by the protocol. Hence, as a user, you might end up spending at least the gas price in order to be eligible for a token airdrop. As I did not own an ENS domain when ENS announced the airdrop, I was not eligible for the same.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Identify Your Echochamber</title>
      <link>/posts/identify-your-echochamber/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/identify-your-echochamber/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After 4 years, I have started using Social Media platforms again. While I had no difficulties posting (except stories on Instagram), there are certain observations and patterns that I have started to come across different social media platforms. Detailing them out here :&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1.&lt;strong&gt;Twitter&lt;/strong&gt; Tagline from a user&amp;rsquo;s perspective : I am smart and &amp;ldquo;intellectual&amp;rdquo; as well. Please koi&#xA;meri bhi sun lo. From replying on Elon Musk&amp;rsquo;s and Balajis Tweets to posting random threads on why you should&#xA;switch to Signal, Twitter is an echo - chamber of wanna be &amp;ldquo;intellectuals&amp;rdquo;. While Twitter does&#xA;help one get deep insights into any topic from some of the most credible individuals, it is also&#xA;an echo - chamber of people who are &amp;ldquo;faking&amp;rdquo; it till they make it. There&amp;rsquo;s nothing right/wrong in&#xA;this. Well, who doesn&amp;rsquo;t like to have a million followers! But what I&amp;rsquo;ll really appreciate is a following built on one&amp;rsquo;s substance, skills and not copy pasted Tweets, or networking.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>So You Want to Form New Habits?</title>
      <link>/posts/so-you-want-to-form-new-habits/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/so-you-want-to-form-new-habits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Creating positive habits takes more than just willpower. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen by itself as it is more science than art. It requires constant re-evaluation of where you are spending time, people whom you are spending time with and your environment. Last year, I spent significant amount of time researching this and stumbled upon different books, bootcamps and blog posts that have proven to be really helpful in planning my day and subsequently, my week. This blog post is to detail out my learnings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What am I Reading These Days</title>
      <link>/posts/what-am-i-reading-these-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/what-am-i-reading-these-days/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With ~ 21 more books in the bag, the lockdown has turned out to be quite productive. Although I have tried to maintain variety in the kind of books and content that I read, a couple of books that have stood out for me are : Courage To Be Disliked by Ichiro Ishimi and Atomic Habits by James Clear. Going candid on this one:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Stating the names and description of the books that I liked and have read thus far:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting Your Time Back</title>
      <link>/posts/getting-your-time-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/getting-your-time-back/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few things that I have started doing to get back my time:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Setting an agenda for the meeting with the meeting invite. Agenda less meetings create confusion and&#xA;lead to people talking about random things.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;30 mins meeting by default as a calendar invite. This has helped me to close the open points quickly to&#xA;free up time for important things.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Putting slots on my calendar when I want to get work done without any distraction. I cancel/&#xA;reschedule all meetings if they clash during that time.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ending meetings early or declining to attend those that do not provide any insight/actionable. I also&#xA;make sure that one of the attendees or I share the actionables from a meeting with all the relevant    stakeholders within 24 hours of the meeting.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Not attending calls/meetings just because they are on my calendar.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;While talking feedback and ideas from relevant stakeholders is important, executing low impact ideas may&#xA;not be the best use of your time. To avoid this, I try to make the person who proposes an idea think.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;End meetings early if you are done discussing the action items. No point extending the meeting for an&#xA;hour just because the calendar invite was for one hour.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You may wish to choose &lt;a href=&#34;https://asana.com/resources/eisenhower-matrix#:~:text=The%20Eisenhower%20Matrix%20is%20a,the%20tasks%20you&#39;ll%20delete.&#34;&gt;Eisenhover Matrix&lt;/a&gt; to prioritise your work.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strong Opinions Loosely Held</title>
      <link>/posts/strong-opinions-loosely-held-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/strong-opinions-loosely-held-copy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bobsutton.typepad.com/my_weblog/2006/07/strong_opinions.html&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Strong opinions, weakly held&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; is one of the frameworks used to deal with an uncertain future and yet, still move forward. It is one of the tools to become aware and have the courage to act on your knowledge, but also have the humility to doubt what we know. It is a framework that I use to prevent myself from seeing and hearing only the things that I like and discard others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Launching a Course on Venture Capital 101</title>
      <link>/posts/a-course-on-venture-capital-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/a-course-on-venture-capital-copy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;VC is a black box. It is a tightly knit community and this makes it really hard to know the inner workings of a VC fund. It is one thing to know about VC through blogs and books and another through a group of people who have been there, done that!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These are some of the most common remarks that I&amp;rsquo;ve come across when speaking to most folks who aspire to break into Venture capital. From those in B - schools to those working in corporates, getting into a Venture Capital firm seems a far fetched dream.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Habit Stacking Tools</title>
      <link>/posts/habit-stacking-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/habit-stacking-tools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some of my friends asked me to detail out the tools/platforms that I use to form and stick to my daily habits. Listing some of them down here :&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A. &lt;strong&gt;Note - Taking&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://evernote.com/&#34;&gt;Evernote&lt;/a&gt; : Everything new that I come across goes into Evernote. I use 7 - 10 different accounts with each account having a different purpose such as writing, online learning, book summaries, designing.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.notion.so/&#34;&gt;Notion&lt;/a&gt; : While some of the notebooks are same as that on Evernote, I use Notion when I’m using Desktop or on web. Notion is a place where all my notes are structured so that I can pull info. on any topic anytime.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gingerlabs.com/&#34;&gt;Notability&lt;/a&gt; : One of the best apps for taking notes. The experience of writing on a paper using a pen/pencil is unbeatable. I use Notability on iPad and iPhone along with Apple Pencil and compile all of my notes on Notion at the end of each week.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.google.android.keep&amp;amp;hl=en_IN&amp;amp;gl=US&#34;&gt;Google Keep&lt;/a&gt; : Everything high level/strategic goals here&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.whatsapp.com/?lang=en&#34;&gt;Whatsapp&lt;/a&gt; : The best note - taking app out there. I have 15 - 20 different groups where I share notes to myself and subsequently, put it all on Notion at the end of each week.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B. Reading&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Personal OKRs 2021</title>
      <link>/posts/personal-okrs-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/personal-okrs-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://axiomatic-diver-1c4.notion.site/e7ea574ebafd492fa927b9beb3256766?v=5627b3e927104714a69351d36e303194&#34; title=&#34;Personal OKRs 2021&#34;&gt;Personal OKRs 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Everything is a Product</title>
      <link>/posts/everything-is-a-product/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/everything-is-a-product/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This realisation came to me after reading the biographies of Michael Jordan and Leonardo Da Vinci. Some of the VCs and Product Folks in Silicon Valley also subscribe to this thought. They treat themselves and their careers as that of professional athletes. According to them, the way you conduct yourself, the way you eat, your personal journal or as a matter of fact, your fingernails are nothing but mini - products. They see these attributes as features and a part of a bigger product i.e. themselves.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Delhi Rant</title>
      <link>/posts/delhi-rant/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/delhi-rant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve stayed in Delhi - NCR for ~ 1.5 years now (since September 2019) and came back to Delhi after 14 years (after 2005). Now that I look back, there are certain observations that worry me about Delhi - Gurgaon culture. Listing them down here :&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Overt celebration of &lt;strong&gt;eat-sleep-repeat&lt;/strong&gt; culture : The common phrase that I hear most people use is : “ I don’t want to think too much and just chill”. While it is perfectly fine to do so, you have lost the right to complain about your problems. Every third person here has an opinion on some of the most pressing issues such as education, poverty and pollution, but I wonder what they are doing about it. These issues will not be solved by &lt;strong&gt;eat-sleep-repeat&lt;/strong&gt; culture. Put in the effort first to form an opinion and do your bit towards solving the problem. If you are not doing so, please stop complaining.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Forming World views through Bollywood movies and TV shows such as Friends&lt;/strong&gt; : While I agree that some of the shows (such as Friends) and movies are a delight to watch, doesn’t mean that you expect the same things to happen in your life. One needs to have the lens of objectivity on while watching such content. It is a script written by a professional whose end goal is to either increase the TRP or sales of subscription. Bollywood is one of the biggest ceilings of this country IMO. More on this &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/balajis/status/1350065743035985922&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; .“Let me make the songs of a nation, and I care not who makes its laws”. Song writers and movie directors are doing their job, we need to do ours. This &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.in/Amusing-Ourselves-Death-Discourse-Business/dp/014303653X&#34;&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; might come handy if you want to dig deeper into this topic.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fluff over substance :&lt;/strong&gt; Most folks that I’ve met here come across as extremely pretentious and unauthentic. North Star for such people is to play the status game while forgetting that they do not have substance. You can only go so far with “fake it till you make it” attitude. Self - awareness as a trait is limited in supply in this part of this country .&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With that being said, there are some good things about Delhi such as food, which I will miss. The above pointers are based on my personal experiences and opinions of some of my close friends. You may choose to disagree and form your opinion/experiences.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Does It Take to Build a Successful Consumer Brand in India?</title>
      <link>/posts/what-does-it-take-to-build-a-successful-consumer-brand-in-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/what-does-it-take-to-build-a-successful-consumer-brand-in-india/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://firesideventures.com&#34;&gt;Fireside Ventures&lt;/a&gt; (a consumer focussed fund) closed their second fund worth $118 Million three days ago. This comes at a time when people in India (my parents included) are willing to try out new products and give challenger brands a try. As India&amp;rsquo;s retail market evolves, modern trade (likes of LeMarche) is set to account for 15% (from 8%) of the overall distribution whereas online retail is expected to account for 5% (currently at ~ 3%). A few questions that I had in mind while observing this upsurge were why now? What has changed? Why is it so easy to start a consumer brand? I read a number of reports and spoke to 60+ founders in my quest to find the answers. This blog post is to detail out my findings :&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting Rich Without Getting Lucky</title>
      <link>/posts/getting-rich-without-getting-lucky/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/getting-rich-without-getting-lucky/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a summary of the framework used by Naval Ravikant to create order in chaos. Summarizing everything that I have learnt from his blogposts and podcasts:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wealth vs Money vs Status&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Seek wealth, not money or status. Wealth is having assets that earn while you sleep. Money is how we transfer time and wealth. Status is your place in the social hierarchy. Status is a zero sum game so,   ignore those who enjoy playing this game.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best of Masters of Scale</title>
      <link>/posts/best-of-masters-of-scale/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/best-of-masters-of-scale/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Below is the list of podcasts from Masters of Scale series that I found the most engaging and insightful. I finished listening to all its episodes last year. This is for those who are short on time and wondering where to start.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mastersofscale.com/luis-von-ahn/&#34;&gt;A Masterclass in Outsourcing with Luis von Ahn&lt;/a&gt;  (Duolingo)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/open-or-closed-answer-is-both-w-joi-ito-mit-media-lab/id1227971746?i=1000436867368&#34;&gt;Open or closed with Joe Ito :&lt;/a&gt; A podcast on community building&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mastersofscale.com/ben-chestnut-the-case-for-bootstrapping/&#34;&gt;The case for Bootstrapping with Ben Chestnut&lt;/a&gt; (Mailchimp)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mastersofscale.com/tobi-lutke-be-a-platform/&#34;&gt;Be a platform with Tobi Lütke&lt;/a&gt; (Shopify)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mastersofscale.com/peter-thiel-escape-the-competition/&#34;&gt;Escape the competition with Peter Thiel&lt;/a&gt; (Needs no introduction)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mastersofscale.com/reed-hastings-culture-shock/&#34;&gt;Why culture matters with Reid Hastings&lt;/a&gt; (Netflix)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/bonus-10-new-rules-for-big-career-changes-graduation/id1227971746?i=1000442249696&#34;&gt;New rules for big career changes with Jordan Harbinger&lt;/a&gt; : The best podcast that I found on mapping your career trajectory&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mastersofscale.com/eric-ries/&#34;&gt;Build, Measure, Learn with non other than Eric Ries&lt;/a&gt; (Lean Startup)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/id1227971746?i=1000456865058&#34;&gt;How to set the drumbeat with Jeff Weiner&lt;/a&gt; (LinkedIn - LinkedIn)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mastersofscale.com/mark-zuckerberg-imperfect-is-perfect/&#34;&gt;Imperfect is perfect with Mark Zuckerberg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mastersofscale.com/reid-hoffman-make-everyone-a-hero-part-two/&#34;&gt;Reid Hoffman Story : Part 2 - Make everyone a hero&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mastersofscale.com/mariam-naficy-the-money-episode/&#34;&gt;Raise more than you need with Mariam Naficy&lt;/a&gt; (Minted)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mastersofscale.com/ellen-kullman/&#34;&gt;4 core principles of crisis management&lt;/a&gt; (Ellen Kullman)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/ray-dalio-how-to-embrace-conflict/id1227971746?i=1000457863860&#34;&gt;How to embrace conflict with Ray Dalio&lt;/a&gt; : This is my personal favourite&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mastersofscale.com/aneel-bhusri-the-elusive-formula-for-great-hiring/&#34;&gt;The elusive formula for great hiring with Aneel Bhusri&lt;/a&gt; (Workday)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/79-how-to-master-your-emotions-w-sam-harris/id1227971746?i=1000506611995&#34;&gt;How to Master Emotion with Sam Harris&lt;/a&gt;. He also has an amazing app called &lt;a href=&#34;https://wakingup.com&#34;&gt;Waking Up&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/building-bridges-to-scale-w-kinds-daniel-lubetzky/id1227971746?i=1000500934868&#34;&gt;Building bridges to scale with Daniel Lubetzky&lt;/a&gt; (Kind)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/73-wikipedias-jimmy-wales-to-scale-find-the-right-values/id1227971746?i=1000494572313&#34;&gt;To scale find the right values with Jimmy Wales&lt;/a&gt; (Wikipedia)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mastersofscale.com/john-foley/&#34;&gt;How to turn sceptics into fans with John Foley&lt;/a&gt; (Peloton)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Speed Reading</title>
      <link>/posts/speed-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/speed-reading/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back in January, 2019, I came across a technique called “Speed Reading” on one of Tim Ferris’ videos. I was so intrigued by it that not only did I start “reading about speed reading” a lot, I also started practicing the same tirelessly. Since then, I have almost doubled my reading speed with increased retention and have started to summarise all the books that I read on Evernote (Will share them all and make it accessible to everyone by the end of this year). The next question that should come to your mind is what the hell is “speed reading” and how do I use it to increase my reading speed?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is your superpower?</title>
      <link>/posts/what-is-your-superpower-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/what-is-your-superpower-copy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; &#xA;    src=&#34;https://manassaloi.com/assets/img/no_filter.png&#34; &#xA;    alt=&#34;image&#34; &#xA;     /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In one of the excerpt from the book No Filter: The Inside Story of Instagram, Kevin Systorm explains to Ashton Kutcher why Instagram blew up. It was not because of network effects. There were no network effects on day 1. It was not because of celebrity users. It was not because they rode on Twitter and Facebook graph of users. All of these happened later. Like most B2C products, it started as a single player use case: &lt;strong&gt;How to make your photos more beautiful, and shareable&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Personal OKRs 2020</title>
      <link>/posts/personal-okrs-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/personal-okrs-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://axiomatic-diver-1c4.notion.site/3acaabebd8e04c899e32b9da6c0a5e76?v=0510c7d736ef4aba9a6cd2e0c52e2c5a&#34; title=&#34;Personl OKRs 2020&#34;&gt;Personal OKRs 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seek to Understand Before Trying to be Understood</title>
      <link>/posts/seek-to-understand-before-trying-to-be-understood/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/seek-to-understand-before-trying-to-be-understood/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;People are just either not that interested in what you&amp;rsquo;re saying, or they are too focused on their own agenda. It&amp;rsquo;s ridiculous to see two people acting like they can’t really hear each other — by choice.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In &amp;ldquo;The Significance Principle,&amp;rdquo; authors Les Carter and Jim Underwood posit that we should listen past where the other person has finished. We should even pause before answering. Let them get their point, their story, their compliment, and even their criticism out. Completely.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thinking in Pomodoros</title>
      <link>/posts/thinking-in-pomodoros-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/thinking-in-pomodoros-copy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week (week from 24th May - 31st May) has turned out to be the most productive week in my life. Not that I have cut down on my side gigs or changed my priorities, but a simple addition of an age old technique called Pomodoro has changed the way I have started to think about time. Here’s how I see the difference :&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Old Me&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let me list down what I am supposed to do today and complete today’s To - Dos. I’ll go through the list one by one and then reward myself at the end of the day with an episode of “House of Lies” or reply to some of my Whatsapp messages. But there is something inherently evil with this strategy which is “not defining your stop losses”. As soon as I find my flow in one of the activities in my To - Do list, I lose track of time and can only complete ~ 50% of the assigned tasks on any given day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Differentiating Yourself Through Social Media</title>
      <link>/posts/differeniating-yourself-through-social-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/differeniating-yourself-through-social-media/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Increasing number of users are spending their time online and are using social media tools to express themselves. Amidst this, can the activities (posts/likes/comments) performed by people on social media be used to hire candidates for different job profiles? I see this as a great way to differentiate candidates from others in cases where they have similar educational backgrounds, skill sets, and resumes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We put ourselves out there whenever we post something, like/comment on a post, or update our Goodreads account with the latest book that we’ve read. Every activity that we perform online conveys some or the other aspect about us. I feel that the reliance on social media to filter applicants will increase with time and will be used to differentiate similar candidates, especially to determine cultural fit (something on the lines of Klout Score, but more focussed towards determining cultural fit instead of influence) . Not limiting to jobs, activities on social media will also be used to filter university applications.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
