<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Ruchil Sharma</title>
    <link>/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Ruchil Sharma</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>So you want to setup your own blog</title>
      <link>/posts/so-you-want-to-setup-your-own-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/so-you-want-to-setup-your-own-blog/</guid>
      <description>If a cool blogpost template is stopping you from writing more, the problem is most definitely not that cool template. Writing more requires writing a lot in the initial phases. Same goes with writing well. It&amp;rsquo;s about turning on your mental faucet to let the ideas flow freely, which in turn, leads to quality content. If you really think a cool blog website will help you cross your motivation barrier and push you to start writing more, then maybe this post can help.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reddit May Define the Future of IPOs</title>
      <link>/posts/reddit_ipo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/reddit_ipo/</guid>
      <description>Reddit, founded in 2005, has filed for an IPO. If you missed out on other indicators of this bull market, this is definitely one of the most glaring ones. Markets have opened up, tech stocks and top crypto tokens such as Bitcoin and Ethereum are ripping. But there’s one thing special about Reddit IPO’s that is not talked about enough - stock allocation to it users
From Stratechery:
Airdrops and token allocation for community members is very common in the Web3 universe, but users of a web2 platform getting a stock allocation for their contributions is unheard of in the Web 2 World.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excerpts from Man’s Search for Meaning</title>
      <link>/posts/excerpts-from-mans-search-for-meaning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/excerpts-from-mans-search-for-meaning/</guid>
      <description>I recently finished the book Man’s Search for Meaning which was kept for a long time on my digital bookshelf. I found the following timeless excerpts the most interesting that I’ll keep with me. Hope you find them interesting too.
On love On Choosing One’s Attitude On the Meaning of Life </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pausing Monthly Read Posts</title>
      <link>/posts/pausing-monthly-read-posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/pausing-monthly-read-posts/</guid>
      <description>I tried to share the best of what I read each month through my previous posts. While it helped me to push myself write a post each month, it was coming in the way of meditating on what I read. I will try to write (reming me if I don’t) a post on what meditation on what you&amp;rsquo;ve read means, but it definitely does not mean completing your reading backlog for the sake of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ID by amoamo Breakdown</title>
      <link>/posts/id-by-amo-amo-breakdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/id-by-amo-amo-breakdown/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been keeping track of the new app in town ID by amoamo and found its onboarding and user experience really refreshing as compared to most other social media apps. I even Tweeted about it which was caught up by some of their team members.
This was quite innovative by @amoamoamo app. Explaining why you should invite your friends while humanising the experience . Felt refreshing pic.twitter.com/MqwuzeIwWF
&amp;mdash; @roohchill (@roohchill) January 14, 2024 You can see the breakdown here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I Read in January</title>
      <link>/posts/what-i-read-in-january/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/what-i-read-in-january/</guid>
      <description>Posts
What to do if your product isn’t taking off How Gong builds product Adding a work trial to your interview process The Pulse #75: Will US companies hire fewer engineers due to Section 174? The Pulse #77: Will EMs and PMs take over TPM roles in a post-ZIRP world? The end of 0% interest rates: what the new normal means for software engineers The Pulse #79: Is it fair for profitable companies to fire staff to make more money?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Opportunity Spotters vs Squatters</title>
      <link>/posts/opportuntiy-spotters-vs-squatters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/opportuntiy-spotters-vs-squatters/</guid>
      <description>In my experience working across various sectors and stages of startups, I’ve learned that successful companies need a balance of visionaries who can conceive new ideas and track industry trends, as well as doers who can execute these ideas. Have too many visionaries who think of imaginative ideas every hour, you’ll end up with a company that has a longer list of ideas than the number of users for a long time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perplexity Initial Thoughts</title>
      <link>/posts/perplexity-initial-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/perplexity-initial-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>I recently tried out the Perplexity app and was quite impressed with the results. While I’ve not spent enough time to come to a conclusion yet, what really delighted me was the time it took to answer my question. Searching through Perplextiy felt like speaking to a friend who knows what exactly you are looking for and spoon feeding the response.
I searched for how should I select an uploaded image on Notability inside Perplexity search.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Writing Well and Writing More</title>
      <link>/posts/on-writing-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/on-writing-more/</guid>
      <description>I have written the most in 2023 as compared to the previous years. While I’m proud of my consistency in 2023, the journey from “On writing more” to “On writing well” is indeed a long one. My goal for 2024 is to improve the quality and depth of my writings. If my writing resonates with even just one person (apart from myself), helping them in their personal or professional journey, I&amp;rsquo;ll consider it a great achievement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I Read in December</title>
      <link>/posts/what-i-read-in-december/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/what-i-read-in-december/</guid>
      <description>Posts
Lessons from going freemium: a decision that broke our business Inside OpenAI: How does ChatGPT Ship So Quickly? The Pulse #71: The Tech Behind Stripe’s Realtime Cyber Monday Dashboard How to Build a Better Social Network How to Mourn Omegle The Pulse #74: Adobe Can’t buy Figma: the Impact of this on the Tech Industry First-principles thinking Why You Should Build in Deep Tech This Week in Governance - December 14: Distributed Robustness Podcasts</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Truth Seekers Win</title>
      <link>/posts/truth-seekers-win/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/truth-seekers-win/</guid>
      <description>In a World full of influencers, and wannabe influencers begging for people&amp;rsquo;s attention (nothing wrong with that), I was questioning myself who wins in the long run. I am defining winning as companies that not only survive, but thrive for over atleast 5 - 10 decades.
Based on my conversation with multiple friends, I’ve observed that most early stage company founders&amp;rsquo;, employees&amp;rsquo; fall into the trap of celebrating milestones that do not contribute to revenue, or creating shareholder&amp;rsquo;s value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learnings from 2023</title>
      <link>/posts/2023-learnings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2023-learnings/</guid>
      <description>2023 has been a relatively good year for me as compared to 2022. As we step into 2024, I want to share some of the most impactful lessons I&amp;rsquo;ve learned, some of which date back even further.
1.Remove things as much as you can aka focus is critical for success
I dabbled in too many things before 2023 with a generalist mindset and couldn’t really find time to double down on what is needed from me at a particular time or what I want from myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting up vs Formal Degree</title>
      <link>/posts/start-ups-vs-degree/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/start-ups-vs-degree/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I had this discussion with a friend that brought to light the old age dilemma: the choice between pursuing a college degree, and the path of entrepreneurship or joining an early-stage startup. Traditionally, society, including my own family, has leaned heavily towards academic glory, valuing the potential for increased earnings and the prestige it brings. In contrast, the entrepreneurial route, while riskier and with uncertain success rates, offers great learning opportunities and a chance to go deep into the real-world challenges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I Read in November</title>
      <link>/posts/what-i-read-in-november/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/what-i-read-in-november/</guid>
      <description>After close to an year, I took a small break to visit my family. While I didn&amp;rsquo;t reach as much as I usually do, sharing what I did:
Read Lessons from going freemium: a decision that broke our business Inside OpenAI: How does ChatGPT Ship So Quickly? The Pulse #71: The Tech Behind Stripe’s Realtime Cyber Monday Dashboard How to Build a Better Social Network How to Mourn Omegle Podcast Control Pain and Heal Faster with your Brain Sam Altman Back at OpenAI Satya Nadella on OpenAI Debacle Elon Musk Dealbook Summit Book Clear Thinking by Shane Parrish </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I Read in October</title>
      <link>/posts/what-i-read-in-october/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/what-i-read-in-october/</guid>
      <description>Reads
Stacked Diffs (and why you should know about them) How to build a killer sales pitch How to validate your B2B startup idea The Power of Designing for a Single User This Week in Governance - October 5: Councils, Gardeners, and Robots This Week in Governance - October 12: Grants, Loans, and Longevity How to Make Yourself Into a Learning Machine How to win and find your first 10 B2B Customers The Man Behind the Big Tech Comics DRAFT: Proposed Grants Council Charter - Season 5 Podcast</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;ve started shipping code</title>
      <link>/posts/started-shipping-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/started-shipping-code/</guid>
      <description>Not too long ago, I used to introduce myself as someone who didn&amp;rsquo;t write code. Well, things have changed! With the rise of AI, especially since the introduction of ChatGPT, I am absolutely amazed by the capabilities of AI in assisting me with coding and building projects. I had a strong desire to create my own website after successfully launching one using Jekyll in 2020, but I was struggling with customizing it to my liking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I Read in September</title>
      <link>/posts/what-i-read-in-september/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/what-i-read-in-september/</guid>
      <description>Posts
Why I’m Betting Big on Nostr The Pulse #63: Working at a Startup vs in Big Tech Arbitrum’s Short-Term Incentive Program The Double Bind Theory—Or Why Sensationalism Works How the most successful B2B startups came up with their original idea Books
The Alchemist Videos
AI SAFETY PANEL | Elon Musk, Max Tegmark, Greg Brockman, Benjamin Netanyahu Mark Zuckerberg: First Interview in the Metaverse Ray Kurzweil: Singularity, Superintelligence, and Immortality </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I Read in August</title>
      <link>/posts/what-i-read-in-august/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/what-i-read-in-august/</guid>
      <description>Posts
The Pulse #60: Tech IPOs are back! The Pulse #58: Zoom; An RTO Turning Point? How to Develop Your Taste for New Technologies Follow the Money: Categories of Consumer Spend How to identify your ideal customer profile (ICP) Books
Obviously Awesome: How to Nail Product Positioning so Customers Get It, Buy It, Love It Can&amp;rsquo;t Hurt Me: Master Your Mind and Defy the Odds Videos
Design and make money with Vision Pro!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I was too early to Shark Tank?</title>
      <link>/posts/shark-tank/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/shark-tank/</guid>
      <description>In my final year of college, a friend recommended Shark Tank US to me, and from the moment I watched the first episode, I was completely hooked. I binge-watched the first 5 seasons that year and quickly caught up on the remaining ones.
During my final year internship in Mumbai, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but wonder why there wasn&amp;rsquo;t something like Shark Tank in India. With a population of over a billion, I was convinced that it could be a huge success.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I Read in June and July</title>
      <link>/posts/what-i-read-in-june-and-july/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/what-i-read-in-june-and-july/</guid>
      <description> After The Merge How to blow up a timeline How to do great work Successful grants program in Web 3 history OP Stack Docs How to create luck Big Tech Biggest Bets Fundraising Advice I religiously read and listen to Stratechery, The Daily Gwei, The Pragmatic Engineer, The Chopping Block Podcast, Lenny’s Newsletter, and Every on a daily/weekly basis Podcast and Books
The Threads Episode: How We Got Here, Meta Obstacles and Advantages, Everyone Hates Twitter (And Uses It Every Day) High Growth Handbook Never Split The Difference </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Talented Tech Players Need to Stay in the Game</title>
      <link>/posts/why-talented-tech-players-need-to-stay-in-the-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/why-talented-tech-players-need-to-stay-in-the-game/</guid>
      <description>Every week, big tech and startups produce something remarkable that takes everyone by surprise. These remarkable advancements quickly become the household talks and spark discussions among tech pundits who are eager to delve into the intricacies of these technologies and launches.
Back in 2006, when I was in 6th grade, I loved watching Match of The Day, a show where all football pundits got together and talked about managerial decisions, controversial moments in the game, and transfers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I Read in May</title>
      <link>/posts/what-i-read-in-may/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/what-i-read-in-may/</guid>
      <description> State of DAO Funding LIDO Dual Governance 5 Phases of End Game An Education Side Project Scaling solutions on Ethereum.org Ethereum PoS Series Spotify Financial Reports Shreyas Doshi’s Product Sense Workshop Scaling to $100k MRR by Nathan Barry Book - Banker to the Poor Book - Make Something Wonderful </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s wrong with voting only decision making in DAO&#39;s</title>
      <link>/posts/what-is-wrong-with-daos/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/what-is-wrong-with-daos/</guid>
      <description>Grant programs are one of the best ways to attract high-quality contributors to your ecosystem. There&amp;rsquo;s no denying their potential impact. However, many ecosystems fail to realize that if not implemented well, these programs can lead to the loss of key contributors. In an attention scare World, where abundant opportunities exist, it is crucial for ecosystems to provide the best experience in order to attract and retain high-quality contributors. I&amp;rsquo;ve personally faced the following problems as a DAO contributor:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Dives - Spotify</title>
      <link>/posts/spotify-deep-dive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/spotify-deep-dive/</guid>
      <description>Turn up the music - Spotify’s Teardown</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Dives - Maker DAO</title>
      <link>/posts/maker-dao-deep-dive/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/maker-dao-deep-dive/</guid>
      <description>Maker DAO is a well-known protocol that has been a pioneer in the decentralized finance (DeFi) space. In 2021, Maker Foundation took a significant step towards decentralization by dissolving itself and spinning up a DAO. As someone who has delved deep into the inner workings of Maker DAO over the past two weeks, I&amp;rsquo;ve gathered valuable insights and resources that will help anyone start contributing to Maker DAO.
Major Events</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Balaji is right, but he may lose the bet</title>
      <link>/posts/balaji-is-right-but-he-will-lose-the-bet-copy-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/balaji-is-right-but-he-will-lose-the-bet-copy-2/</guid>
      <description>I will take that bet.
You buy 1 BTC.
I will send $1M USD.
This is ~40:1 odds as 1 BTC is worth ~$26k.
The term is 90 days.
All we need is a mutually agreed custodian who will still be there to settle this in the event of digital dollar devaluation.
If someone knows how to do this… https://t.co/hhPr522PQu pic.twitter.com/6Aav9KeJpe
&amp;mdash; Balaji (@balajis) March 17, 2023 Having reviewed this tweet&amp;rsquo;s contents in detail, I find Balaji&amp;rsquo;s argument about inflation being a significant threat to the American economy quite persuasive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revamping My Blog Post Theme</title>
      <link>/posts/revamping-my-blog-post-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/revamping-my-blog-post-theme/</guid>
      <description>I am currently working on migrating and enhancing my blog&amp;rsquo;s theme and will not be posting for sometime. I intent to start posting again next year and port all the previous posts as soon as the new theme design and migration is done. Till then, you can reach out to me on Twitter(pinned above) DM. Have a great year ahead! 🤝</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal OKRs 2022</title>
      <link>/posts/personal-okrs-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/personal-okrs-2022/</guid>
      <description>Personal OKRs 2022</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Magic of Airdrops : Earn While Your Learn</title>
      <link>/posts/the-magic-of-airdrops-earn-while-you-learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-magic-of-airdrops-earn-while-you-learn/</guid>
      <description>Airdrops, in my opinion, are the fastest way to educate users about your product and get user adoption. For me, the starting point was ENS. Seeing my close friends earning ~ $10k through the ENS airdrop piqued my interest into ENS and that eventually led me to buying my own ENS domain.
Simply put, an airdrop is a distribution of a crypto token or coin, usually for free, to numerous wallet addresses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identify Your Echochamber</title>
      <link>/posts/identify-your-echochamber/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/identify-your-echochamber/</guid>
      <description>After 4 years, I have started using Social Media platforms again. While I had no difficulties posting (except stories on Instagram), there are certain observations and patterns that I have started to come across different social media platforms. Detailing them out here :
1.Twitter Tagline from a user&amp;rsquo;s perspective : I am smart and &amp;ldquo;intellectual&amp;rdquo; as well. Please koi meri bhi sun lo. From replying on Elon Musk&amp;rsquo;s and Balajis Tweets to posting random threads on why you should switch to Signal, Twitter is an echo - chamber of wanna be &amp;ldquo;intellectuals&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So You Want to Form New Habits?</title>
      <link>/posts/so-you-want-to-form-new-habits/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/so-you-want-to-form-new-habits/</guid>
      <description>Creating positive habits takes more than just willpower. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen by itself as it is more science than art. It requires constant re-evaluation of where you are spending time, people whom you are spending time with and your environment. Last year, I spent significant amount of time researching this and stumbled upon different books, bootcamps and blog posts that have proven to be really helpful in planning my day and subsequently, my week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What am I Reading These Days</title>
      <link>/posts/what-am-i-reading-these-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/what-am-i-reading-these-days/</guid>
      <description>With ~ 21 more books in the bag, the lockdown has turned out to be quite productive. Although I have tried to maintain variety in the kind of books and content that I read, a couple of books that have stood out for me are : Courage To Be Disliked by Ichiro Ishimi and Atomic Habits by James Clear. Going candid on this one:
Stating the names and description of the books that I liked and have read thus far:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Your Time Back</title>
      <link>/posts/getting-your-time-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/getting-your-time-back/</guid>
      <description>A few things that I have started doing to get back my time:
Setting an agenda for the meeting with the meeting invite. Agenda less meetings create confusion and lead to people talking about random things. 30 mins meeting by default as a calendar invite. This has helped me to close the open points quickly to free up time for important things. Putting slots on my calendar when I want to get work done without any distraction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strong Opinions Loosely Held</title>
      <link>/posts/strong-opinions-loosely-held-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/strong-opinions-loosely-held-copy/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Strong opinions, weakly held&amp;rdquo; is one of the frameworks used to deal with an uncertain future and yet, still move forward. It is one of the tools to become aware and have the courage to act on your knowledge, but also have the humility to doubt what we know. It is a framework that I use to prevent myself from seeing and hearing only the things that I like and discard others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Launching a Course on Venture Capital 101</title>
      <link>/posts/a-course-on-venture-capital/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/a-course-on-venture-capital/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;VC is a black box. It is a tightly knit community and this makes it really hard to know the inner workings of a VC fund. It is one thing to know about VC through blogs and books and another through a group of people who have been there, done that!&amp;rdquo;
These are some of the most common remarks that I&amp;rsquo;ve come across when speaking to most folks who aspire to break into Venture capital.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Habit Stacking Tools</title>
      <link>/posts/habit-stacking-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/habit-stacking-tools/</guid>
      <description>Some of my friends asked me to detail out the tools/platforms that I use to form and stick to my daily habits. Listing some of them down here :
A. Note - Taking
Evernote : Everything new that I come across goes into Evernote. I use 7 - 10 different accounts with each account having a different purpose such as writing, online learning, book summaries, designing. Notion : While some of the notebooks are same as that on Evernote, I use Notion when I’m using Desktop or on web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal OKRs 2021</title>
      <link>/posts/personal-okrs-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/personal-okrs-2021/</guid>
      <description>Personal OKRs 2021</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everything is a Product</title>
      <link>/posts/everything-is-a-product/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/everything-is-a-product/</guid>
      <description>This realisation came to me after reading the biographies of Michael Jordan and Leonardo Da Vinci. Some of the VCs and Product Folks in Silicon Valley also subscribe to this thought. They treat themselves and their careers as that of professional athletes. According to them, the way you conduct yourself, the way you eat, your personal journal or as a matter of fact, your fingernails are nothing but mini - products.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delhi Rant</title>
      <link>/posts/delhi-rant/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/delhi-rant/</guid>
      <description>I’ve stayed in Delhi - NCR for ~ 1.5 years now (since September 2019) and came back to Delhi after 14 years (after 2005). Now that I look back, there are certain observations that worry me about Delhi - Gurgaon culture. Listing them down here :
Overt celebration of eat-sleep-repeat culture : The common phrase that I hear most people use is : “ I don’t want to think too much and just chill”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Build a Successful Consumer Brand in India?</title>
      <link>/posts/how-to-build-a-successful-consumer-brand-in-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-to-build-a-successful-consumer-brand-in-india/</guid>
      <description>Fireside Ventures (a consumer focussed fund) closed their second fund worth $118 Million three days ago. This comes at a time when people in India (my parents included) are willing to try out new products and give challenger brands a try. As India&amp;rsquo;s retail market evolves, modern trade (likes of LeMarche) is set to account for 15% (from 8%) of the overall distribution whereas online retail is expected to account for 5% (currently at ~ 3%).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Rich Without Getting Lucky</title>
      <link>/posts/getting-rich-without-getting-lucky-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/getting-rich-without-getting-lucky-copy/</guid>
      <description>This is a summary of the framework used by Naval Ravikant to create order in chaos. Summarizing everything that I have learnt from his blogposts and podcasts:
Wealth vs Money vs Status
Seek wealth, not money or status. Wealth is having assets that earn while you sleep. Money is how we transfer time and wealth. Status is your place in the social hierarchy. Status is a zero sum game so, ignore those who enjoy playing this game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best of Masters of Scale</title>
      <link>/posts/best-of-masters-of-scale/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/best-of-masters-of-scale/</guid>
      <description>Below is the list of podcasts from Masters of Scale series that I found the most engaging and insightful. I finished listening to all its episodes last year. This is for those who are short on time and wondering where to start.
A Masterclass in Outsourcing with Luis von Ahn (Duolingo) Open or closed with Joe Ito : A podcast on community building The case for Bootstrapping with Ben Chestnut (Mailchimp) Be a platform with Tobi Lütke (Shopify) Escape the competition with Peter Thiel (Needs no introduction) Why culture matters with Reid Hastings (Netflix) New rules for big career changes with Jordan Harbinger : The best podcast that I found on mapping your career trajectory Build, Measure, Learn with non other than Eric Ries (Lean Startup) How to set the drumbeat with Jeff Weiner (LinkedIn - LinkedIn) Imperfect is perfect with Mark Zuckerberg Reid Hoffman Story : Part 2 - Make everyone a hero Raise more than you need with Mariam Naficy (Minted) 4 core principles of crisis management (Ellen Kullman) How to embrace conflict with Ray Dalio : This is my personal favourite The elusive formula for great hiring with Aneel Bhusri (Workday) How to Master Emotion with Sam Harris.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speed Reading</title>
      <link>/posts/speed-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/speed-reading/</guid>
      <description>Back in January, 2019, I came across a technique called “Speed Reading” on one of Tim Ferris’ videos. I was so intrigued by it that not only did I start “reading about speed reading” a lot, I also started practicing the same tirelessly. Since then, I have almost doubled my reading speed with increased retention and have started to summarise all the books that I read on Evernote (Will share them all and make it accessible to everyone by the end of this year).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is your superpower?</title>
      <link>/posts/what-is-your-superpower-copy-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/what-is-your-superpower-copy-2/</guid>
      <description>In one of the excerpt from the book No Filter: The Inside Story of Instagram, Kevin Systorm explains to Ashton Kutcher why Instagram blew up. It was not because of network effects. There were no network effects on day 1. It was not because of celebrity users. It was not because they rode on Twitter and Facebook graph of users. All of these happened later. Like most B2C products, it started as a single player use case: How to make your photos more beautiful, and shareable</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seek to Understand Before Trying to be Understood</title>
      <link>/posts/seek-to-understand-before-trying-to-be-understood/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/seek-to-understand-before-trying-to-be-understood/</guid>
      <description>People are just either not that interested in what you&amp;rsquo;re saying, or they are too focused on their own agenda. It&amp;rsquo;s ridiculous to see two people acting like they can’t really hear each other — by choice.
In &amp;ldquo;The Significance Principle,&amp;rdquo; authors Les Carter and Jim Underwood posit that we should listen past where the other person has finished. We should even pause before answering. Let them get their point, their story, their compliment, and even their criticism out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking in Pomodoros</title>
      <link>/posts/thinking-in-pomodoros-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/thinking-in-pomodoros-copy/</guid>
      <description>Last week (week from 24th May - 31st May) has turned out to be the most productive week in my life. Not that I have cut down on my side gigs or changed my priorities, but a simple addition of an age old technique called Pomodoro has changed the way I have started to think about time. Here’s how I see the difference :
The Old Me
Let me list down what I am supposed to do today and complete today’s To - Dos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Differentiating Yourself Through Social Media</title>
      <link>/posts/differeniating-yourself-through-social-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/differeniating-yourself-through-social-media/</guid>
      <description>Increasing number of users are spending their time online and are using social media tools to express themselves. Amidst this, can the activities (posts/likes/comments) performed by people on social media be used to hire candidates for different job profiles? I see this as a great way to differentiate candidates from others in cases where they have similar educational backgrounds, skill sets, and resumes.
We put ourselves out there whenever we post something, like/comment on a post, or update our Goodreads account with the latest book that we’ve read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal OKRs 2020</title>
      <link>/posts/personal-okrs-2020-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/personal-okrs-2020-/</guid>
      <description>Personal OKRs 2020</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
