<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ruchil Sharma</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ruchil Sharma</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
    <title>Deep Dives - Maker DAO</title>
    <link>/posts/maker-dao-deep-dive/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/maker-dao-deep-dive/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;Maker DAO is a well-known protocol that has been a pioneer in the decentralized finance (DeFi) space. In 2021, Maker Foundation took a significant step towards decentralization by &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.makerdao.com/the-maker-foundation-focuses-on-its-dissolution/&#34;&gt;dissolving itself&lt;/a&gt; and spinning up a DAO. As someone who has delved deep into the inner workings of Maker DAO over the past two weeks, I&amp;rsquo;ve gathered valuable insights and resources that will help anyone start contributing to Maker DAO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Major Events&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://forum.makerdao.com/t/the-endgame-plan-parts-1-2/15456&#34;&gt;The End Game Proposal&lt;/a&gt; - Last year, Rune Christensen, the founder of Maker DAO, put forth a proposal that outlined the constitution and end game for Maker DAO. This proposal aimed to streamline the governance structure and achieve true decentralization. This proposal has been considered one of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://vote.makerdao.com/polling/QmTmS5Nf#vote-breakdown&#34;&gt;largest restructurings in its history&lt;/a&gt; and the proposal has passed with significant support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://forum.makerdao.com/t/simple-makerdao-governance-from-first-principles/16207&#34;&gt;Hasu&amp;rsquo;s Proposal&lt;/a&gt; - Hasu, a Maker DAO delegate, had put forward a proposal advocating for the creation of a constitution and a council of Makers. This proposal had sparked debate within the Maker community as it presented a differing perspective compared to Rune&amp;rsquo;s proposal and resulted in a division of opinions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://forum.makerdao.com/t/can-we-justify-the-existential-risk-posed-by-psm-usdc/16180/14&#34;&gt;Mitigating PSM concerns during Tornado Cash Sanctions&lt;/a&gt; : In June 2022, a number of Maker DAO members expressed concerns about the protocol&amp;rsquo;s reliance on USDC to maintain the stability of DAI&amp;rsquo;s peg. This was due to the fact that Circle, the company behind USDC, had blacklisted addresses associated with Tornado cash. This raised questions within the Maker DAO community about the possibility of Circle blacklisting USDC in the PSM vault, which would have a major impact on DAI&amp;rsquo;s stability. The PSM vault, which held $3B worth of USDC, was not generating any returns for Maker DAO and posed a significant risk to DAI&amp;rsquo;s peg. To mitigate the risks associated with relying solely on USDC, the Maker DAO community undertook two major initiatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generating 1.5% reward on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coinbase.com/blog/coinbase-launches-usdc-institutional-rewards-program-with-makerdao&#34;&gt;$1.6B worth of assets&lt;/a&gt; through Coinbase institutional rewards program.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Giving &lt;a href=&#34;https://mips.makerdao.com/mips/details/MIP65#sentence-summary&#34;&gt;$500M assets to Monetalis&lt;/a&gt; to deploy those funds or buying treasuries and deploying it to real World Assets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://forum.makerdao.com/t/adding-real-world-assets-rwa-as-dai-collateral-is-a-critical-step-for-maker-to-stabilize-the-peg-and-in-doing-so-we-change-the-world/3653&#34;&gt;Onboarding Real World Assets&lt;/a&gt; : To address the concerns regarding DAI&amp;rsquo;s peg  and diversification of the collateral asset class, Maker DAO introduced Real World Assets (RWA) as collateral for DAI. As a significant milestone, Maker DAO successfully onboarded Huntingdon Valley Bank to open a $100M DAI loan, creating a huge buzz in both the DeFi and TradFi World.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maker&amp;rsquo;s Governance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Off chain governance&lt;/em&gt; - Off-chain governance refers to processes for making decisions that don&amp;rsquo;t require on-chain voting and gathering feedback prior to on-chain voting. Off-chain governance happens on the Maker Governance Forum, where the community meets to propose and discuss new proposals. Anyone can participate in off-chain governance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Informal Polls&lt;/em&gt; -
Informal Polls make use of the forum&amp;rsquo;s support for poll creation. Informal Polls provide a set of options for the community to vote on. Although more structured than discussions, they cannot effect protocol changes nor trigger processes immediately; they are commonly used to measure community sentiment about issues affecting the MakerDAO ecosystem. Informal Polls can be created by anyone and there are no guidelines on the general use of Informal Polls other than courtesy and common sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Signal Requests&lt;/em&gt;
Signal Requests are the most immediately powerful means of effecting change off-chain. Signal Requests are a type of poll whose specific parameters and necessity are established by processes that have been ratified within the MIPs Framework. The nature of the effects of Signal Requests can vary greatly in accordance to the MIP-ratified process that requires or allows Signal Requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Governance Polling&lt;/em&gt; - Polling proposals are voted upon by MKR holders. Governance Polls occur on-chain and are used to measure the sentiment of MKR voters. Polls often run concurrently, allowing voters to participate in any number of them at the same time. Polls may have different formats like Binary Voting, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ranked_voting&#34;&gt;Instant Run-Off Voting&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Approval_voting&#34;&gt;Approval Voting&lt;/a&gt; depending on the topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Executive Votes&lt;/em&gt; - Executive Votes execute technical changes to the Maker Protocol. When active, each Executive Vote has a proposed set of changes being made to the Maker Protocol&amp;rsquo;s smart contracts. Executive Votes use a Continuous Approval Voting model. Executive Votes can occur at any time, but the current schedule calls for Executive Votes to go live on Wednesdays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The MakerDAO&amp;rsquo;s governance cycle is split into two distinct time frames&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://forum.makerdao.com/t/mip16-the-weekly-governance-cycle/3008&#34;&gt;Weekly Governance Cycle&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
    src=&#34;https://github.com/makerdao/mips/blob/master/MIP16/weekly_governance_cycle.png?raw=true&#34; 
    alt=&#34;!img&#34; 
     /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://forum.makerdao.com/t/mip3-governance-cycle/1905/5&#34;&gt;Monthly Governance Cycle&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
    src=&#34;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/53664591/114054203-8c7de580-9887-11eb-90da-0431b051fff3.png&#34; 
    alt=&#34;img&#34; 
     /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This diagram provides a comprehensive overview of Maker DAO&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://manual.makerdao.com/governance/flowcharts/governance-flow&#34;&gt;governance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
    src=&#34;https://1532779581-files.gitbook.io/~/files/v0/b/gitbook-x-prod.appspot.com/o/spaces%2F1H5WOQe0EwkbgnI9bkOd%2Fuploads%2Fgit-blob-6f98f286bfdd18a4e747ceed2201c24d4fa86f29%2Fgovernance-flowchart.png?alt=media&#34; 
    alt=&#34;image&#34; 
     /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tokenomics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can think of Maker DAO as a bank that provides lending services in a permissionless manner, where borrowers are required to lock in collateral. Whenever a user deposits collateral, Maker DAO generates its own stablecoin, DAI, on the blockchain. Borrowers have the freedom to use DAI as they please, but they are charged a stability fee by Maker DAO as long as they hold DAI. To understand the tokenomics of Maker DAO, you can refer to the diagram below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
    src=&#34;https://miro.medium.com/v2/resize:fit:720/0*jbg1VUlK4T_YD3NJ&#34; 
    alt=&#34;image&#34; 
     /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get a comprehensive understanding of Maker DAO&amp;rsquo;s tokenomics, I recommend going through this &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o4uR3_kiwrw&#34;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; and this &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/tokenomics-dao/tokenomics-101-makerdao-a083410aa158&#34;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To quote one of the Core Unit Members of Maker DAO from my recent conversation &amp;ldquo;It is an exciting time to start contributing to Maker DAO, as the organization is undergoing a major shift that will create many opportunities.I&amp;rsquo;d suggest folks who want to contriute to lurk around Discord and the forum and start contributing to the discussions&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resources&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reverie.ooo/podcast-episode/rune-christensen-makerdaos-past-present-and-future&#34;&gt;Rune Christensen - MakerDAO&amp;rsquo;s Past, Present, and Future&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/monetsupply-perspectives-on-makerdao-governance/id1587401478?i=1000569708752&#34;&gt;MonetSupply - Perspectives on MakerDAO Governance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.makerdao.com/smart-contract-modules/core-module&#34;&gt;Core Modules of Maker DAO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://makerburn.com/#/&#34;&gt;Maker Burn Dashboard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://daistats.com/&#34;&gt;DAI Stats Dashboard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Balaji is right, but he may lose the bet</title>
    <link>/posts/balaji-is-right-but-he-will-lose-the-bet/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/balaji-is-right-but-he-will-lose-the-bet/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;I will take that bet.&lt;br&gt;You buy 1 BTC.&lt;br&gt;I will send $1M USD.&lt;br&gt;This is ~40:1 odds as 1 BTC is worth ~$26k.&lt;br&gt;The term is 90 days.&lt;br&gt;All we need is a mutually agreed custodian who will still be there to settle this in the event of digital dollar devaluation.&lt;br&gt;If someone knows how to do this… &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/hhPr522PQu&#34;&gt;https://t.co/hhPr522PQu&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/6Aav9KeJpe&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/6Aav9KeJpe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Balaji (@balajis) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/balajis/status/1636797265317867520?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;March 17, 2023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
 &lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having reviewed this tweet&amp;rsquo;s contents in detail, I find Balaji&amp;rsquo;s argument about inflation being a significant threat to the American economy quite persuasive. However, I remain unconvinced that the average citizien has the time to go into these complex details and subsequently exit to Bitcoin. The majority of people will likely accept the Federal Reserve&amp;rsquo;s explanation, which will be disseminated through various channels, and will continue to invest their money in the fiat system. Although the average American may have lost faith in the Fed, they are yet to reach the point of taking their hard-earned dollars out of the fiat system. They may have exited their trust, they will not exit thier $$&amp;rsquo;s right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To quote &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/worldnews/europe/eu/10874230/Jean-Claude-Juncker-profile-When-it-becomes-serious-you-have-to-lie.html&#34;&gt;Jean-Claude Juncker&lt;/a&gt;: &amp;ldquo;When it becomes serious, you have to lie&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think most people will believe that lie for a little longer.&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Revamping My Blog Post Theme</title>
    <link>/posts/revamping-my-blog-post-theme/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/revamping-my-blog-post-theme/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;I am currently working on migrating and enhancing my blog&amp;rsquo;s theme and will not be posting for sometime. I intent to start posting again next year and port all the previous posts as soon as the new theme design and migration is done. Till then, you can reach out to me on Twitter(pinned above) DM. Have a great year ahead! 🤝&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Personal OKRs 2022</title>
    <link>/posts/personal-okrs-2022/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/personal-okrs-2022/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://axiomatic-diver-1c4.notion.site/6506f40d988e426590ee8abe5ae12bea?v=e5de44c28ea540f6a45c98fea43a80e3&#34; title=&#34;Personal OKRs 2022&#34;&gt;Personal OKRs 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>The Magic of Airdrops : Earn While Your Learn</title>
    <link>/posts/the-magic-of-airdrops-earn-while-you-learn/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/the-magic-of-airdrops-earn-while-you-learn/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;Airdrops, in my opinion, are the fastest way to educate users about your product and get user adoption. For me, the starting point was ENS. Seeing my close friends earning ~ $10k through the ENS airdrop piqued my interest into ENS and that eventually led me to buying my own ENS domain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply put, an airdrop is a distribution of a crypto token or coin, usually for free, to numerous wallet addresses. But it is not as trivial as it sounds. The caveat here is that an airdrop comes with the price. For one to be eligible for receiving an airdrop, one needs to use a protocol and interact with it in a manner prescribed by the protocol. Hence, as a user, you might end up spending at least the gas price in order to be eligible for a token airdrop. As I did not own an ENS domain when ENS announced the airdrop, I was not eligible for the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
    src=&#34;https://images.mirror-media.xyz/publication-images/Ur8NGD1r88Og_SZdobelO.png?height=926%5cu0026width=1164&#34; 
    alt=&#34;image&#34; 
     /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what I saw when I tried connecting my wallet to earn the airdrop
This is what I saw when I tried connecting my wallet to earn the airdrop
While I was initially hesitant spending $50 - $100 as gas fees to use a protocol, I am a lot more comfortable doing so now. If you are someone who is full time into crypto and whose primary source of income depends on understanding different crypto ecosystems, gas fees is the cost you pay to educate yourself. After buying my ENS domain, I have used several other protocols and have paid more than a $1,000 (might be insignificant for a lot of you) in gas fees to educate myself about different protocols and ecosystems while prioritising those who have a high likelihood of announcing an airdrop soon. You can find them here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To conclude, if you are someone who is getting started with Web 3.0 and is not undergoing financial crisis, don’t let gas fee be a blocker to use a protocol and understand its nuances. The value that you derive from going deeper into the rabbit hole, ecosystem understanding, friends that you make along the way and the value of the potential airdrops far outweighs the amount that you will spend as gas fees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a side-note, I strongly believe that till the point L2 scaling solutions are not widely adopted, all Web 3 companies that require their employees/community members to have a deep understanding of the Web 3.0 ecosystem should set aside funds dedicated towards protocols/Dapps usage and gas fees. This can be a great differentiator and incentive to lure talented folks into your ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Identify Your Echochamber</title>
    <link>/posts/identify-your-echochamber/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/identify-your-echochamber/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;After 4 years, I have started using Social Media platforms again. While I had no difficulties posting (except stories on Instagram), there are certain observations and patterns that I have started to come across different social media platforms. Detailing them out here :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.&lt;strong&gt;Twitter&lt;/strong&gt; Tagline from a user&amp;rsquo;s perspective : I am smart and &amp;ldquo;intellectual&amp;rdquo; as well. Please koi
meri bhi sun lo. From replying on Elon Musk&amp;rsquo;s and Balajis Tweets to posting random threads on why you should
switch to Signal, Twitter is an echo - chamber of wanna be &amp;ldquo;intellectuals&amp;rdquo;. While Twitter does
help one get deep insights into any topic from some of the most credible individuals, it is also
an echo - chamber of people who are &amp;ldquo;faking&amp;rdquo; it till they make it. There&amp;rsquo;s nothing right/wrong in
this. Well, who doesn&amp;rsquo;t like to have a million followers! But what I&amp;rsquo;ll really appreciate is a following built on one&amp;rsquo;s substance, skills and not copy pasted Tweets, or networking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.&lt;strong&gt;Instagram&lt;/strong&gt; Tagline from a user&amp;rsquo;s perspective : I can post, apply filters, travel to Thailand and
Dubai. Mein bhi fake Picasso. Scrolling through some of the posts on Instagram is a sheer delight as it is one of the biggest echo chambers. Same is the case with Facebook. A snapshot of the post. I would appreciate if people can bring some innovation to their replies and not copy/paste &amp;ldquo;great&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;wow&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are the smartest individual and get validated from others all the time, you are doing more harm than good to yourself. It is time to leave the table and join a new one when you stop getting pushback from your inner circle/ community. You are just fooling yourself and hiding your insecurities otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be a philosophical king, one needs to become a king first. So, moving forward, I&amp;rsquo;ll avoid posting generic stuff unless I am really tempted to.&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>So You Want to Form New Habits?</title>
    <link>/posts/so-you-want-to-form-new-habits/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/so-you-want-to-form-new-habits/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;Creating positive habits takes more than just willpower. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen by itself as it is more science than art. It requires constant re-evaluation of where you are spending time, people whom you are spending time with and your environment. Last year, I spent significant amount of time researching this and stumbled upon different books, bootcamps and blog posts that have proven to be really helpful in planning my day and subsequently, my week. This blog post is to detail out my learnings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.in/dp/B07R6VQBSZ/ref=dp-kindle-redirect?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;btkr=1&#34;&gt;1. Tiny Habits by BJ Fogg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prof. B.J. Fogg is the founder of the Behaviour Design Lab at Stanford University and teaches industry
innovators how behaviour really works. Kevin Systrom (founder of Instagram) was one of BJ Fogg’s
students and as in the case with any other product, habit formation is one of the core elements of Instagram (stories being one of them).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to BJ Fogg, any behaviour can be broken down into three elements :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Motivation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prompt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Behaviour = MAP&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Motivation&lt;/strong&gt; :  The least effective strategy to form new habits as one feels highly motivated during the day and less as the day goes by.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ability&lt;/strong&gt;: Make the action so tiny that your ability to do it increases significantly. Want to lose 10 kgs in 3 months? Just visit the gym and come out for the first three days. Want to start your own blog?
Great, open any notepad and start jotting down your thoughts. We overestimate what we can achieve in the short run and underestimate what we can in the long run. Consistency &amp;raquo; Magnitude of Work Done&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prompt&lt;/strong&gt; : This is the easiest to manage among all three. Your environment speaks volumes about how serious you are about getting the job done. Designing the environment that is conducive to successful
completion of a behaviour is often underestimated. A few examples would be setting up the alarm to go for a run, turning off social media notifications (prompt removal) while focussing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
    src=&#34;https://behaviormodel.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Fogg-Behavior-Model.jpg&#34; 
    alt=&#34;image&#34; 
     /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other hacks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Habit Chain : Any of the following factors can act as a friction to form new habits successfully :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Money&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Physical Effort&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mental Effort&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Routine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pinpoint the exact root cause and try to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fear and self - doubt decrease the likelihood of habit formation whereas hope increases the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.in/Atomic-Habits-James-Clear/dp/1847941834/ref=sr_1_2?dchild=1&amp;amp;keywords=atomic+habits&amp;amp;qid=1610539028&amp;amp;sr=8-2&#34;&gt;2. Atomic Habits by James Clear&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make the habit an obvious thing to do&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make it attractive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make it easy (by increasing the ability)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make it satisfying : By enjoying the process and celebrating after the successful completion of the desired behaviour.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
    src=&#34;https://expertprogrammanagement.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Atomic-Habits_-Plateau-of-Latent-Potential.png&#34; 
    alt=&#34;image&#34; 
     /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other Hacks&lt;/strong&gt; :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Batching&lt;/strong&gt; : Club similar habits together to get things done. One example could be listening to podcast while going for a walk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Embracing Boredom&lt;/strong&gt; : It takes a long time to successfully build and sustain new habits, so embrace boredom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Process over Outcomes&lt;/strong&gt; : Focus on completing the habit rather than achieving the goal. It takes a while to realise the power of compounding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Role of friends and family&lt;/strong&gt; : Choose your peers wisely. Peers who will contribute towards the successful change in habits. Everything else is secondary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Change the content of self - talk&lt;/strong&gt; : If you want to read more, do not tell yourself : “I want to read more&amp;quot;; instead say &amp;ldquo;I am a reader”. The key to building lasting habits is focusing on creating a new identity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other resources that you may refer to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.in/Power-Habit-Why-What-Change/dp/1847946240/ref=sr_1_3?crid=3OG16L8DTKU74&amp;amp;dchild=1&amp;amp;keywords=power+of+habit+charles+duhigg&amp;amp;qid=1610533836&amp;amp;sprefix=power+of+habit+Charles+%2Caps%2C289&amp;amp;sr=8-3&#34;&gt;Power of habit by Charles Duhigg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.in/Hooked-How-Build-Habit-Forming-Products/dp/0241184835/ref=sr_1_1?dchild=1&amp;amp;keywords=hooked+nir+eyal&amp;amp;qid=1610533881&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34;&gt;Hooked by Nir Eyal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/show/7BQZHMsYPInemu2GMVSYNH&#34;&gt;Jim Kwik Podcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bjfogg.com/bootcamp&#34;&gt;Tiny Habits Bootcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.habitify.me&#34;&gt;Habit tracking apps such as Habitify, Checklist+&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Making your goals public to ensure accountability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the goals that I have this year is to get at least one blog post out each week using the above framework.&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>What am I Reading These Days</title>
    <link>/posts/what-am-i-reading-these-days/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/what-am-i-reading-these-days/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;With ~ 21 more books in the bag, the lockdown has turned out to be quite productive. Although I have tried to maintain variety in the kind of books and content that I read, a couple of books that have stood out for me are : Courage To Be Disliked by Ichiro Ishimi and Atomic Habits by James Clear. Going candid on this one:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stating the names and description of the books that I liked and have read thus far:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/18656827-hatching-twitter&#34;&gt;Hatching Twitter&lt;/a&gt; : Politics, betrayal and loads of money. The only thing missing in
this one is infidelity (wait, shayad wo bhi hai), for it to become a superhit movie. Have started stalking Jack Dorsey after this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/34466963-why-we-sleep&#34;&gt;Why We Sleep?&lt;/a&gt;: I&amp;rsquo;m mostly sleep deprived and have been sleeping for less than 6 hours
for quite sometime now, but this book has come across as a  lightning bolt. Never in my life have I recommended someone to rest and sleep properly, but now I do. An eye opener and a must read!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/40499078-let-s-talk-money&#34;&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s Talk Money&lt;/a&gt;: A great starter for those looking for investment advice and save a
few bucks to check off that bucket list. I was already practicing most of the things mentioned in the book and will share the summary soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/40121378-atomic-habits&#34;&gt;Atomic Habits&lt;/a&gt;: One of the best books on habit formation and how we make decisions.
This one is an ultimate guide to become aware about your bad habits and replace them with the good ones. Iska to itna bada fan ban gaya hun k physical copy saath lekar h sota hun.
Next One : B.J. Fogg&amp;rsquo;s : Tiny Habits. Although I&amp;rsquo;ve seen most of his videos&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/50772888-no-filter&#34;&gt;No Filter : The Inside Story of Instagram&lt;/a&gt;: Although I am not a big fan of Instagram
as a product, this book describes how two passionate founders with complementary skill sets decided to
take on Benchmark backed portfolio company. Although the initial vision of Instagram was very different from what it has become now (Zuckerbro taking over again), I just love the fact that both Kevin and Mike left facebook when Zuck tried to take over and dominate the vision of the company. (Kevin Systrom made ~ 800M in the process)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/52346729-big-billion-startup&#34;&gt;Big Billion Startup : The Flipkart Story&lt;/a&gt; : Isme bhi, Twitter level politics, but at
a much smaller scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/8034188-where-good-ideas-come-from&#34;&gt;Steven Johnson : Where Good Ideas Come From&lt;/a&gt;: Well, shower and an evening walk. Hahah. On
a serious note, this goes deeper into how we think and how ideas shape up in our heads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/900.The_Game&#34;&gt;The Game : Neil Strauss&lt;/a&gt;: Welcome to the community of pickup artists. Isn&amp;rsquo;t
this enough to make you read the book?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/44573628-super-pumped&#34;&gt;Super Pumped : The Battle of Uber&lt;/a&gt;: Well, no matter how much all of us criticize/
ridicule Travis Kalanick, he has revolutionized the entire transportation industry through Uber. Iska bhi fan ban gaya hun. Do watch some of his talks on Youtube!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/18197267-don-t-make-me-think-revisited&#34;&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t Make Me Think&lt;/a&gt;: This one made me think a lot. A brief read on how things are
designed on web and mobile in general and best practices that one should follow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/25416321-actionable-gamification&#34;&gt;Gamification&lt;/a&gt;: I was fascinated by how gamification can be used to
influence consumer psychology. Ended up completing a course on Coursera on the same!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/840.The_Design_of_Everyday_Things?ac=1&amp;amp;from_search=true&amp;amp;qid=lZCtNNKZy6&amp;amp;rank=1&#34;&gt;Design of Everyday Things&lt;/a&gt;: The next time you are unable to open that annoying door,
curse its designer, but do not blame yourself. Loved reading this one. Summary coming out soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/44428950-that-will-never-work&#34;&gt;That Will Never Work : Birth of Netflix&lt;/a&gt;: Well, it worked. Netflix par hai.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/368593.The_4_Hour_Workweek&#34;&gt;4-Hour Workweek&lt;/a&gt;: I wish ye jaldi h ho jaye. This suggests you to earn your living by
building specific knowledge (Naval Ravikant&amp;rsquo;s framework) across different domains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/43306206-the-courage-to-be-disliked&#34;&gt;Courage To Be Disliked&lt;/a&gt;: Last, but this one tops the lot. Unlike its name, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t
tell you to do things that make others dislike you, but the fact that others dislike you makes you free. Kaafi deep hai. A must read for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/user/show/54195959-ruchil&#34;&gt;the list&lt;/a&gt; of all the books that I&amp;rsquo;ve read this year. For the remaining half of this year, I intend to read a lot on technology, design, food and health, personal finance, investing and politics (ye zyada nahi). Along with this, I intend to read all the publicly available reports on different industries published by BCG, Mckinsey, CB Insights, VC funds, and create my own personal models and frameworks.&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Getting Your Time Back</title>
    <link>/posts/getting-your-time-back/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/getting-your-time-back/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;A few things that I have started doing to get back my time:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setting an agenda for the meeting with the meeting invite. Agenda less meetings create confusion and
lead to people talking about random things.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;30 mins meeting by default as a calendar invite. This has helped me to close the open points quickly to
free up time for important things.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Putting slots on my calendar when I want to get work done without any distraction. I cancel/
reschedule all meetings if they clash during that time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ending meetings early or declining to attend those that do not provide any insight/actionable. I also
make sure that one of the attendees or I share the actionables from a meeting with all the relevant    stakeholders within 24 hours of the meeting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not attending calls/meetings just because they are on my calendar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While talking feedback and ideas from relevant stakeholders is important, executing low impact ideas may
not be the best use of your time. To avoid this, I try to make the person who proposes an idea think.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;End meetings early if you are done discussing the action items. No point extending the meeting for an
hour just because the calendar invite was for one hour.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You may wish to choose &lt;a href=&#34;https://asana.com/resources/eisenhower-matrix#:~:text=The%20Eisenhower%20Matrix%20is%20a,the%20tasks%20you&#39;ll%20delete.&#34;&gt;Eisenhover Matrix&lt;/a&gt; to prioritise your work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Strong Opinions Loosely Held</title>
    <link>/posts/strong-opinions-loosely-held-copy/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/strong-opinions-loosely-held-copy/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bobsutton.typepad.com/my_weblog/2006/07/strong_opinions.html&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Strong opinions, weakly held&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; is one of the frameworks used to deal with an uncertain future and yet, still move forward. It is one of the tools to become aware and have the courage to act on your knowledge, but also have the humility to doubt what we know. It is a framework that I use to prevent myself from seeing and hearing only the things that I like and discard others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Being ruthlessly honest with yourself&lt;/strong&gt; : Whenever we feel disappointed or despondent in life, we
tend to blame either the triggers or the circumstances or both (if they are one and the same thing). But while building our hypothesis about why we feel the way we do, we forget about our actions. Example that comes to my mind right now is &amp;ldquo;I could not do X, because of Y&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;I did X, because of Y&amp;rdquo;. Rarely does the Y in this statement involve us. Being self - critical and self - aware is as important as caring about oneself.
This pertains to a long held debate between Freudian and Adlerian psychology. Freud&amp;rsquo;s idea is that a person&amp;rsquo;s psychic wounds, disappointments, feelings cause his/her present unhappiness whereas Adler&amp;rsquo;s view states that we are not determined by our experiences, but by the meaning we give them . Read more about this &lt;a href=&#34;https://sipreads.com/the-courage-to-be-disliked/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. To quote Elon Musk : &amp;ldquo;A well thought out critique of whatever you are doing is as valuable as gold&amp;rdquo;. Hence, seeking constant feedback about your skills, behaviour, and conduct from your friends, acquaintance and family members is a great way to identify the area of improvements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;What&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;How&amp;rdquo; are equally important&lt;/strong&gt; : This will come really handy while implementing the first
point. More often than not, we come across situations when we have to work with someone we do not like or when we are required to give feedback to someone. Imagine working with that one colleague of yours whom you absolutely despise or rehearsing a difficult conversation you have been planning to have with your close friend (about a thing that he/she annoys you with).In such situations, the one thing that I make sure of is communicating my feedback while keeping a check on how I communicate the same.
Knowing that &amp;ldquo;what&amp;rdquo; is something that the other person might not like, working on the &amp;ldquo;how&amp;rdquo; helps soften the blow. The intention here should not be to hurt the other person, but to communicate your feedback and help the other person improve on those areas. If he/she takes the feedback in a positive spirit and is willing to change, you have helped someone to grow personally/professionally. If he/she is not willing to budge and is not self - aware about his/her strengths/weaknesses, see how he/she reacts to point 1. You might be able to change someone&amp;rsquo;s World view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Giving and Seeking Advice&lt;/strong&gt; : Reject most advice. As per &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ScottAdamsSays?ref_src=twsrc%5Egoogle%7Ctwcamp%5Eserp%7Ctwgr%5Eauthor&#34;&gt;Scott Adams&lt;/a&gt;, follow systems
and not goals. Most people (including your friends and family members) are sharing their lottery numbers, which were applicable to them, but may not be applicable to you. There is definitely something to be learnt from them, but we can&amp;rsquo;t take the exact same advice and map it onto our circumstances. That may turn out to be detrimental. The best people that I&amp;rsquo;ve known and worked with read everything, listen to everyone, and ignore all of it. Seeking a 360 degree feedback helps them to clarify the problem, but not the solution. These folks already have their personal model of how to apply things to their situation and they do not hesitate to discard all information. People will always offer advice if you seek one (on topics they have absolutely no idea about such as career,investments,and even relationships), but it is you who has to face the consequences. Start asking people to put some amount of money on the line or have some skin in the game, and see how their advice changes. One great book to read on this topic : &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/36064445-skin-in-the-game?from_search=true&amp;amp;from_srp=true&amp;amp;qid=XW6mDhxbYM&amp;amp;rank=1&#34;&gt;Skin in the Game&lt;/a&gt;. You can choose to discard whatever I&amp;rsquo;ve written in this blog post if my advice does not align with your model (have one if you already don&amp;rsquo;t).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Questioning More&lt;/strong&gt;: Our Worldview is formed mainly from what others have told us. Most things that we
identify as true have been told to us by our parents, friends and media. We never bother to question them and form our worldview around these. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Five_whys&#34;&gt;&amp;lsquo;Five Whys&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt; is one of the frameworks that one can use to question things. You will stop at one of the three things when you keep questioning a particular statement or belief:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Endless series of Why&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Circular reasoning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An axiom&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am really looking forward to read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/44245196-the-great-mental-models&#34;&gt;The Great Mental Models&lt;/a&gt; to go deeper into this topic&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The abundance problem&lt;/strong&gt; : Ancient struggles involved scarcity. Modern struggles are struggles that
involve abundance. People in previous generations were always looking out for food, entertainment, and resources which are abundant in the modern economy. In the modern economy, we are over - exposed to almost everything and a human brain is not designed to take the click bait headline news at the current rate. Teams of statisticians and programmers are working out of Silicon Valley to make sure that you spend more time on these social media and news platforms. The most powerful people of this generation are not politicians, but the developers who are writing the algorithms for social media platforms such as Facebook, Instagram, Twitter, TikTok and Snapchat. One great tool that I&amp;rsquo;ve found to better handle this problem is &lt;a href=&#34;https://freedom.to&#34;&gt;Freedom&lt;/a&gt;. Do check it out! Additionally, saying &amp;ldquo;no&amp;rdquo; as a default response and putting a price to my time has also been very helpful to navigate the abundance issue.Too much socialising might turn out to be the biggest problem of this generation(transitioning one). The next generation IMO will learn to deal with these click bait platforms and ads way better than the current one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Words from the man himself : &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=J54k7WrbfMg&#34;&gt;Chamath Palihapitiya&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Embracing Boredom&lt;/strong&gt; : Mastery is never an accident. You can win the lottery and become rich
overnight, but no one has ever mastered their craft by chance. Whether we are talking about athletes, artists, or academics, the story is the same. If you want to fulfill your potential then you must practice a specific skill for a long time with remarkable consistency. Of course, whenever “experts” share stories about successful people they often leave out a key ingredient of the story. How, exactly, do top performers fall in love with boredom? Perhaps more importantly, how can you fall in love with boredom when you&amp;rsquo;re trying to build a habit that you know you should do, but you don&amp;rsquo;t really want to do. Success is often found by practicing the fundamentals that everyone knows they should be doing, but they find too boring or basic to practice routinely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quoting Steve Wozniak (Co - founder of Apple):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
    src=&#34;https://github.com/23Ruchil/Blog/blob/gh-pages/assets/Images/Image-1.jpeg?raw=true&#34; 
    alt=&#34;image&#34; 
     /&gt;
&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
    src=&#34;https://github.com/23Ruchil/Blog/blob/gh-pages/assets/Images/Image-2.jpeg?raw=true&#34; 
    alt=&#34;image&#34; 
     /&gt;
&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
    src=&#34;https://github.com/23Ruchil/Blog/blob/gh-pages/assets/Images/Image-4.jpeg?raw=true&#34; 
    alt=&#34;image&#34; 
     /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Valuing friends and relationships&lt;/strong&gt; : The answers to all great questions are paradoxical in nature.
Believing that life is a single player game is okay, but having friends and relationships (and valuing them) to help you navigate difficult circumstances in life is extremely important (while keeping point 3 in mind). Asking the meaning of life and &amp;ldquo;Why am I here&amp;rdquo; is something that we all do. The real beauty lies not in the answer, but in the question itself. Each one of us should look to complete this sentence &amp;ldquo;I exist because&amp;hellip;.&amp;rdquo; instead of asking &amp;ldquo;Why do I exist?&amp;rdquo;. Ask &amp;ldquo;where can I contribute&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;what excites me&amp;rdquo; instead of &amp;ldquo;what is the meaning of life&amp;rdquo;. Do watch this &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3qHkcs3kG44&#34;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; if you want to dig deeper into this topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: I will keep expanding this list.&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Launching a Course on Venture Capital 101</title>
    <link>/posts/a-course-on-venture-capital/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/a-course-on-venture-capital/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;VC is a black box. It is a tightly knit community and this makes it really hard to know the inner workings of a VC fund. It is one thing to know about VC through blogs and books and another through a group of people who have been there, done that!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are some of the most common remarks that I&amp;rsquo;ve come across when speaking to most folks who aspire to break into Venture capital. From those in B - schools to those working in corporates, getting into a Venture Capital firm seems a far fetched dream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I entered Venture Capital with the expectation of helping founders build scalable products, but was given a reality check once I got to know the inner workings of the fund. Why would a founder who has spent somewhere between 2 - 10 years take my advice in building the product?  The best way to know how to build a scalable product is to build one yourself. I exited the world of Venture Capital to be a part of product building myself and with the expectation to make a return after gaining foundational skillsets in my arsenal so that I can be of enough value to the founders later in my career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that being said, a stint at a VC fund teaches you a number of things. The first and most important one being selfless. One needs to be selfless while reaching out to the founders and empathise with them. While there are enough smart folks around, founders are the ones with courage. They are the ones who dream big; who provide employment to millions of individuals. VCs cannot exist without such founders, but founders can thrive without VCs! Some of the other skills that one picks during a stint at a VC firm are structured thinking, discipline, relationship building (networking being a fancy word used for this), and building, refining intuition pertaining to different sectors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To ensure that more folks do not repeat the mistakes that we&amp;rsquo;ve made, we are launching a course on Venture Capital 101. The objective of this course is to familiarise VC aspirants with how a VC firm functions and help them get a stint at one. We do not guarantee a job out of this course and hence, are only interested in speaking those who wish to learn about Venture Capital. You can find the details about the course &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.notion.so/Course-Structure-VC-101-0ba0ab2cc7164295b0cba7691c4b6a26&#34;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we may not have a large investment portfolio , we have ambition. If you are working in a VC firm or on ex - VC who would like to contribute in teaching, get in touch with us. We need more hands!&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Habit Stacking Tools</title>
    <link>/posts/habit-stacking-tools/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/habit-stacking-tools/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;Some of my friends asked me to detail out the tools/platforms that I use to form and stick to my daily habits. Listing some of them down here :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A. &lt;strong&gt;Note - Taking&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://evernote.com/&#34;&gt;Evernote&lt;/a&gt; : Everything new that I come across goes into Evernote. I use 7 - 10 different accounts with each account having a different purpose such as writing, online learning, book summaries, designing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.notion.so/&#34;&gt;Notion&lt;/a&gt; : While some of the notebooks are same as that on Evernote, I use Notion when I’m using Desktop or on web. Notion is a place where all my notes are structured so that I can pull info. on any topic anytime.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gingerlabs.com/&#34;&gt;Notability&lt;/a&gt; : One of the best apps for taking notes. The experience of writing on a paper using a pen/pencil is unbeatable. I use Notability on iPad and iPhone along with Apple Pencil and compile all of my notes on Notion at the end of each week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.google.android.keep&amp;amp;hl=en_IN&amp;amp;gl=US&#34;&gt;Google Keep&lt;/a&gt; : Everything high level/strategic goals here&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.whatsapp.com/?lang=en&#34;&gt;Whatsapp&lt;/a&gt; : The best note - taking app out there. I have 15 - 20 different groups where I share notes to myself and subsequently, put it all on Notion at the end of each week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B. Reading&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://outreadapp.com/&#34;&gt;Outread&lt;/a&gt; : This is one of the best apps that can help you read at 500 wpm with quality retention. Highly recommend this one.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://speechify.com/&#34;&gt;Speechify&lt;/a&gt; : I use Speechify to read articles that I find online at 400wpm - 500wpm. Not the best product out there as it does not help one to bucketize the articles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.amazon.kindle&amp;amp;hl=en_IN&amp;amp;gl=US&#34;&gt;Kindle&lt;/a&gt; : I use Kindle on rare occasions as it does not have speed reading tracker built into it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/&#34;&gt;GoodReads&lt;/a&gt; : I summarise all my books on Goodreads so that others can go through my summaries if they do not have enough time to read the book. In addition to this, Goodreads is one of my go - to book discovery platforms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C. &lt;strong&gt;Focus and Time Tracking&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.forestapp.cc/&#34;&gt;Forest&lt;/a&gt; : The best app out there to implement the Pomodoro technique. Unfortunately, it is not available for Mac&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://flowapp.info/&#34;&gt;Flow&lt;/a&gt; : Use this to implement Pomodoro while working on the Mac&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://freedom.to/&#34;&gt;Freedom&lt;/a&gt; : One of the best investments I’ve ever made this year. Freedom disconnects you from the internet for as long as you want.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/calendar/about/&#34;&gt;Google Calendar&lt;/a&gt; : I put everything on Google calendar and ensure that I review it every week. The objective is to know where you are spending your time and maximise productivity. You’d be surprised to know how conveniently you end up wasting your time on things that you despise.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;D. &lt;strong&gt;Habit Tracking&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.habitify.me/&#34;&gt;Habitify&lt;/a&gt; : List down all the habits that you want to implement. Habitify will make sure that you get atleast one notification stating “0/10 habits completed today”. That notification is a game changer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/momentum/laookkfknpbbblfpciffpaejjkokdgca?hl=en&#34;&gt;Mometum&lt;/a&gt; : Momentum is a Google Chrome extension that replaces new tab page with a personal dashboard featuring to-do, weather, and inspiration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;E. &lt;strong&gt;Health and Fitness&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.pepkit.ssg&amp;amp;hl=en_IN&amp;amp;gl=US&#34;&gt;Step Set Go&lt;/a&gt; : I review the number of steps walked on SSG everyday&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.googleadservices.com/pagead/aclk?sa=L&amp;amp;ai=DChcSEwiEyOn_94vvAhWUMysKHUUHB8EYABAIGgJzZg&amp;amp;ohost=www.google.com&amp;amp;cid=CAESQOD2KY7U0HT8nt4tmqEfXbn6V3OTTuG8kPiJY-7avVbAY8VlPgo_rUFC3SdWYwP49anX7XQJS5OU-MWcXFB3mRs&amp;amp;sig=AOD64_1ZRqdPtVAEysTOlSdCVdNwga6u7A&amp;amp;q&amp;amp;adurl&amp;amp;ved=2ahUKEwiOt9__94vvAhVReH0KHQ3jDMkQ0Qx6BAgaEAE&#34;&gt;Fibit Versa 2&lt;/a&gt; : Getting a Fitbit health tracker today. I hope it does justice to its hype&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wakingup.com/&#34;&gt;Waking Up&lt;/a&gt; : In terms of content, Waking Up »» Headspace. Peace! The coolest part is that you get access to all its premium features without paying. How? Just write an email to their team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;F. &lt;strong&gt;Design&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://procreate.art/&#34;&gt;Procreate&lt;/a&gt; : I’m still a noob at Procreate; the objective is to be great by the end of this year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.figma.com/&#34;&gt;Figma&lt;/a&gt; : Still early in my journey to master Figma. Figma is one of the most used and talked about tools within the design community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tool for writing a Comic book&lt;/strong&gt; : Still in the exploration mode. Any suggestion will be appreciated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;G. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://23ruchil.github.io/Blog/&#34;&gt;This Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than anything else, this blog is a reminder to myself. A reminder to re-read my notes and share my learnings with others over the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Personal OKRs 2021</title>
    <link>/posts/personal-okrs-2021/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/personal-okrs-2021/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://axiomatic-diver-1c4.notion.site/e7ea574ebafd492fa927b9beb3256766?v=5627b3e927104714a69351d36e303194&#34; title=&#34;Personal OKRs 2021&#34;&gt;Personal OKRs 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Everything is a Product</title>
    <link>/posts/everything-is-a-product/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/everything-is-a-product/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;This realisation came to me after reading the biographies of Michael Jordan and Leonardo Da Vinci. Some of the VCs and Product Folks in Silicon Valley also subscribe to this thought. They treat themselves and their careers as that of professional athletes. According to them, the way you conduct yourself, the way you eat, your personal journal or as a matter of fact, your fingernails are nothing but mini - products. They see these attributes as features and a part of a bigger product i.e. themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stripe employees treat documentation as a part of their product development process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next question that one should ask : What does it mean for anything to be a product? Well, it means that it can be broken down into smaller chunks conceptually. Each detail can be worked upon and can be made better so that when all the pieces are reconnected, the picture looks significantly better than what it was. A few examples :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A. Treating reading as a product&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Objectives :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To increase the reading speed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To retain the read material better&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KPIs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reading Speed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Performance on a retention test&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Processes that affect the KPIs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Device used while reading i.e. Kindle/Mobile/Tablet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Background music (if any)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Environment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Posture . . . Countless other details&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B. Treating your diet as a product&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Objectives : To eat healthy and ensure that you do not gain weight because of your diet&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KPIs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Calorie intake&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other quantifiable metrics that I am not aware of&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Processes that affect the KPIs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A diet chart&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time of the day when the meal is consumed . . . Countless other details&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From your Instagram page to how you mentor someone, everything is a product. You are a professional athlete who’s a product!&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Delhi Rant</title>
    <link>/posts/delhi-rant/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/delhi-rant/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;I’ve stayed in Delhi - NCR for ~ 1.5 years now (since September 2019) and came back to Delhi after 14 years (after 2005). Now that I look back, there are certain observations that worry me about Delhi - Gurgaon culture. Listing them down here :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overt celebration of &lt;strong&gt;eat-sleep-repeat&lt;/strong&gt; culture : The common phrase that I hear most people use is : “ I don’t want to think too much and just chill”. While it is perfectly fine to do so, you have lost the right to complain about your problems. Every third person here has an opinion on some of the most pressing issues such as education, poverty and pollution, but I wonder what they are doing about it. These issues will not be solved by &lt;strong&gt;eat-sleep-repeat&lt;/strong&gt; culture. Put in the effort first to form an opinion and do your bit towards solving the problem. If you are not doing so, please stop complaining.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Forming World views through Bollywood movies and TV shows such as Friends&lt;/strong&gt; : While I agree that some of the shows (such as Friends) and movies are a delight to watch, doesn’t mean that you expect the same things to happen in your life. One needs to have the lens of objectivity on while watching such content. It is a script written by a professional whose end goal is to either increase the TRP or sales of subscription. Bollywood is one of the biggest ceilings of this country IMO. More on this &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/balajis/status/1350065743035985922&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; .“Let me make the songs of a nation, and I care not who makes its laws”. Song writers and movie directors are doing their job, we need to do ours. This &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.in/Amusing-Ourselves-Death-Discourse-Business/dp/014303653X&#34;&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; might come handy if you want to dig deeper into this topic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fluff over substance :&lt;/strong&gt; Most folks that I’ve met here come across as extremely pretentious and unauthentic. North Star for such people is to play the status game while forgetting that they do not have substance. You can only go so far with “fake it till you make it” attitude. Self - awareness as a trait is limited in supply in this part of this country .&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that being said, there are some good things about Delhi such as food, which I will miss. The above pointers are based on my personal experiences and opinions of some of my close friends. You may choose to disagree and form your opinion/experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>How to Build a Successful Consumer Brand in India?</title>
    <link>/posts/how-to-build-a-successful-consumer-brand-in-india/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/how-to-build-a-successful-consumer-brand-in-india/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://firesideventures.com&#34;&gt;Fireside Ventures&lt;/a&gt; (a consumer focussed fund) closed their second fund worth $118 Million three days ago. This comes at a time when people in India (my parents included) are willing to try out new products and give challenger brands a try. As India&amp;rsquo;s retail market evolves, modern trade (likes of LeMarche) is set to account for 15% (from 8%) of the overall distribution whereas online retail is expected to account for 5% (currently at ~ 3%). A few questions that I had in mind while observing this upsurge were why now? What has changed? Why is it so easy to start a consumer brand? I read a number of reports and spoke to 60+ founders in my quest to find the answers. This blog post is to detail out my findings :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.&lt;strong&gt;Rise of the &amp;lsquo;Millennials&amp;rsquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;India will have 500M+ millennial consumers (age 22-37) by 2021 with a total consumption expenditure of $350B+. Millennials bring strong brand affinity, seek instant gratification, are not averse to change and are risk takers while purchasing. They want new experiences, a sense of individualism and nonconformity. They spend an average of 17 hours per week online across various mediums. Majority of millenials are first time employees and are more financially independent than their predecessor generation. With significant shift towards millennials, the consumer brand landscape is expected to change in favour of new-age challenger brands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.&lt;strong&gt;Rising Aspirations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As millennials do not wish to commit and own things, they are spending the residual income to try out newer brands, seek new experiences. The desire to get that &amp;rsquo;like&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;comment&amp;rsquo; on Facebook, Instagram and be amongst the early adopters is one of the strongest driving forces behind this behaviour. &amp;lsquo;Access trumps ownership&amp;rsquo; - this seems to be the motto of millennials and Gen - Z.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3.&lt;strong&gt;Distribution Channels&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Channels such as e-commerce, modern trade, assisted commerce, direct-to-consumer are providing more power to the consumers who are now able to access goods &amp;amp; services from remote locations. With a reach of more than 19,000 pincodes in India, most large consumer brands have adopted online distribution. I remember speaking to an ambitious founder who is currently running 100+ Cr apparel business along with his wife and most of their sales come from E - commerce platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4.&lt;strong&gt;Ease of Getting the Product Manufactured&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While building the sectoral thesis, I was so fascinated by the concept of building brands that I strongly considered building one on my own in the footwear category. One of my friends is a huge fan of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vibram&#34;&gt;Vibram Furoshiki&lt;/a&gt; shoes and we both wanted to make more people try it out. Upon locking the concept, finding contract manufacturers who could build the product out was extremely easy. Indiamart was the answer! It has a huge database of manufacturers who can manufacture the product based on your specifications. The hardest part was negotiating for MOQs as most manufacturers were looking at 10,000 units as the first lot size and this required a significant upfront investment :(&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking back, I&amp;rsquo;m glad that we did not decide to go forward and didn&amp;rsquo;t give into our naivety as we were not aware about certain challenges within this segment. You can read more about them &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.notion.so/Rise-of-Indian-D2C-Brands-a75d57e92a17472c89fa103263576f5a&#34;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5.&lt;strong&gt;Building a Brand Story&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of all the vanilla parameters, one that stood out in majority of the brands was their story. Brands such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/tailorandcircus/?hl=en&#34;&gt;Tailor and Circus&lt;/a&gt;  and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/sleepyowlcoffee/?hl=en&#34;&gt;Sleepy Owl&lt;/a&gt;  have done a phenomenal job at building a story around their products. They have a story that they communicate to their fans and make sure that they stick to it across all communication channels. How do they communicate these stories?
Social Media! Nobody could have imagined getting such a loyal following and quantifying it a decade ago. But because of the adoption of social media platforms (especially Instagram), the new age brands have arrived!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brand Categories&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.&lt;strong&gt;Fashion and Apparel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three most important things that customers prefer while selecting any apparel product are :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Style/ Design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quality of the material used&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.&lt;strong&gt;Food and Beverage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taste&lt;/strong&gt; remains to be the strongest differentiator when it comes to customer preference within the F&amp;amp;B category. No matter how well packaged your product is and who endorses the product, if it tastes bad, the expectation to have your customer buy the product again is unfair. Some of the categories that are currently being disrupted are :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Healthy Snacking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Babyfood (Brand sensitivity being one of the biggest challenges as one instance of a bad press can ruin the brand image)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pet food&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time/Convenience as a value proposition. e.g. Instant coffee mix&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3.&lt;strong&gt;Personal Care&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do not have a strong thesis for this sector, but if you are looking to start your own brand within this category, you may refer to this &lt;a href=&#34;https://yourstory.com/smbstory/personal-care-indian-brands-entrepreneurs-soap-shampoo-kimrica-bare-anatomy-medimix-natures-essence-sacred-salts&#34;&gt;link.&lt;/a&gt; One category that has seen quite an upsurge is men&amp;rsquo;s grooming. Companies such as The Man Company and Ustraa have become the &amp;ldquo;poster brands&amp;rdquo; of Indian personal care space. With that being said, dental care still remains to be an ignored category and has seen no disruption since years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Challenges and Opportunities for Disruption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.&lt;strong&gt;High MOQs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As most manufacturers ask for MOQs of about 5,000 - 10,000 units, testing the product out without raising/investing a significant capital still remains the biggest challenge for building a consumer brand in India. There will be a proliferation in the number of brands coming out of India if the founders are able to create an MVP as easily as running an experiment online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.&lt;strong&gt;Unorganised Distribution&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because modern trade contributes a significantly lower % of the overall retail, distribution remains the toughest task that lies ahead of any founder venturing out in the consumer segment. It takes ~ 2 years to ensure that your product reaches the popular outlets (modern and general trade) of major cities in India. Setting up distribution also requires you to pay upfront costs to the Modern Trade outlets and it is in general a very capital intensive game. While it is convenient to use jargons such as &amp;lsquo;D2C&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;online brand building&amp;rsquo;, the true value cannot be unlocked without streamlining distribution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3.&lt;strong&gt;Data and Personalisation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While most brands do take customer feedback during the product development process, they have no way to identify the end consumer (for offline segment) and hence, can&amp;rsquo;t personalise the product as per the user needs. As of today, Pepsi doesn&amp;rsquo;t know the details of the customers who opened the cap of its bottle. Imagine if Pepsi/Coke could know this and offer a personalised drink as per your needs that you could order from its website. This is where the true disruption lies according to me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Personal Take&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unless the time to distribution and personalisation is solved (as mentioned in the challenges above), I do not intend to venture out in the consumer brand category.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kalaari Capital&amp;rsquo;s report : T20 consumerism. I contributed to this report and you can buy it on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scribd.com/document/407597572/Consumer-Brands-1-Kalaari-Document&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; link&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The New Indian : One of the best reports I&amp;rsquo;ve read till date : &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bcg.com/en-in/publications/2017/marketing-sales-globalization-new-indian-changing-consumer&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reimagining FMCG in India : &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bcg.com/en-in/publications/2017/marketing-sales-globalization-new-indian-changing-consumer&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Acknowledgments&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Founders of all the brands who took the time out to speak with me&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My colleagues and mentors at Kalaari&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Getting Rich Without Getting Lucky</title>
    <link>/posts/getting-rich-without-getting-lucky-copy/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/getting-rich-without-getting-lucky-copy/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;This is a summary of the framework used by Naval Ravikant to create order in chaos. Summarizing everything that I have learnt from his blogposts and podcasts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wealth vs Money vs Status&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seek wealth, not money or status. Wealth is having assets that earn while you sleep. Money is how we transfer time and wealth. Status is your place in the social hierarchy. Status is a zero sum game so,   ignore those who enjoy playing this game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Investing and Owning a Piece of a Business&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Invest in equity through public markets or through angel investment or by owning some equity in your
company. The likelihood of becoming insanely rich (net worth greater than Rs. 100 Cr.) by trading your time or by earning salary is extremely low. You must own equity — a piece of a business — to gain financial freedom. A few mediums to get started with investing : &lt;a href=&#34;https://angel.co&#34;&gt;AngelList&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.crowdcube.com&#34;&gt;Crowdcube&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mutual_fund&#34;&gt;Mutual Funds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monika Halal&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.in/s?k=lets+talk+money&amp;amp;adgrpid=58389672949&amp;amp;ext_vrnc=hi&amp;amp;gclid=EAIaIQobChMIzdb25v_76gIVDSQrCh2PSAQoEAAYAiAAEgLqNPD_BwE&amp;amp;hvadid=426078221670&amp;amp;hvdev=c&amp;amp;hvlocphy=1007765&amp;amp;hvnetw=g&amp;amp;hvqmt=e&amp;amp;hvrand=5468676216733939630&amp;amp;hvtargid=kwd-330135955363&amp;amp;hydadcr=23639_1979266&amp;amp;tag=googinhydr1-21&amp;amp;ref=pd_sl_7uqirjrj4i_e&#34;&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s Talk Money&lt;/a&gt; is a good starting point. Having an active and diversified portfolio is the key to success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Building Specific Knowledge&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specific knowledge is the knowledge that you cannot be trained for. If society can train you, it can train someone else, and replace you. Specific knowledge is found by pursuing your genuine curiosity and passion rather than whatever is hot right now. Building specific knowledge will feel like play to you but will look like work to others. When specific knowledge is taught, it’s through apprenticeships, not schools. Specific knowledge is often highly technical or creative. It cannot be outsourced or automated. Arming yourself with specific knowledge gives you &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;leverage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; and building a fortune requires leverage. Which takes me to the next point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Building Leverage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Business leverage comes from capital, people, and products with no marginal cost of replication (code and media).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Capital: Capital means money. To raise money, apply your specific knowledge, with accountability, and show resulting good judgment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People: Labor means people working for you. It’s the oldest and most fought-over form of leverage. Labor leverage will impress your parents, but don’t waste your life chasing it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Products: Code &amp;amp; Media. The Internet has massively broadened the possible space of careers. Most people haven’t figured this out yet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Types of Leverage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Permissioned Leverage: Capital and labor are permissioned leverage. Everyone is chasing capital, but someone has to give it to you. Everyone is trying to lead, but someone has to follow you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Permissionless Leverage: Product (Code and media) are permissionless leverage. They’re the leverage behind the newly rich. You can create software and media that works for you while you sleep. An army of robots is freely available — it’s just packed in data centers for heat and space efficiency. Use it. If you can’t code, write books and blogs, record videos and podcasts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Set and enforce an &lt;strong&gt;aspirational personal&lt;/strong&gt; hourly rate. If fixing a problem will save less than your
hourly rate, ignore it. If outsourcing a task will cost less than your hourly rate, outsource it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Know when you are lucky&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More often than not, we attribute things beyond our control to &amp;ldquo;being lucky&amp;rdquo;. Naval Ravikant has bucketised luck into four different types:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blind Luck/Dumb Luck : Well, this is sheer dumb luck.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Luck that comes to you through persistence – “fortune favors the bold”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spotted luck – “chance favors the prepared mind”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Luck that finds you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last three types of luck come from building specific knowledge. One will enjoy a greater share of dumb luck if he/she possesses specific knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it for now!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Best of Masters of Scale</title>
    <link>/posts/best-of-masters-of-scale/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/best-of-masters-of-scale/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;Below is the list of podcasts from Masters of Scale series that I found the most engaging and insightful. I finished listening to all its episodes last year. This is for those who are short on time and wondering where to start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mastersofscale.com/luis-von-ahn/&#34;&gt;A Masterclass in Outsourcing with Luis von Ahn&lt;/a&gt;  (Duolingo)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/open-or-closed-answer-is-both-w-joi-ito-mit-media-lab/id1227971746?i=1000436867368&#34;&gt;Open or closed with Joe Ito :&lt;/a&gt; A podcast on community building&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mastersofscale.com/ben-chestnut-the-case-for-bootstrapping/&#34;&gt;The case for Bootstrapping with Ben Chestnut&lt;/a&gt; (Mailchimp)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mastersofscale.com/tobi-lutke-be-a-platform/&#34;&gt;Be a platform with Tobi Lütke&lt;/a&gt; (Shopify)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mastersofscale.com/peter-thiel-escape-the-competition/&#34;&gt;Escape the competition with Peter Thiel&lt;/a&gt; (Needs no introduction)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mastersofscale.com/reed-hastings-culture-shock/&#34;&gt;Why culture matters with Reid Hastings&lt;/a&gt; (Netflix)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/bonus-10-new-rules-for-big-career-changes-graduation/id1227971746?i=1000442249696&#34;&gt;New rules for big career changes with Jordan Harbinger&lt;/a&gt; : The best podcast that I found on mapping your career trajectory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mastersofscale.com/eric-ries/&#34;&gt;Build, Measure, Learn with non other than Eric Ries&lt;/a&gt; (Lean Startup)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/id1227971746?i=1000456865058&#34;&gt;How to set the drumbeat with Jeff Weiner&lt;/a&gt; (LinkedIn - LinkedIn)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mastersofscale.com/mark-zuckerberg-imperfect-is-perfect/&#34;&gt;Imperfect is perfect with Mark Zuckerberg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mastersofscale.com/reid-hoffman-make-everyone-a-hero-part-two/&#34;&gt;Reid Hoffman Story : Part 2 - Make everyone a hero&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mastersofscale.com/mariam-naficy-the-money-episode/&#34;&gt;Raise more than you need with Mariam Naficy&lt;/a&gt; (Minted)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mastersofscale.com/ellen-kullman/&#34;&gt;4 core principles of crisis management&lt;/a&gt; (Ellen Kullman)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/ray-dalio-how-to-embrace-conflict/id1227971746?i=1000457863860&#34;&gt;How to embrace conflict with Ray Dalio&lt;/a&gt; : This is my personal favourite&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mastersofscale.com/aneel-bhusri-the-elusive-formula-for-great-hiring/&#34;&gt;The elusive formula for great hiring with Aneel Bhusri&lt;/a&gt; (Workday)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/79-how-to-master-your-emotions-w-sam-harris/id1227971746?i=1000506611995&#34;&gt;How to Master Emotion with Sam Harris&lt;/a&gt;. He also has an amazing app called &lt;a href=&#34;https://wakingup.com&#34;&gt;Waking Up&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/building-bridges-to-scale-w-kinds-daniel-lubetzky/id1227971746?i=1000500934868&#34;&gt;Building bridges to scale with Daniel Lubetzky&lt;/a&gt; (Kind)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/73-wikipedias-jimmy-wales-to-scale-find-the-right-values/id1227971746?i=1000494572313&#34;&gt;To scale find the right values with Jimmy Wales&lt;/a&gt; (Wikipedia)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mastersofscale.com/john-foley/&#34;&gt;How to turn sceptics into fans with John Foley&lt;/a&gt; (Peloton)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Speed Reading</title>
    <link>/posts/speed-reading/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/speed-reading/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;Back in January, 2019, I came across a technique called “Speed Reading” on one of Tim Ferris’ videos. I was so intrigued by it that not only did I start “reading about speed reading” a lot, I also started practicing the same tirelessly. Since then, I have almost doubled my reading speed with increased retention and have started to summarise all the books that I read on Evernote (Will share them all and make it accessible to everyone by the end of this year). The next question that should come to your mind is what the hell is “speed reading” and how do I use it to increase my reading speed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us get ourselves acquainted with a few terminologies to get started and know more:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purpose&lt;/strong&gt; : Defining the purpose about why you are reading a book helps you to focus and keep you persistent in order to finish the book. Purpose is valuable because it helps us determine what we want to get out of reading. Once we know, we can inspect the text to see if it will meet our goal. If it does not, a great deal of time has been saved right off the bat. So, what is a good way to inspect a written piece to see if it meets a given purpose? Tell yourself this while reading a book : “I am reading this book to learn money-saving strategies that will help me grow my business.” “I am reading this novel to prepare for tomorrow’s literature discussion”. Sure, developing a purpose takes time, but very little time. It shouldn’t take longer than a few seconds to one minute to state a clear, meaningful objective. The short time that is spent will, in turn, help you get more from the reading, which will, ultimately, save considerably more time in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Power of Preview&lt;/strong&gt; : Preview is one of the most important steps you can take to improve your reading speed and the type of comprehension. That’s because previewing gives the mind a framework of what will be discussed. This helps the mind understand information that will be presented and how it will be organized. Humans are by no means perfect. Countless quotes speak of our erroneous nature, such as “To err is human”. One reason is that the mind doesn’t necessarily respond to what is happening in real time but to what it thinks is going to happen. In other words, the mind is continually making predictions about the future.To remember all this, use the acronym T.H.I.E.V.E.S: • Title • Headings • Introduction • Every word in bold, underline, quote, and italics • Visuals Aids • End of Chapter Questions • Summary/Conclusion. Therefore, spend no more than 45 seconds to 5 minutes on this step. Typically, this means 45 seconds to 1 minute for shorter items like articles and reports, and 3 to 5 minutes for lengthier ones, such as books and manuals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Change Styles&lt;/strong&gt; : Don’t assume that all written works must be read in the same manner or at the same speed. It is okay to vary reading approach based on the material.Let’s start with technical manuals, which often present detailed instructions and procedures that must be carefully followed. This makes each line of text extremely important.The same approach applies to legal documents, annual reports, write-ups, and policies. These types of documents are better read in their entirety and given full attention and focus. Similarly, it’s sensible to slow down if you have to teach the material to someone else. Even a love letter or poem might be worth slowing down for, so you can enjoy the prose in the way the writer intended. It goes without saying that the more detailed and complete awareness you seek, the slower and more attentively you should read. If the text is challenging, read slowly. The same applies if the topic is new, unfamiliar, or if it is something you really want or need to remember. On the other hand, if the content proves boring, familiar, or easy to read, process, and digest, feel free to increase speed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Space Reading&lt;/strong&gt; : The eye has the ability to process an image or object both as a whole and as a collection of individual parts.When looking at a friend’s face, for example, the eyes and mind process the face as a whole rather than looking at individual parts, such as eyes, mouth, nose, and all the other minute features. This allows you to recognize the friend immediately. At the same time, if you wanted to focus on the individual features, you could do that as well.Though, what would happen if you did focus on a single feature of your friend, such as an eyelash, nostril, or dimple? Narrowing vision to such a minute detail would hinder the ability to recognize the person. Such a restricted focus would require scanning other parts of the face and then putting all those parts together in order to recognize that individual. This is how most of us read; we narrow our focus to each word or letter.This is not an effective way to read since, as you now know, the eyes and mind have the ability to see and process much more in a single glance. The solution, therefore, is to not focus on single words but rather to expand visual awareness and see groups of words at one time. This is the natural way the mind absorbs information from sight.There are two ways to look at groups of words. The first method, called space reading which directs you to avoid looking at the words you are reading, but rather at the spaces in between the words. That’s right—at the spaces between words!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chunking&lt;/strong&gt; : The second technique to look at a group of words rather than single ones is called “chunking”. Chunking opens line sight to capture more words in a single glance. The eyes are not set on a single word of a sentence, but instead, on a block, or of chunk, of words in that sentence. You look at a chunk, move to another chunk, then another, and so on. The key to this technique is not to grab words at random but to grab combinations that form a phrase.You might like both, finding that space reading works better with certain types of material, while chunking works better with others, which is perfectly acceptable. Whichever you prefer, refrain from using both techniques at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Removing Subvocalization&lt;/strong&gt; : Subvocalization is the act of pronouncing every word that is read. When subvocalizing, you either say words out loud, hear them spoken in your mind, or move your lips to their pronunciation. Any one of these acts is subvocalizing. Subvocalization greatly reduces the speed at which you read by adding an unnecessary step, or steps, to your reading. In addition to seeing the word, you are also hearing and/or speaking it. We might assume the material we were reading was causing that boredom, but in reality, the cause was simply the sound of our inner voice!Subvocalization is a behavior that starts when we first learn to read, because we are taught (blame the teachers) to read phonetically. We read out loud to connect the right sound to the right word. This is necessary for the brain to learn the words and develop associations with those words. Once we become fluent, we stop reading out loud but continue the phonetic process. We either start whispering these sounds in our mind or begin moving our lips so others can’t hear us. Most people continue reading this way for the rest of their lives, hearing the little voice in the back of their mind and moving their lips to that voice.As beneficial as it is to silence the inner narrator though, it’s not easy. As you learned, it takes time and effort to break long-lasting habits. Nonetheless, the following suggestions reduce the difficulty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Close your mouth when reading : Keeping the mouth closed disengages these processes, thus preventing you from saying the words you urge to verbalize.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read faster than speech : Read at a fast-enough pace where you simply cannot pronounce words or think about their sounds. Humans speak one word at a time and not three or four.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hum : Another option involves humming. Hum a tune, a song, or a basic melody. Humming works because it preoccupies the vocal cords, so that you can’t speak or whisper any words. Humming also drowns out the voice in your head, along with any distracting noise in the immediate environment. If, for example, you are reading around noisy neighbors or loud machinery, humming can replace those annoying sounds with something more soothing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Music : The last and most popular option to break the subvocalization habit is to listen to music. Play it loud enough so that you can’t hear yourself think, because if you can’t hear yourself think, you won’t be able to hear yourself.Research shows that music without words or lyrics, such as classical, instrumental, or electronic music, are the best options for reading. Lyrics in a song compete with words in a text for the mind’s attention. Without lyrics, extraneous words aren’t getting in the way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fixation&lt;/strong&gt; : Though fixation sounds like a complex psychological disorder, it is simply the length of time the eyes stop and rest on a subject. Anytime we look at something, our eyes still themselves. This pause, called fixation, is the eyes’ ability to stop moving so they can focus. If they didn’t do this, everything in life would be a blur. Fixation occurs during reading as well. When we read, our eyes stop and fix on words to see them clearly. They don’t stop for long, but they do, indeed, stop with each and every word. This quick pause gives the eyes an opportunity to pick up the text. As the eyes look at a word, they fixate. To look at the next word, they jump. Fixation also reduces reading comprehension. Meaning is easier to pull from groups of words than from individual words or even single letters. We falsely assume that slower reading means better comprehension. This may be true in some cases, but in most cases, the factors causing slower reading also cause lower comprehension. If you read slowly and still struggle with comprehension, you are likely to fixate too much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The question that now arises is how to reduce fixations. The answer : Space reading and chunking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Regression&lt;/strong&gt; : Regression is the act of reading the same text multiple times. Regression reduces comprehension. Our minds take meaning from what we just read to help us understand what we are about to read. By skipping back to a previous sentence,paragraph, or section, we can’t help but lose track of the point that was being currently made. So, returning to a passage after regression, you may have forgotten what was just read, making it difficult to understand what you are about to read.Most importantly, regression breaks flow, and speed reading is all about flow. It’s about syncing the pace of the eyes to the rhythm of the mind. As the eyes see words, the mind processes them. As soon as the mind finishes processing one set of words, the eyes pick up a new set. Overall, regression doubles, or even triples, reading time and may even result in better comprehension.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Visual Range&lt;/strong&gt; : Visual range is the ability to see objects beyond your direct line of focus. When looking at something in front of you, it’s easy to see that object because the eyes are set directly on it. It’s difficult to capture details on either side of the object unless you move your eyes.We use peripherals more often than you might think. Whenever we try to look at someone without them knowing, we employ peripheral vision.If you’ve never worked on expanding peripheral range, chances are that it isn’t very wide. Therefore, the number of extra words it can capture is limited. If that’s the case, then in addition to training yourself to use the peripheral while reading, you also want to widen it. Widening the peripheral vision further increases the eyes’ capacity to capture words from both the left and right corners. Developing this is a key to developing the skill of speed reading. You can widen your peripheral vision through Schultz table. Look at the number in the middle of your screen and write all the numbers in the square down to practice widening your peripheral vision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m almost on the verge of completing 21 books (will share summaries of each one of them on my blog soon) till June, 2020 using the techniques mentioned above. It’s your time to put the information and techniques to use!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy reading!&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>What is your superpower?</title>
    <link>/posts/what-is-your-superpower-copy/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/what-is-your-superpower-copy/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
    src=&#34;https://manassaloi.com/assets/img/no_filter.png&#34; 
    alt=&#34;image&#34; 
     /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In one of the excerpt from the book No Filter: The Inside Story of Instagram, Kevin Systorm explains to Ashton Kutcher why Instagram blew up. It was not because of network effects. There were no network effects on day 1. It was not because of celebrity users. It was not because they rode on Twitter and Facebook graph of users. All of these happened later. Like most B2C products, it started as a single player use case: &lt;strong&gt;How to make your photos more beautiful, and shareable&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To quote one of my seniors, &amp;ldquo;I have been thinking about the concept of superpowers a lot. Brian Norgard is known for talking about giving your users superpowers. The ability to super like a person on a dating app is a superpower. And Norgard’s advice is to monetize by charging for these super powers, which is what most dating apps do. But I think the superpower concept can be extended even further. Instead of a normal feature vs monetizable superpower feature, think of how you can give ordinary users super powers though your product&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listed below are other superpowers that I think can make you a superhero in the 21st century. Perhaps, a few business ideas for future entrepreneurs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speedreading : Helping users read 500 - 1000 wpm with ~ 90% retention&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to learn and write code quickly (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/44770129-ultralearning&#34;&gt;Ultralearning model by Scott H. Young&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to understand and create design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to let users network (Different from LinkedIn in the sense that the network is a community
rather than just a number)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apps that let users meditate deeply&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saying &amp;ldquo;no&amp;rdquo; without feeling guilty&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Critical reasoning : Thinking from first priciples&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Financial literacy and maximizing ROI through investments in equities and public markets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The most important skill of the 21 st century : &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/learn/learning-how-to-learn&#34;&gt;Learning how to learn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Personal OKRs 2020</title>
    <link>/posts/personal-okrs-2020/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/personal-okrs-2020/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://axiomatic-diver-1c4.notion.site/3acaabebd8e04c899e32b9da6c0a5e76?v=0510c7d736ef4aba9a6cd2e0c52e2c5a&#34; title=&#34;Personl OKRs 2020&#34;&gt;Personal OKRs 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Seek to Understand Before Trying to be Understood</title>
    <link>/posts/seek-to-understand-before-trying-to-be-understood/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/seek-to-understand-before-trying-to-be-understood/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;People are just either not that interested in what you&amp;rsquo;re saying, or they are too focused on their own agenda. It&amp;rsquo;s ridiculous to see two people acting like they can’t really hear each other — by choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &amp;ldquo;The Significance Principle,&amp;rdquo; authors Les Carter and Jim Underwood posit that we should listen past where the other person has finished. We should even pause before answering. Let them get their point, their story, their compliment, and even their criticism out. Completely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, before preparing your response, ask more about what they said. Get engaged. Understand what and why.
Seeking real understanding affirms the other person and what they have to say. That&amp;rsquo;s what they want. That&amp;rsquo;s what we all want — to be understood, valued and affirmed. What if you seek to understand but others don&amp;rsquo;t? Two things come to mind. One person truly listening is generally better than none. More important, one person listening generally leads to two people listening. Let’s be honest, if I honor you with my ears, you’ll be more likely to reciprocate. Others learn the habit through our example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ability to hear is a gift. The willingness to listen is a choice. Putting yourself in others&amp;rsquo; shoes and being empathetic is a very important life skill (a critical part of my job as a part of the product community). I&amp;rsquo;ve failed at doing this multiple times and have pestered my friends when I should have just tried to understand the other person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contextualizing this to dating and relationships (The hardest part)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hardest thing in a conflict is to separate the person and the points he/she is making.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is easier said than done and I have failed many times in the past to make this separation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we are engaged in a heated discussion with someone we tend to listen more with the intent of replying, than to understand his/her point of view. We bring things from the past and use them to fight in the present&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We let our preconceived notions about the person cloud our judgement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best thing to do in such a situation is to take a pause and ask yourself whether you are fighting the person or the points he/she is making. And respond to his/her points than his/her behavior (be it past or present). If you have been hurt by his/her way of speaking, something he/she did in the past, you can always bring that up later when the main discussion has ended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this way you will prevent fights from getting dragged on and on, and also take the decision which is best for your relationship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some resources that might come handy while dealing with such situations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Books: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/71730.Nonviolent_Communication&#34;&gt;Nonviolent Communication: A Language of Life&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/15014.Crucial_Conversations&#34;&gt;Crucial Conversations: Tools for Talking When Stakes Are High&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Articles: &lt;a href=&#34;https://firstround.com/review/our-6-must-reads-for-cutting-through-conflict-and-tough-conversations/&#34;&gt;Best reads on Firstround to deal with conflicts&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/the-year-of-the-looking-glass/5-hard-questions-to-ask-yourself-during-a-conflict-f4a91bab347a&#34;&gt;5 hard questions to ask yourself during a conflict&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@ameet/the-5-principles-of-good-argument-63d394ca3051&#34;&gt;How to make a good argument&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@joulee/5-steps-for-disagreeing-effectively-9d745ce0dbb4&#34;&gt;5 steps for Disagreeing Effectively&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Thinking in Pomodoros</title>
    <link>/posts/thinking-in-pomodoros-copy/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/thinking-in-pomodoros-copy/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;Last week (week from 24th May - 31st May) has turned out to be the most productive week in my life. Not that I have cut down on my side gigs or changed my priorities, but a simple addition of an age old technique called Pomodoro has changed the way I have started to think about time. Here’s how I see the difference :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Old Me&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me list down what I am supposed to do today and complete today’s To - Dos. I’ll go through the list one by one and then reward myself at the end of the day with an episode of “House of Lies” or reply to some of my Whatsapp messages. But there is something inherently evil with this strategy which is “not defining your stop losses”. As soon as I find my flow in one of the activities in my To - Do list, I lose track of time and can only complete ~ 50% of the assigned tasks on any given day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The New Me&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Defining the activities on and outside my To - Do list as Pomodoros.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grocery Shopping - 1 Pomodoro&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reading Books - 5 Pomodoros&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Having a chat with my family : 1 Pomodoro&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Office Work : 22 Pomodoros&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interacting with my family and friends over the weekend : 2 Pomodoros&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only has thinking in Pomodoros made me more productive, but also helped me do a lot more work in a lot less time. The reason for this is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;25 mins of focussed attention that makes me much more productive as compared to dragging things for hours with decreasing productivity. This leads to nothing, but an increased production of Adenosine in my body.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Doing more activities and putting a hard stop to a particular activity after completing the assigned Pomodoros.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Taking 7 minute breaks in which I practice playing Harmonica (Well, it makes me feel relaxed and obsess over my Harmonica tunes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Differentiating Yourself Through Social Media</title>
    <link>/posts/differeniating-yourself-through-social-media/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/differeniating-yourself-through-social-media/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;Increasing number of users are spending their time online and are using social media tools to express themselves. Amidst this, can the activities (posts/likes/comments) performed by people on social media be used to hire candidates for different job profiles? I see this as a great way to differentiate candidates from others in cases where they have similar educational backgrounds, skill sets, and resumes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We put ourselves out there whenever we post something, like/comment on a post, or update our Goodreads account with the latest book that we’ve read. Every activity that we perform online conveys some or the other aspect about us. I feel that the reliance on social media to filter applicants will increase with time and will be used to differentiate similar candidates, especially to determine cultural fit (something on the lines of Klout Score, but more focussed towards determining cultural fit instead of influence) . Not limiting to jobs, activities on social media will also be used to filter university applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, some of the platforms and parameters that these institutions(universities, corporate firms, insurance companies, etc.) will use to determine the quality of the candidates are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GoodReads : Number of books, subject/discipline the candidate is interested in&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twitter : Tweets posted by the user, relevance of the Tweets to the job, relevance of the people followed by the applicant to the job&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LinkedIn : Frequency of articles posted by the users, relevance of the post to the job, relevance of the people followed by the applicant to the job&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instagram : Pages liked, relevance of the people followed by the applicant to the job, relevance of pictures posted by the applicant to know his/her interests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Especially during these unprecedented times, when jobs for some of the major sectors have disappeared and when most of us are liking those cat videos, differentiating yourself and posting stuff relevant to your professional interests might come handy for securing your dream job in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To conclude, I’ll turn up the volume by saying that choosing the right social media platform is similar to chosing your peers. If done right, it can do wonders!&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
