<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ruchil Sharma</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ruchil Sharma</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
    <title>Is ChatGPT the New Twitter?</title>
    <link>/posts/is-chatgpt-the-new-twitter/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/is-chatgpt-the-new-twitter/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;Since 2022, we’ve been accustomed to text-based Q&amp;amp;As and black-box answers. While the use cases are numerous, I think the next wave will be dominated by image and video generation, if not already, similar to TikTok and YouTube Shorts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ChatGPT could end up like Twitter/X: a place for the most insightful questions and answers, but with distribution largely controlled by players such as Google and MidJourney, where most users create and consume &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/AI_slop&#34;&gt;AI slop&lt;/a&gt;. I’ve been long on Google for a while and remain bullish on midwit AI usecases.&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Meaning of Money</title>
    <link>/posts/meaning-of-money/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/meaning-of-money/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;The beauty of money is that it means something different to each of us. For some, it’s about meeting basic needs. For others, it’s power, status, or superiority. If you haven’t asked yourself what money truly means to &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt;, chances are you’re already living within someone else’s definition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s what it means to me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tomorrow’s Peace&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Money is like stored potential energy, a weapon against uncertainity. It gives you the ability to look ahead without fear of survival, to know you can put food on the table tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buying Time&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of us are trading time for money. A rare few either compound money at unimaginable absolute scale or spend decades working on what they truly love while making money in the same field. For the rest, money buys back discretionary time. The freedom to choose how you spend your hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Freedom from Toxic People&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a previous &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ruchilsharma.com/posts/strong-opinions-loosely-held---2025/&#34;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;, I touched on personality disorders like &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Narcissistic_personality_disorder&#34;&gt;NPD&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Borderline_personality_disorder&#34;&gt;BPD&lt;/a&gt;. They’re more common than we think, just rarely diagnosed. Having money gives you leverage to set boundaries, to walk away from those who drain you, manipulate you, or hold you back. On another note, if you hear someone say, &lt;em&gt;“I want to feel superior”&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;“I like playing status games”,&lt;/em&gt; turn around and run as fast as you can. No amount of fixing on your part will heal their unresolved (childhood) trauma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Capital Allocation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At its core, every business is about allocating capital. But you can’t allocate what you don’t have. Money lets you invest in what matters to you, your health, your appearance, your passions etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luxury for the sake of showing off i.e. exotic holidays, flashy lifestyles doesn’t excite me. Those things might matter to you, and that’s fine. In that case, your FU number will likely be much higher. I&amp;rsquo;d definitely like to spend every penny that I&amp;rsquo;ve earned before I die.&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>On Mindset</title>
    <link>/posts/mindset-is-everything/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/mindset-is-everything/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;I’ve been meaning to write this for a while. I wrote a partial version of this post a few years back. Early in my career, I realized that the hardest thing to change is someone’s mindset, including our own. It takes enormous effort!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people, though, work relentlessly to build what I’d call a *champion’s mindset.*Giving everything you’ve got on the field. Leaving nothing behind. Of course, there are exceptions when someone is facing severe physical or mental challenges. But outside of that, a champion’s mindset means seeing every area where you’re falling short as a &lt;em&gt;skill gap,&lt;/em&gt; and then relentlessly working on it if it truly matters to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By contrast, a &lt;em&gt;loser’s mindset&lt;/em&gt; is knowing what needs to be done, but never even trying. It’s convincing yourself you can’t, either because you believe it deep down or because someone else told you so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last one is the &lt;em&gt;victim’s mindset&lt;/em&gt;: blaming others for your shortcomings. It’s not that you never try, but you refuse to take ownership of your effort or output. Most people fall into this bucket. They don’t reflect, they always have an excuse, and they rarely take responsibility for their actions and consider themselves the most unfortunate of all.&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Have Stories Worth Telling</title>
    <link>/posts/do-you-have-stories-worth-telling/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/do-you-have-stories-worth-telling/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;This one’s a short post. 2025 has been nothing short of an inflection point for me shaped partly by unforced errors, but also by lessons I wouldn’t trade for anything. At the end of the day, if you live long enough to have stories worth telling, it’s all worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been fortunate, unfortunate to experience so many different worlds, from industries to sports and probably more . Only a handful of those bets have worked out (and maybe more will in the future), but what I’m left with is a treasure chest of stories. When I think about it, those stories are the only real things I’ll carry with me to the grave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here’s a reminder to self: live in a way that gives you stories worth telling. Do whatever you want with this.&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Raising the Bar: 2025 Goals and Progress Update</title>
    <link>/posts/2025-focus-areas-updated/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/2025-focus-areas-updated/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;At the start of 2025, I had set a list of personal goals for myself. Looking back, I realised they weren’t ambitious enough. Hence, I have decided to push harder, think bigger, and track my progress. Here’s where I stand today, and what I’ve added to my list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Progress on Existing Goals&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Learning Macro Trends and Technical Analysis for Investing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve made decent progress here. I’ve finished a couple of books and, more importantly, have become comfortable reading charts with nuance. I can now understand patterns like &lt;strong&gt;head and shoulders, double tops, triple bottoms&lt;/strong&gt;, and spot signals such as a &lt;strong&gt;volume increase at specific price points&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This clarity has  shaped my investing and swing trading decisions. Positive signs so far. Fingers crossed, but even if the year doesn’t end with a huge win, I’ve built enough confidence (and cushion) to keep going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Building Compelling Narratives and Storytelling&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve read a few storytelling-focused books and started using tools that give me real-time feedback with impact scores. I to practice storytelling weekly in my day job. I want to build this muscle deliberately. Musk and Sam Altman are masters at storytelling, raising billions purely on narrative spinning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Building Products Using AI&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where I’ve been behind. I had planned to start in July, but life had other ideas. I will get back on track with a ton of product ideas brewing, inspired by recent events and conversations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My plan now: &lt;strong&gt;experiment quickly, build with Cursor, and ship to the App Store&lt;/strong&gt;. I expect most of these projects to fail  and that’s okay. The goal is to flush out the bad ideas, so the good ones can come out quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Becoming Better at FIFA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started at &lt;strong&gt;Division 5&lt;/strong&gt; (or 10 I afaik) starting this year, losing most games, but now I’m competing in &lt;strong&gt;Division 2&lt;/strong&gt;. Sure, I still lose, but against much stronger players. Next : Win consistently in &lt;strong&gt;Division I&lt;/strong&gt; and (most importantly) win against a few friends I respect as good FIFA players.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Attain 2021 mindset&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most valuable lessons I’ve carried from 2021 is accountability. This year sure has been a test, and has pushed me to adopt the same mindset again. I’m proud of how much I’ve been able to get done, but this is just the beginning. My aim is to increase the intensity , letting experiments and serendipity shape what’s next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Goals for 2025&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to push myself further. Here’s what I’m adding:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reaching $networth goal by end of 2025:&lt;/strong&gt; Not because I need it, but as a personal challenge. Most founders don’t make meaningful money from their ventures. I&amp;rsquo;d want to make it before I start something. But only when the timing and problem truly make sense,  not just for the sake of status.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;80% of entrepreneurs make the same amount of money they would if they were employed.&amp;quot; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/SKxaFKsLzN&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/SKxaFKsLzN&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Paras Chopra (@paraschopra) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/paraschopra/status/1625081039554215936?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;February 13, 2023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The two areas that make sense the most right now are AI infrastructure/consumer or consumer crypto such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.redotpay.com/&#34;&gt;reddotpay&lt;/a&gt;, Kast Card, or OpenFX on the B2B side. Most of the wealth in technology is created during periods of rapid ascent , but only a handful of players, usually the top one or two, truly make meaningful money. The rest are eventually consolidated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Focus on health:&lt;/strong&gt; Between gym training 4x a week and twice a week football sessions, fitness has become a big part of my routine. Football especially gives me unparalleled joy. I can clearly see how far I’ve come compared to two years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Publishing My First Comic Book:&lt;/strong&gt;  I want to publish a comic book on Amazon Kindle this year. This one&amp;rsquo;s a small but deeply personal milestone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll try to share another update by the end of the year, hopefully with more wins this time, and some lessons from failures.&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Strong Opinions Loosely Held - 2025</title>
    <link>/posts/strong-opinions-loosely-held---2025/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/strong-opinions-loosely-held---2025/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;Back in 2021, I wrote a post on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ruchilsharma.com/posts/strong-opinions-loosely-held-copy/&#34;&gt;Strong Opinions, Loosely Held&lt;/a&gt;. This is a follow-up to that, an extended version. I’m a bit wiser now, but there’s still a lot to learn!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-on-people&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#1-on-people&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg class=&#34;icon&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; focusable=&#34;false&#34; height=&#34;16&#34; version=&#34;1.1&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 16 16&#34; width=&#34;16&#34;&gt;
            &lt;path fill-rule=&#34;evenodd&#34;
                d=&#34;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&#34;&gt;
            &lt;/path&gt;
        &lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;1. On People&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last four years feel like a decade compressed. I’ve met countless people in this period. Some inspiring and with good intentions, others absolutely terrible. Looking ahead, I want to be more intentional about who I keep close. Thankfully, with decades of hard-earned savings and some independence, I can now choose my circle carefully. Here are the qualities that matter most to me (feel free to define your own markers):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Digital footprint honesty:&lt;/strong&gt; YouTube, Spotify, Netflix history says more about a person than their words. You can fake conversations, but not how you spend your alone time. Privacy matters, of course, but I’d rely on this much more over surface-level conversations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Team sports background:&lt;/strong&gt; Winning in sports teaches discipline, character, and ethics. You can’t fake those traits on the field.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Authenticity:&lt;/strong&gt; I want to stay away from people who constantly shift accents, personas, or chase validation through likes and power plays.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Patience and comfort with boredom:&lt;/strong&gt; Everything worthwhile has trade-offs. If you can’t endure boredom or delay gratification, it’s hard to build anything meaningful, including your own character.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Long-term friendships:&lt;/strong&gt; I’m grateful for the friends who’ve stuck around for a decade or more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-on-mental-health&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#2-on-mental-health&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg class=&#34;icon&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; focusable=&#34;false&#34; height=&#34;16&#34; version=&#34;1.1&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 16 16&#34; width=&#34;16&#34;&gt;
            &lt;path fill-rule=&#34;evenodd&#34;
                d=&#34;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&#34;&gt;
            &lt;/path&gt;
        &lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;2. On Mental Health&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If someone finds joy in another’s misery, or is obsessed with power without empathy, something is broken at their core. Often, the answers lie in their childhood. A child who is constantly shut down or excessively appeased may grow into an adult struggling with identity, sometimes developing Narcissism Personality Discorder (the urge to feel superior and much more), Boderline Personality Disorders, or bipolar traits. I read about this for a few weeks and this area is absolutely fascinating. Unreal in some sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meeting such people often feels like meeting a “non-person.” Around others, they wear a mask. Alone, they’re something else entirely. Someone terrified of facing the undeveloped inner child they’re still protecting. To survive, they create a false identity and shield it fiercely, rejecting any criticism that threatens it. Even in London recently, many cab drivers spoke about their children struggling with mental health conditions such as ADHD or other conditions. Despite special schools, the demand far outpaces supply. Parents are left exhausted, fighting for limited opportunities. This reinforced for me how much mental health is both personal &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; systemic. These two graphs support the observation. One in every six individuals globally suffers from Narcissistic Personality Disorder. The prevalence is definitely higher in India, given the gaps in parenting awareness and socio-economic challenges that contribute to poor upbringing. It can take nearly a decade of therapy to overcome such issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
    src=&#34;https://rift-zephyr-e94.notion.site/image/attachment%3A79fc1301-2153-459c-944a-54fe9d613937%3AScreenshot_2025-08-16_at_6.49.45_PM.png?table=block&amp;amp;id=251ef8a9-f43b-80ed-9038-f9afb091d160&amp;amp;spaceId=eeadcd95-73d1-4a78-8123-3bf4e28b4b47&amp;amp;width=1370&amp;amp;userId=&amp;amp;cache=v2&#34; 
    alt=&#34;image&#34; 
     /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
    src=&#34;https://rift-zephyr-e94.notion.site/image/attachment%3A1e8a94f8-af4a-4111-a13e-c9b1c635a651%3AScreenshot_2025-08-16_at_6.49.06_PM.png?table=block&amp;amp;id=251ef8a9-f43b-8008-a25f-da07ca49fd6a&amp;amp;spaceId=eeadcd95-73d1-4a78-8123-3bf4e28b4b47&amp;amp;width=1420&amp;amp;userId=&amp;amp;cache=v2&#34; 
    alt=&#34;image&#34; 
     /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-on-travel&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#3-on-travel&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg class=&#34;icon&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; focusable=&#34;false&#34; height=&#34;16&#34; version=&#34;1.1&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 16 16&#34; width=&#34;16&#34;&gt;
            &lt;path fill-rule=&#34;evenodd&#34;
                d=&#34;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&#34;&gt;
            &lt;/path&gt;
        &lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;3. On Travel&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I barely traveled in the last four years, and my recent London trip reminded me what I’ve been missing. Not for Instagram, but for the sheer learning travel brings. The calm of mountains, the openness of oceans, the cultural contrasts. The experience is very humbling. In London, strangers stopped to help me multiple times without any hesitation. Conversations with Uber drivers were among the best insights I had. From football clubs to local quirks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;4-on-growth&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#4-on-growth&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg class=&#34;icon&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; focusable=&#34;false&#34; height=&#34;16&#34; version=&#34;1.1&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 16 16&#34; width=&#34;16&#34;&gt;
            &lt;path fill-rule=&#34;evenodd&#34;
                d=&#34;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&#34;&gt;
            &lt;/path&gt;
        &lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;4. On Growth&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything today is packaged as “growth”. Joining a startup, attending Vipassana course, cleaning beaches, giving talks at Toastmasters. They’re all valid, but the real question is: &lt;em&gt;Do you really want it?&lt;/em&gt; Desires are often memetic. We want things because others want them. That’s how we get trapped in status and ego games. If you’re not clear on what &lt;strong&gt;you&lt;/strong&gt; want, you’ll keep chasing what belongs to others. If you are one of them, best of luck!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;5-on-boredom&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#5-on-boredom&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg class=&#34;icon&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; focusable=&#34;false&#34; height=&#34;16&#34; version=&#34;1.1&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 16 16&#34; width=&#34;16&#34;&gt;
            &lt;path fill-rule=&#34;evenodd&#34;
                d=&#34;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&#34;&gt;
            &lt;/path&gt;
        &lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;5. On Boredom&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My view hasn’t changed since 2021: success is usually hidden in the boring basics everyone avoids.  Watch this &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pqWUuYTcG-o&amp;amp;t=627s&#34;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; for inspiration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;6-on-self-reliance&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#6-on-self-reliance&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg class=&#34;icon&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; focusable=&#34;false&#34; height=&#34;16&#34; version=&#34;1.1&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 16 16&#34; width=&#34;16&#34;&gt;
            &lt;path fill-rule=&#34;evenodd&#34;
                d=&#34;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&#34;&gt;
            &lt;/path&gt;
        &lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;6. On Self-Reliance&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going forward, I want to cut most dependencies. Cooking and driving are highest on the list. I’ve started with the basics such as making tea first. Yeah, it is simple, but still a marker of progress. I’ve resisted driving partly because I believe autonomous cars will take over in the next decade, and partly because I love speed in every aspect of life. Still, self-reliance in commuting is worth pursuing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;7-on-presentation&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#7-on-presentation&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg class=&#34;icon&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; focusable=&#34;false&#34; height=&#34;16&#34; version=&#34;1.1&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 16 16&#34; width=&#34;16&#34;&gt;
            &lt;path fill-rule=&#34;evenodd&#34;
                d=&#34;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&#34;&gt;
            &lt;/path&gt;
        &lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;7. On Presentation&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the area I’ve neglected the most. Presentation matters, but not without substance, ethics, character, and competence. How you carry yourself does make a difference. That’s why this pointer is the last on my list, but not the least. Time to finally invest in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: I will keep expanding this list.&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>How to Rise from the Ashes?</title>
    <link>/posts/rising-from-the-ashes/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/rising-from-the-ashes/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;Life isn’t always fair. Sometimes, no matter how hard you try, things just don’t go your way. Other times, it’s not about you, it’s the people around you, circumstances beyond your control, or sheer bad luck. And when life hits hardest, it can feel like betrayal, like someone poured you a glass of wine, only to tell you after the last sip that it was poisoned. I’ve been through these moments. More than once. And while I don’t claim to have all the answers, here’s what I’ve learned from clawing my way out of the ashes. It works everytime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do Not Act Immediately&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you’re down and out, the instinct is to &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; something. Often, it’s something impulsive, driven by rage, hurt, or despair. But acting in the heat of emotion usually makes things worse. Pause. Breathe. Let the storm pass inside you before making a move. Paper is more patient than a man.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Return to Your Values and Mission&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask yourself: &lt;em&gt;What truly matters to me? What helps me sleep at night?&lt;/em&gt; Your values are your compass, especially when the world feels directionless.I’ve shared mine in few earlier posts, and I revisit them often to make sure I’m still aligned. Don’t compromise your core beliefs. While values can evolve, betraying them for short-term gains is like shaking hands with the devil. Without a deeper sense of meaning, status seeking and hierarchy quietly take their place as life’s default goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ask What Do You Like Doing?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What makes you feel alive? For me, it’s football, learning new things, diving into strategy, and lately exploring the power of storytelling. Life with someone can be great, but a life built on self-driven progress isn&amp;rsquo;t bad either. Stories shape reality. Narratives can move hearts, shift perceptions. They’re powerful enough to make people believe almost anything. It’s like winding up a toy, the narrative becomes the fuel that sets it in motion, driving everything it does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Imagine Your Final Speech in Heaven&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Picture this: You’re at the end. You meet the maker. You get two minutes to reflect on your life. What would you say? Would you be able to say, &lt;em&gt;“I gave it my all”?&lt;/em&gt; “I succeeded at everything,” “I tried my best.” That’s the only mirror that matters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Avoid 2-Minute Dopamine Traps&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick hits of pleasure scrolling, likes, distractions are numbing us. They’re shaping a generation that’s anxious, unfocused, and disconnected. I’ve written about this &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ruchilsharma.com/posts/strong-opinions-loosely-held-copy/#:~:text=The%20abundance%20problem&#34;&gt;before&lt;/a&gt;, and I’m becoming more convinced that this is the silent epidemic of our times. I’m even considering helping people with therapy and mental health issues because emotional discipline and empathy are becoming rare and valuable skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m currently reading &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.in/Anxious-Generation-Rewiring-Childhood-Epidemic/dp/0593655036&#34;&gt;The Anxious Generation&lt;/a&gt;, and its early chapters paint a sad picture of what&amp;rsquo;s ahead. I’ll write a separate post on this.&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Al Talent War Is Starting to Look Like a Sports Draft</title>
    <link>/posts/al-talent-war-is-starting-to-look-like-a-sports-draft/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/al-talent-war-is-starting-to-look-like-a-sports-draft/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;Mark Zuckerberg is reportedly offering $100 million+ offers to top AI researchers and engineers and for good reason. Meta is trailing in the AI race, and after the launch of Llama 4, Zuck knows he needs to catch up fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$100M might sound like a lot, until you consider Meta’s ~$2T market cap. Spending a few billion to improve even slightly the odds (to 5% from less than 1% right now) of becoming a top 3 AI company seems obvious. The upside is potentially worth trillions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think of it like sports. In the NBA, LeBron James is offered $50 million a year. The Lakers? Valued at $10 billion. LeBron can single-handedly win championships. That’s what elite AI researchers are today : game changers. A single breakthrough can put a company ahead for months, even years, and massively pull market share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For years, game defining tech talent&amp;rsquo;s comp. has been &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.techemails.com/p/steve-jobs-emails-adobes-ceo&#34;&gt;capped&lt;/a&gt; and they are arguably underpaid. AI talent wars changes that. We’re entering a world where bidding wars for top engineers will start to look more like sports bidding, and rightfully so. For others, well, we&amp;rsquo;ll all be unemployed anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Interesting Relationship Between Ad Prices and Ad Inventory</title>
    <link>/posts/2025-6-meta-ads/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/2025-6-meta-ads/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;This has been noted in Meta’s earnings and in several prominent tech blogs, but I find it a particularly fascinating observation. Contrary to intuition, ad impressions and price-per-ad move in opposite directions. See chart below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
    src=&#34;https://axiomatic-diver-1c4.notion.site/image/attachment%3A362742f3-caa8-48ca-ac17-67727ed43be7%3AScreenshot_2025-05-11_at_3.08.35_PM.png?table=block&amp;amp;id=1f08b13c-4f08-8093-a431-c74ae0632451&amp;amp;spaceId=c6a62786-f859-45a8-8419-fae4370cf6f4&amp;amp;width=1420&amp;amp;userId=&amp;amp;cache=v2&#34; 
    alt=&#34;image&#34; 
     /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Impressions vs. Price-Per-Ad: When Meta  increases ad inventory (e.g. by monetizing a new surface like Stories or Reels), impressions go up, but price-per-ad tends to drop due to greater supply.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conversely, when surfaces saturate (like Reels today), impression growth slows and Meta relies on price-per-ad increases for revenue growth. This introduces long term revenue related risks for Meta.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meta’s playbook then hinges on continually introducing new ad surfaces that can fuel impression growth before monetization peaks. How Meta unlocks the next wave is the big question. Its bets on AR glasses and VR may be the next frontier.&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>The Book I Keep Coming Back To</title>
    <link>/posts/scott-adams---book-summary/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/scott-adams---book-summary/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;I recently revisited one of my favorite books: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.in/How-Fail-Almost-Everything-Still/dp/0241003709&#34;&gt;How to Fail at Almost Everything and Still Win Big&lt;/a&gt; that profoundly shaped my worldview back in 2016. Reading it again with a few more years of experience under my belt, I found myself coming across insights I had completely missed the first time around. I strongly recommend reading it. But if you’re short on time, I’ve shared my notes below, written as lifelong advice to myself, and hopefully valuable to you too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consistency is the best marker of truth that we have, imperfect though it may be.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can debate the morality of viewing profits as the top priority in business, but you can’t argue that it doesn’t work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You’re the best judge of what works for you, as long as you acquire that wisdom through pattern recognition, trial, and observation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sometimes the only real difference between crazy people and artists is that artists write down what they imagine seeing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can cure your loneliness only by doing the talking yourself and—most important—being heard. For the next three and a half years I experienced a total disconnect from normal life and a profound sense of aloneness, despite the love and support of family and friends.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you stand in front of an audience, your sensation of time is distorted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That’s why inexperienced presenters speak too rapidly. I mentally adjusted my internal clock to match the audience’s sense of timing. I also wanted them to wait in silence for a beat or two, to engage their curiosity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is passion a useful tool for success, or is it just something that makes you irrational?Passionate people who fail don’t get a chance to offer their advice to the rest of us. But successful passionate people are writing books and answering interview questions about their secrets for success every day. Naturally those successful people want you to believe that success is a product of their awesomeness, but they also want to retain some humility.Passion can also be a simple marker for talent. We humans tend to enjoy doing things we are good at, while not enjoying things we suck at. We’re also fairly good at predicting what we might be good at before&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You already know that when your energy is right you perform better at everything you do, including school, work, sports, and even your personal life. Energy is good. Passion is bullshit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everything you want out of life is in that huge, bubbling vat of failure. The trick is to get the good stuff out.I’ve long seen failure as a tool, not an outcome. I believe that viewing the world in that way can be useful for you too.Success is entirely accessible, even if you happen to be a huge screwup 95 percent of the time.My failure taught me to seek opportunities in which I had an advantage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Timing is often the biggest component of success. And since timing is often hard to get right unless you are psychic, it makes sense to try different things until you get the timing right by luck.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I believe the way he explained it is that your job is not your job; your job is to find a better job.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This was my first exposure to the idea that one should have a system instead of a goal. In other words, goal-oriented people exist in a state of nearly continuous failure that they hope will be temporary. That feeling wears on you. Goal-oriented people exist in a state of continuous presuccess failure at best, and permanent failure at worst if things never work out. Systems people succeed every time they apply their systems, in the sense that they did what they intended to do. The goals people are fighting the feeling of discouragement at each turn.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At various times I was a branch banking trainee, project manager, computer programmer, product manager, lending officer, budget supervisor, and a few other jobs I’ve forgotten.I had officially failed at my banking career and, against all odds, my incompetence wasn’t the cause. Little did they realize that looking good on paper was my best skill.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This was one of many examples in which the universe makes sure there isn’t much of a link between job performance in the corporate world and outcomes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wishing starts in the mind and generally stays there. If you want success, figure out the price, then pay it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Successful people don’t wish for success; they decide to pursue it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The most important form of selfishness involves spending time on your fitness, eating right, pursuing your career, and still spending quality time with your family and friends.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At every turn, we cheat our own future to appear generous today.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We humans are wired to be easily influenced by the people who are in relationships with us, no matter what those relationships are.Influence works best when the person being influenced has no objection to the suggested change. Often all one needs is some form of permission to initiate a change, and it doesn’t always matter what form the permission is in, or if it even makes sense. I’m sure you already want to be fit and successful and happy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apparently humans are wired to take care of their own needs first, then family, tribe,country, and the world, roughly in that order.The healthiest way to look at selfishness is that it’s a necessary strategy when you’re struggling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The problem with all of this wanting is that the time you spend chasing one of those desires is time you can’t spend chasing any of the others. So how do you organize your limited supply of time to get the best result? I make choices that maximize my personal energy because that makes it easier to manage all of the other priorities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For years, the prospect of starting “my own thing” and leaving my cubicle behind gave me an enormous amount of energy. “Energy” is a simple word that captures a mind-boggling array of complicated happenings. For our purposes I’ll define your personal energy as anything that gives you a positive lift, either mentally or physically. Like art, you know it when you see.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple systems are probably the best way to achieve success. Once you have success, optimizing begins to have more value.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To change how you feel, and how you think, you can simply change where you are sitting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most of my problems were caused by my own bad decisions, lack of skill, and bad luck.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I would define an asshole as anyone who chooses to make the lives of others less pleasant for reasons that don’t appear productive or necessary. I assume asshole behavior exists because it feels good when you do it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you ruin yourself, you won’t be able to work on any other priorities. So taking care of your own health is job one.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The next rings are your local community, your country, and the world, in that order. Don’t bother trying to fix the world until you get the inner circles of your priorities under control.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It’s not a foolproof gauge, but if you know a particular path will make you feel more stressed, unhealthy, and drained, it’s probably the wrong choice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On the other hand, if your boss routinely asks you to work overtime for no good reason other than to claw through piles of brain-deadening administrative work, you probably need to look for a new job.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Priorities are the things you need to get right so the things you love can thrive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your brain is wired to continuously analyze your environment, your thoughts, and your health and to use that information to generate a sensation you call your attitude. You can control your attitude by manipulating your thoughts, your body, and your environment. A positive attitude is an important tool. It’s important to get it right. The best way to manage your attitude is by understanding your basic nature as a moist robot that can be programmed for happiness if you understand the user interface. Exercise, food, and sleep should be your first buttons to push if you’re trying to elevate your attitude.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For the truly bad moods, exercise, nutrition, sleep, and time are the smart buttons to push.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let your ideas for the future fuel your energy today. No matter what you want to do in life, higher energy will help you get there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Walk away from the soul suckers. You have a right to pursue happiness and an equal right to run as fast as you can from the people who would deny it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A great strategy for success in life is to become good at something, anything, and let that feeling propel you to new and better victories. Success can be habit-forming.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The way I motivate myself to take on a task this large is by imagining that I have fascinating and useful things to say that will help people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you manage your illusions wisely, you might get what you want, but you won’t necessarily understand why it worked.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Never assume you understand the odds of things. My optimism is like an old cat that likes to disappear for days, but I always expect it to return.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thanks to my odd life experiences, and odder genes, I’m wired to think things will work out well for me no matter how unlikely it might seem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A child who eagerly accepts the risk of embarrassment in front of a crowd—even a friendly crowd—probably has some talent for entertaining. The smartest system for discerning your best path to success involves trying lots of different things—sampling, if you will.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Things that will someday work out well start out well. Things that will never work start out bad and stay that way. What you rarely see is a stillborn failure that transmogrifies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The predictor is that customers were clamoring for the bad versions of the product before the good versions were even invented.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My observation is that some people are born with a natural impulse to practice things and some people find mindless repetition without immediate reward to be a form of torture.It’s naive to expect the average person to embrace endless practice in pursuit of long-term success.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Success isn’t magic; it’s generally the product of picking a good system and following it until luck finds you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The formula, roughly speaking, is that every skill you acquire doubles your odds of success.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My combined mediocre skills are worth far more than the sum of the parts. If you think extraordinary talent and a maniacal pursuit of excellence are necessary for success, I say that’s just one approach, and probably the hardest. When it comes to skills, quantity often beats quality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The More You Know, the More You Can Know&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The more time you spend exposing yourself to bad news, the more it will weigh on you and sap your energy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t think of the news as information. Think of it as a source of energy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That seems like an obvious strategy and you probably think you already do it. The hard part is figuring out the odds of any given game, and that’s harder than it looks. Several years ago I gave a talk to a fifth-grade class.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t assume you know how much potential you have. Sometimes the only way to know what you can do is to test yourself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When I look at the list of my personal failures and successes, one of the things that stand out is psychology.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quality is not an independent force in the universe; it depends on what you choose as your frame of reference.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When politicians tell lies, they know the press will call them out. They also know it doesn’t matter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A lie that makes a voter feel good is more effective than a hundred rational arguments. That’s even true when the voter knows the lie is a lie. If you’re perplexed at how society can tolerate politicians who lie so blatantly, you’re thinking of people as rational beings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If your view of the world is that people use reason for their important decisions, you are setting yourself up for a life of frustration and confusion. You’ll find yourself continually debating people and never winning except in your own mind. Few things are as destructive and limiting as a worldview that assumes people are mostly rational.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Steve Jobs’s understanding that the way a product makes users feel trumps most other considerations, including price. If Steve Jobs had seen people as rational beings, he might have followed a path similar to Dell, selling highly capable machines at the lowest possible price.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rational behavior is especially useless in any situation that is too complex for a human to grasp. Cell-phone companies exploit that fact by offering pricing plans that are too complicated to compare with the competition. (I coined the word “confusopoly” to describe that strategy.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instead, consumers make largely uninformed decisions and convince themselves they did well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“The boy hit the ball” more easily than “The ball was hit by the boy.” Unnecessary words and passive writing kill the timing of humor the same way they kill the persuasiveness of your point. If you want people to see you as smart, persuasive, and funny, consider taking a two-day class in business writing. There aren’t many skills you can learn in two days that will serve you this well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In my entire life I have never met a stranger who didn’t have some fascinating life experiences that spilled out if I asked the right questions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The point of conversation is to make the other person feel good. If you do that one simple thing correctly, the other benefits come along with the deal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People are predisposed to liking attractive people. Talking can only make things worse. If you’re attractive, be sure you’ve created a solid connection before discussing your hobby of collecting baby animal skulls or whatever the hell you’re&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try to get in the habit of asking yourself how you can turn your interesting experiences into story form.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People drift off when you stop talking about stuff that isn’t, well, them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;remember that most people feel awkward in social situations at least some of the time. Chances are that the person you are talking to is feeling just as shy. e single best tip for avoiding shyness involves harnessing the power of acting interested in other people. You don’t want to cross into nosiness, but everyone appreciates it when you show interest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The more you put yourself in potentially embarrassing situations, the easier they all become.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Success builds confidence and confidence suppresses shyness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It’s surprising how uncommon common sense is.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Hopefully” should be an adverb. Say instead, “We waited hopefully for dessert.” In the latter case, “hopefully” is correctly modifying the verb “waited.” In the first example, hopefully just sits there like the wrong word choice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A good starting point in learning the art of persuasion is to go to your preferred online bookstore and search for “persuasion.” You’ll see a number of books on the topic. Keep reading those books until they seem to be repeating the same tricks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apparently the word “because” signals reasonableness, and reasonableness allows people to let down their defenses and drop their objections.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you show enthusiasm, others will want to experience the same rush.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cults are a good example of insanity being viewed as leadership.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In any kind of negotiation, the worst thing you can do is act reasonable. Reasonable people generally cave in to irrational people because it seems like the path of least resistance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It’s important to keep a lot of distance between your fun voice and your persuasive voice. For people who know you, the serious voice will send an unambiguous signal that the topic is important and you might not be open to negotiating. But research shows that voice quality is far more important to your overall health and happiness than you might imagine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was literally acting, but it didn’t feel disingenuous because the business world is a lot like theater. Everyone tries to get into character for the job they have.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Despite my obvious lack of ability, nearly every boss I had—and there were many—identified me as a future corporate executive. I doubt that was the case. I think my fake professional voice and body language were at least half of the reason I was seen as having management potential. Unfortunately the flirting stopped as soon as anyone saw me in person. That’s why I assume my fake voice was the secret sauce.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I see in successful people: They treat success as a learnable skill.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People who enjoy humor are simply more attractive than people who don’t. It’s human nature to want to spend time with people who can appreciate a good laugh or, better yet, cause one.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“I, Scott, will become rich.” The long version of the story involves two ridiculously lucky stock picks that came to me out of nowhere in separate flashes of something that felt like intuition.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I’m just a good stock picker and far more handsome than my lying mirror is willing to admit. Whatever the real reason for my success, I got enough of a payoff to encourage me to keep trying affirmations just in case there was something to them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I tried a lot of different ventures, stayed optimistic, put in the energy, prepared myself by learning as much as I could, and stayed in the game long enough for luck to find me. I hoped a buck would eventually walk by, and with Dilbert it did.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Luck won’t give you a strategy or a system—you have to do that part yourself. I find it helpful to see the world as a slot machine that doesn’t ask you to put money in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The pattern I noticed is that the affirmations only worked when I had a 100 percent unambiguous desire for success.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My attitude was always the same: Escape from my cell, free the other inmates, shoot the warden, and burn down the prison.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My observation and best guess is that experts are right about 98 percent of the time on the easy stuff but only right 50 percent of the time on anything that is unusually complicated, mysterious, or even new. If your gut feeling (intuition) disagrees with the experts, take that seriously. You might be experiencing some pattern recognition that you can’t yet verbalize.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are probably dozens of ways we absorb energy, inspiration, skills, and character traits from those around us. Sometimes we learn by example. Sometimes success appears more approachable and ordinary because we see normal people achieve it, and perhaps that encourages us to pursue schemes with higher&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We can’t always know the mechanism by which others change our future actions, but it’s pretty clear it happens, and it’s important.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The programming interface is your location. To change yourself, part of the solution might involve spending more time with the people who represent the change you seek.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For starters, the single biggest trick for manipulating your happiness chemistry is being able to do what you want, when you want.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A person with a flexible schedule and average resources will be happier than a rich person who has everything except a flexible schedule. Step one in your search for happiness is to continually work toward having control of your schedule.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In your personal life and your career, consider schedule flexibility when making any big decision.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t let reality control your imagination. Let your imagination be the user interface to steer your reality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Happiness is the natural state for most people whenever they feel healthy, have flexible schedules, and expect the future to be good.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I’m here to tell you that the primary culprit in your bad moods is a deficit in one of the big five: flexible schedule, imagination, sleep, diet, and exercise. The usual reaction is a blank expression followed by a change of topic. No one wants to believe that the formula for happiness is as simple as daydreaming, controlling your schedule, napping, eating right, and being active every day. You’d feel like an idiot for suffering so many unhappy days while not knowing the cure was so accessible. I know from experience that you might&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My best estimate is that 80 percent of your mood is based on how your body feels and only 20 percent is based on your genes and your circumstances,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That’s why I include diet and fitness in a book about success. If you get your health in order, success will come more easily.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And always remember that failure is your friend. It is the raw material of success. Invite it in. Learn from it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Dabbling with AI</title>
    <link>/posts/dabbling-with-ai/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/dabbling-with-ai/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;A friend and I have started building AI products on the weekends to get used to the latest AI tools and their capabilities. Even though we’re just a few weeks into this (while also managing our day jobs), I’m really impressed by how advanced these tools are. Back in 2019, I dreamed of building products on my own, without relying on developers. Thanks to ser Musk and Altman, that dream is now a reality. I no longer need developers or even designers to launch the first version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What truly matters now is distribution i.e. giving your product the best chance to succeed. This is exactly what I learnt at Questbook and plan to double down on during my free time. I’ll be sharing our first product on my website and other channels. If you are on similar path, feel free to reach out and &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/roohchill&#34;&gt;DM&lt;/a&gt; me on Twitter. Stay tuned for more updates!&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Shifting Tides in Investments</title>
    <link>/posts/shifting-tides-in-investments/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/shifting-tides-in-investments/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;US stocks are at an all-time high, and a comparison between Big Tech P/E ratios and the S&amp;amp;P 500 does indicate that stocks might be overvalued. Both Warren Buffett and Michael Burry have started reallocating their investments from US markets to Chinese and other markets. While I&amp;rsquo;m still evaluating new positions, I&amp;rsquo;ve already started reducing my exposure to US stocks, Indian small and mid-cap stocks, which appear significantly overvalued relative to the broader index.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
    src=&#34;https://axiomatic-diver-1c4.notion.site/image/attachment%3A56e4e7cf-92bc-42d6-bbef-14d2cfb8664a%3AScreenshot_2025-02-16_at_12.55.44_PM.png?table=block&amp;amp;id=19c8b13c-4f08-8099-a880-d0479ff51c19&amp;amp;spaceId=c6a62786-f859-45a8-8419-fae4370cf6f4&amp;amp;width=1420&amp;amp;userId=&amp;amp;cache=v2&#34; 
    alt=&#34;img&#34; 
     /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m also planning to increase my holdings in Chinese stocks and index. To build your own pov, check out this &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qwKvn2mIwl4&#34;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Things I Will Consider Before Working With Someone...</title>
    <link>/posts/things-i-will-consider-before-working-with-someone.../</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/things-i-will-consider-before-working-with-someone.../</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;A short piece  on things that I will consider before working with a company or a group of individuals going forward. There are a number of additonal considerations which I&amp;rsquo;ll try to add later to this post. You may find this helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leadership Quality&lt;/strong&gt;:
When joining a company, carefully evaluate the authenticity of leadership. Many founders are driven by wealth, status, need to earn respect,  or personal gain rather than genuine mission. While these motivations aren&amp;rsquo;t  wrong, ensure they align with your values. Ser Elon creates markets through conviction, but yeah, such leaders are rare.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Growth Potential&lt;/strong&gt;:
There are about 400 million companies globally. Be selective about your environment. Avoid toxic founders who run away from accountability and mistreat others. Their treatment of close associates often reveals their true character. Pay attention to patterns of blame-shifting and how they handle difficult questions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Balancing Risk Reward&lt;/strong&gt;:
Time and energy are your most finite resources - more valuable than monetary compensation. Don&amp;rsquo;t let high salary blind you to red flags about toxic environments. Choose energizing workplaces with competent leadership over higher-paying but demoralizing situations. I would personally prefer working  with talented, well-intentioned colleagues over working with self-proclaimed, narcissistic leaders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intentionality&lt;/strong&gt;:
Match opportunities to your current priorities. Keep your &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.paulgraham.com/identity.html&#34;&gt;identity small&lt;/a&gt; to avoid over-attachment to any role. If financial stability is your goal, consider big tech or well-funded startups. For rapid learning, early-stage startups or VC funds might be more suitable. Above all, prioritize working with trustworthy colleagues who energize rather than drain you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s Okay to Leave Early&lt;/strong&gt;:
Treat the initial period as mutual evaluation. Despite the current employer-favored dynamic, don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to leave toxic companies early. While a formal 14-day trial period would be ideal, use your early days to assess the environment&amp;rsquo;s compatibility with your goals and values. Your potential growth in the next 6-12 months is more valuable than enduring a poor fit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to DM me on &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/roohchill&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; if you have any thoughts on this topic.&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>2025 Personal Focus Areas </title>
    <link>/posts/2025-focus-areas/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/2025-focus-areas/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;My key learning from recent years has been the power of focus rather than broad diversification. After some reflection, I&amp;rsquo;ve moved away from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ruchilsharma.com/posts/personal-okrs-2020/&#34;&gt;OKR framework&lt;/a&gt; in favor of defining targeted focus areas for growth. I also came up with a personal mission statement that captures my core drive. While this remains open to change, it encapsulates what pushes me forward each day. It currently stands at:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;lsquo;To inspire others and myself by challenging the status quo and create new useful things.’&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; This isn&amp;rsquo;t something to complete or check off – it&amp;rsquo;s a compass that I intend to use to guide my decisions and keep me focused during challenging times. This blog is one such attempt towards the mission statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While OKRs are valuable, I found they often led to diluted effort across too many goals. For 2025, I&amp;rsquo;m concentrating on specific high-impact areas:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning macro trends and technical analysis for investing :&lt;/strong&gt; Forget technical analysis, most of us are not taught even the basics of how to grow our wealth. Schools and universities do a terrible job at it. While index investing serves as a good foundation for many, I&amp;rsquo;ve met investors who have deeper market insights and often achieve superior returns. This involves understanding macroeconomic relationships – how interest rate decisions influence market behavior, the interplay between traditional and digital assets, and identifying sectors positioned for outperformance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only do I want to get good at it, I also want to go much deeper into reading blue and green candles and optimize entry and exit points in trades. You can grow your wealth twice if the price of an asset hits the same price after a certain duration. Building conviction and having the courage to take the trade are the hardest part. I’m not suggesting getting into leverage trading, but to explore ways to grow your wealth much faster than index investing.  The question is how many of us are willing to go deeper into it and become self reliant faster. Edited version of sir Peter Thiel’s quote “ &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/quotes/8670225-if-you-have-a-10-year-plan-of-how-to-get#:~:text=If%20you%20have%20a%2010%2Dyear%20plan%20of%20how%20to%20get%20%5Bsomewhere%5D%2C%20you%20should%20ask%3A%20Why%20can%E2%80%99t%20you%20do%20this%20in%206%20months%3F&#34;&gt;If you want to gain financial freedom by 40, why can’t you do it in the next one year?&lt;/a&gt;” While this approach carries higher risks than passive investing, I believe the potential for learning new skills and financial growth outweighs the comfort of staying on the sidelines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One simple example related to this is just holding dollars instead of Rs. You can grow your wealth by 5% every year by just holding dollars due to Re. depreciation. The answer is either US stocks or Stablecoins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Building Compelling Narratives and Storytelling&lt;/strong&gt; : Narratives and memes run the World. Some have the power to shape our world and move people to action. From Musk ser’s vision of making humanity multi-planetary to Steve Jobs calling computers as &amp;lsquo;bicycles for the mind,&amp;rsquo; to the most influential songs of this and the past centuries, we use storytelling to inspire collective progress. These aren&amp;rsquo;t just taglines – they&amp;rsquo;re powerful statements that align people toward ambitious goals that extend beyond individuals. Most missions are unattainable, but still they tap into our fundamental nature as emotional beings. Great leaders are amazing at this skill and I want to spend enough time on this axis in 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Building Products using AI :&lt;/strong&gt;  Not being able to code isn’t an excuse anymore for not shipping products.  In 2025, my focus will be on practical application – shipping mobile apps using AI tools rather than getting caught up in theoretical discussions. I&amp;rsquo;ll be prioritizing tangible outcomes over perfect processes, using AI as an enabler for shipping products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;AI speed up:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;- Engineering: 4x faster&lt;br&gt;- Design: 40% faster&lt;br&gt;- Prototyping: 10x faster&lt;br&gt;- PM: 40x faster&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Sahil Lavingia (@shl) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/shl/status/1876989592793997727?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;January 8, 2025&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Becoming Better at FIFA  :&lt;/strong&gt; Purchasing a PS5 marked a meaningful return to gaming after an eight-year gaming pause since college. During my college days, I consistently ranked among the top three players in local FIFA tournaments. While my skills have  declined over the years – currently reflected in my online friendly matches – I want to get back to old levels. My goal will be to achieve a 95% win rate in online friendlies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I aim to return to the accountability and mindset levels I achieved in 2021. Growth comes from embracing every setback as an opportunity to improve. At its core, mindset is the fundamental driver of daily progress and continuous improvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Growth mindset is just replying to yourself with “skill issue” every time something goes wrong&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Emmett Shear (@eshear) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/eshear/status/1733562620270023129?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;December 9, 2023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
    &lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>2024 Reflections and Looking Ahead</title>
    <link>/posts/2024-reflections/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/2024-reflections/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;2024 has been a year of significant transitions and self-discovery. One of the major changes was my decision to move on from Questbook and Reclaim protocol to take time for reflection. After my longest professional stint (~4 years) as the first employee, saying goodbye wasn&amp;rsquo;t easy. I had poured everything into my role at Questbook, and remain hopeful about our funding round. I&amp;rsquo;ve now started a new chapter at Uber, and I&amp;rsquo;m excited about what lies ahead. Through these experiences, I&amp;rsquo;ve gathered several insights that I want to share - most of them advice to myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Working Out is Non-Negotiable -&lt;/strong&gt; Despite your friends joking that you might end up looking like a gym trainer, maintaining a consistent workout routine can be game changing. Over the past 1.5 years, working out and playing football (once a week) has become my daily routine. All worries, stress, just disappear during this time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be Intentional About Your Career Path -&lt;/strong&gt; In my early career days, I often let serendipity guide my choices. While some decisions were driven by interesting problem statements, I didn&amp;rsquo;t think deeply about my long-term direction. After conversations with over 500 professionals in my network, I&amp;rsquo;ve realized the importance of intentional career planning. Though this might seem to contradict &lt;a href=&#34;https://alchemy.substack.com/p/make-something-wonderful-steve-jobs&#34;&gt;Steve Jobs&amp;rsquo; advice against&lt;/a&gt; career planning, the reality is that certain boxes need to be checked for profile consideratio, especually in Big tech. What&amp;rsquo;s important is understanding what you want in your current life phase. Your desires will evolve, so focus on your goals for the next two years - looking beyond that is futile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zoomed In vs Zoomed Out View -&lt;/strong&gt; After eight years of professional experience, stepping away from Questbook gave me the chance to zoom out and confront questions I&amp;rsquo;d never asked myself: What do I want next? For how long? Why? How will it align with my future goals? While there are no universally right answers, there&amp;rsquo;s usually one that resonates most strongly with you. This introspection led me to withdraw from some opportunities, potentially disappointing people in my network. But it marked the first time I truly thought deeply about myself and my path. To those I might have inconvenienced in this process - I apologize.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Know When to Move On :&lt;/strong&gt; When your contributions to a company&amp;rsquo;s growth decrease while you becoming a cost, it&amp;rsquo;s time to reassess. Companies pivot, and their vision may be different  from yours. The key is to communicate openly and seek common ground. If alignment seems impossible, it&amp;rsquo;s time to move forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Choose your &lt;del&gt;Peers&lt;/del&gt; Leaders Wisely:&lt;/strong&gt; As the first employee at a Series A (soon to be Series B) company, I gained a ton insights into the  dynamics between founders, customers, investors, employees, and other stakeholders. This experience taught me crucial lessons about storytelling, detecting bullshit, fundraising, team building, and stress management. I highly recommend going after such opportunities early in your career, but choose carefully - your selection can be life-changing. Feel free to reach out if you need guidance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A simple note :&lt;/strong&gt; Being contrarian and right just once can transform your life trajectory forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On Choosing Non Linear Career Path :&lt;/strong&gt; My career has been anything but conventional. From consulting for a Special Chief Secretary of the Government to working in venture capital at Kalaari Capital, product management at Grofers (now Blinkit), being a first employee in web3 and B2B SaaS, and now PM at Uber - each role has been unique. The diversity of challenges and my colleagues has shaped who I am in ways that are hard to articulate. Looking back, the dots do connect favourably. The benefits are clear: cross-industry knowledge transfer, multiple opportunities to learn from zero, and increased credibility across various domains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Preparing for the AI Future -&lt;/strong&gt; AI will likely transform most jobs as we know them. Hence, it&amp;rsquo;s important to build as much financial runway as possible before this accelerates. Nonody knows what the future might look like. But we must continue doing our jobs while being aware of this reality - it feels like we&amp;rsquo;re all protagonists in a thriller movie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worrying is a waste of mental energy and doesn&amp;rsquo;t improve any situation. More often than not, it&amp;rsquo;s inaction that leads to worry and stress. The antidote is taking action, however small.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe crypto will go mainstream through consumer social applications. This is definitely a space I&amp;rsquo;ll be watching closely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing is perhaps one of the most undervalued exercises. It&amp;rsquo;s a powerful tool for mental clarity. I regret not writing more consistently after July, 2024, but expect more consistent blogposts from me in 2025&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Back to the Keyboard</title>
    <link>/posts/back-to-the-keyboard/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/back-to-the-keyboard/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;After a six-month pause filled with questions and conversations, a bit of travel, and a renewed focus on physical well-being, I’m back at the keyboard. 2024 has been that year that has made me realise that we truly live in unprecedented times. Each day brings a new reminder of just how uncertain the future is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will share a detailed reflection post soon. For now, I’m simply glad to be back in front of the screen. Stay tuned for more regular posts ahead. Hope you have a good time with your family during this break.&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Memecoins as a way to consume news</title>
    <link>/posts/memecoins-as-a-way-to-consume-news/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/memecoins-as-a-way-to-consume-news/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;Publicly admiting, I dismissed memecoins before the term even existed. But I am also acknowledging the fact that the recent surge in Solana memecoin activity has undeniably contributed to the current bull market. In fact, most of my friends outside the crypto sphere are now asking me which memecoin they should invest in, highlighting the significant impact memecoins have had on the crypto landscape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trading and investing in memecoins will become a normalized and acceptable practice, much like betting has been for years. Just as Warren Buffet made his fortune by identifying high ROI stocks early in his career, the next Warren Buffet is likely sitting behind a laptop, building the framework and developing the playbook for investing in memecoins. By the time this playbook becomes public, he/she will have already amassed a fortune. Crypto drastically accelerates the realization cycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond their financial implications, memecoins also serve as a reflection of current events and news. Memecoins such as BODEN or MODI are clearly signals that elections are around the corner or underway. Unless you are living under a rock! The way we consume information in the future may look very different from what we’re accustomed to today. Future is not evenly distributed.&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>The Business of Selling Fear</title>
    <link>/posts/the-business-of-selling-fear/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/the-business-of-selling-fear/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;“AI will take all jobs.” “You shouldn’t be in your job if you do not know y”. I see these posts everyday on X from various Twitter gurus. These statements seem to do nothing but scare folks. It feels like they’re more into fear-mongering than anything truly insightful, similar to a street-corner astrologer warning of dire consequences just to make a quick buck. Despite that, why do these gurus have massive popularity? Because tech workers already feel insecure about their futures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a post ZIRP era coupled with layoffs and advancements in AI, tech workforce is faced to question their value to their employer. Most fear peddlers just amplify these anxieties, hoping to boost their own following or sell their courses. It doesn’t take much for them to sensationalise and confidently lie about the future. But in this process, they shake the confidence of a 22 year old who’s just starting out in his/her carreer. It’s sad to see that the anxiety of our youth can be exploited for profit. I do not know the right answer to solve this, but things can definitely be improved if Twitter gurus start to question the consequences of their posts. They are called “influencers” for a reason. I’m not saying that all posts are meant to instill fear in the audience, but most posts are for profit or follower maximisation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My suggestion to young individuals would be to critically assess everything they read online. Take this advice for instance, “traveling in your 20s is essential because you won’t enjoy it as much later in life.” People pushing these ideas often haven’t lived enough to speak with authority. My dad, who just turned 57, travels way more than many younger folks sitting behind their laptops. If you have a severe financial crunch, your travel plans can definitely wait. Don’t feel FOMOed by such posts. These “influencers” are just trying to justify their reasoning behind their recent decision to go on a trip and their spends. Be wary of generic life advice floating around like “It’s meant to be” or “You’ll fail if you’re not working 70 hours a week.” These blanket statements can be more harmful than helpful. To reduce anxiety and avoid doubting your worth, apply a filter of context to everything you read or listen. Consider your own situation before taking any advice to heart. By doing so, you’ll likely find yourself in a far reasonable state than if you absorbed every fear-inducing post on your feed. Prioritise a better future over externally triggered fear.&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Retro App Breakdown</title>
    <link>/posts/retro-app-breakdown/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/retro-app-breakdown/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;On most weekends, I try to breakdown mobile apps and make sense of why something exists within an app and what could have been done better. Last week, I went through Retro App. You can go through the breakdown &lt;a href=&#34;https://notability.com/n/218p0go6p7xQHPXSip4OBJ&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; . If you want to go through the onboarding experience, you’d an do so &lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1gfdLnRxKVAYMpi4eEfIaftMN6WZiFLB_/view?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A couple of interesting things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unlike Instagram’s social graph, Retro app has purposefully focused on restricting what you see and share with your friends. Not any random stranger on the internet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It pushes the users to create content or share their pictures and discourages passive viewing weeding out lurkers early in their user journey.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Should We Be More Direct?</title>
    <link>/posts/should-we-be-more-direct/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/should-we-be-more-direct/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;Most young folks at the start of their careers want to take up as much as they can. Time isn’t a concern at all. Well, why not? We are taught to “learn and work hard” and everything will fall in place by itself. It has to … Twitter gurus preach to prioritise long term over short term without telling you what long term means.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, what if there’s an alternative approach? By focusing on short-term objectives, we might be able to find our long-term objectives. Most individuals do not know what they want out of their lives in the long term. Figuring it out takes multiple iteration. It is a continuous exercise which easily takes a few years. Meanwhile, we spend countless hours working on things that realistically, won’t drastically change our lives. Then why do most people grind on their first jobs? They primarily want enough to pay their bills while at the same time convincing themselves that whatever they are working on is their long term goal. This usually isn’t the case. I’m excluding the very few who genuinely love their work and pursue it passionately for its own sake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine if young professionals prioritized earning money above all else to buy the freedom in order to explore their long-term aspirations. Indeed, pursuing higher salaries and promotions is one way to achieve this, but it’s crucial for the accumulated wealth to grow, which doesn’t happen automatically. There are 22-year-olds with net worths of $2 million, achieved by early investments in meme coins, running nodes, receiving airdrops, and trading stocks. They don’t have money problems anymore and have enough time to think what they want next in life. Contrast this with the average hard worker who has been grinding for years with an average pay, most deposits in FD and who is anxious about being replaced by AI. Effective portfolio management and seizing high-return opportunities require time and connections that is very difficult to achieve with a relentless work schedule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cryptocurrencies (not crypto) have made enough millionaires who did not graduate from elite colleges. In fact, the correlation between your ability to make money and your university reputation is only decreasing by the day. Additionally, there’s no shame in trading, aping into memecoins anymore. Betting has been normalised since years. If you can master these skills and proactively seek financial gains instead of passively waiting for wealth accumulation, you will be able to find the space you need to figure out your life’s direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being more direct and truthful to yourself in the short term may in fact be the best answer to all you worries. Gurus will keep saying “long term” and they already have $ millions in their bank. The real question is, are you ready to be more direct in the short term?&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>So you want to setup your own blog</title>
    <link>/posts/so-you-want-to-setup-your-own-blog/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/so-you-want-to-setup-your-own-blog/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;If a cool blogpost template is stopping you from writing more, the problem is most definitely not that cool template. Writing more requires writing a lot in the initial phases. Same goes with writing well. It’s about turning on your mental faucet to let the ideas flow freely, which in turn, leads to quality content. If you really think a cool blog website will help you cross your motivation barrier and push you to start writing more, then maybe this post can help. I greatly admire Tomasz Tunguz’s writings , and my website draws inspiration from his. Here’s a breakdown of how I launched my blog:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Selecting a Static Website Generator: After evaluating various options, I decided on Hugo.
Choosing a Theme: I selected a theme from here.
Customizing the Theme to Fit Your Needs: My advice is to avoid overthinking the design process or spending too much time on it. The goal is to publish your first post as quickly as possible. Don’t think too much about the aesthetics of your site. For example, I haven’t yet added a subscribe button yet to directly identify and engage with readers.
Consistency is Key: Publish posts regularly and write primarily for yourself. It’s incredibly rewarding to know even just one person reads your posts consistently.
Monitor Your Progress: Regularly tracking my posting activity has not only improved my thinking but has also enabled me to achieve my goal of learning HTML and CSS. I’ve thoroughly enjoyed every aspect of redesigning my blog and tailoring it to my preferences, starting from the initial template selection. For instance, my Github activity data looks very different from what it was before 2022. I had ~ 50 Github contributions last year and already have ~10 this year compared with zero a few years back.
If you have any further questions, feel free to DM on Twitter. I would love to help you kickstart your writing journey.&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Reddit May Define the Future of IPOs</title>
    <link>/posts/reddit-may-define-the-future-of-ipos/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/reddit-may-define-the-future-of-ipos/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;Reddit, founded in 2005, has filed for an IPO. If you missed out on other indicators of this bull market, this is definitely one of the most glaring ones. Markets have opened up, tech stocks and top crypto tokens such as Bitcoin and Ethereum are ripping. But there’s one thing special about Reddit IPO’s that is not talked about enough - stock allocation to it users&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Stratechery:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
    src=&#34;https://axiomatic-diver-1c4.notion.site/image/https%3A%2F%2Fprod-files-secure.s3.us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2Fc6a62786-f859-45a8-8419-fae4370cf6f4%2F017ae6ec-30ca-467b-aa86-513aff84c359%2FIMG_0224.jpeg?table=block&amp;amp;id=17423d13-e6cf-44e6-ab6e-3ce885f444f8&amp;amp;spaceId=c6a62786-f859-45a8-8419-fae4370cf6f4&amp;amp;width=1420&amp;amp;userId=&amp;amp;cache=v2&#34; 
    alt=&#34;image&#34; 
     /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Airdrops and token allocation for community members is very common in the Web3 universe, but users of a web2 platform getting a stock allocation for their contributions is unheard of in the Web 2 World. I find this decision taken by the Reddit founders really fascinating! It may well define how IPOs are announced from this point onwards and a way for Web 2 companies to earn user trust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the World is already sleeping on how much one can earn through airdrops. But I’m glad to see the community ownership ethos of Web3 adopted by early internet companies. If users are indeed the product of most Web2 social companies, they should be compensated for growing that product and making it better. This post from Balaji is worth paying attention to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;REDDIT&amp;#39;S IPO DAO&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Is Reddit becoming a DAO?!?&lt;br&gt;Well, not exactly. But kind of.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;An underreported feature of the Reddit IPO is that they&amp;#39;re decentralizing ownership. Early users can get in on the same terms as institutional investors, which is unusual:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;This is definitely a sign of… &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/WdtbiyeWMA&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/WdtbiyeWMA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Balaji (@balajis) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/balajis/status/1763067849218850939?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;February 29, 2024&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;



    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Excerpts from Man&#39;s Search for Meaning</title>
    <link>/posts/excerpts-from-mans-search-for-meaning/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/excerpts-from-mans-search-for-meaning/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;I recently finished the Man’s Search for Meaning which was long kept on my digital bookshelf. I found the following excerpts the most interesting that I’ll keep with me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-love&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#on-love&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg class=&#34;icon&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; focusable=&#34;false&#34; height=&#34;16&#34; version=&#34;1.1&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 16 16&#34; width=&#34;16&#34;&gt;
            &lt;path fill-rule=&#34;evenodd&#34;
                d=&#34;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&#34;&gt;
            &lt;/path&gt;
        &lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    On love
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
    src=&#34;https://axiomatic-diver-1c4.notion.site/image/https%3A%2F%2Fprod-files-secure.s3.us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2Fc6a62786-f859-45a8-8419-fae4370cf6f4%2Fb3374d9c-4834-4887-937b-9c399605dd89%2FScreenshot_2024-03-04_at_1.54.51_PM.png?table=block&amp;amp;id=0d92ad00-1bd7-4d20-b0e4-0f65d08e45eb&amp;amp;spaceId=c6a62786-f859-45a8-8419-fae4370cf6f4&amp;amp;width=1420&amp;amp;userId=&amp;amp;cache=v2&#34; 
    alt=&#34;image&#34; 
     /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-choosing-ones-attitude&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#on-choosing-ones-attitude&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg class=&#34;icon&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; focusable=&#34;false&#34; height=&#34;16&#34; version=&#34;1.1&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 16 16&#34; width=&#34;16&#34;&gt;
            &lt;path fill-rule=&#34;evenodd&#34;
                d=&#34;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&#34;&gt;
            &lt;/path&gt;
        &lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    On Choosing One’s Attitude
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
    src=&#34;https://axiomatic-diver-1c4.notion.site/image/https%3A%2F%2Fprod-files-secure.s3.us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2Fc6a62786-f859-45a8-8419-fae4370cf6f4%2Fda97a748-4ad1-4192-bcb0-5b39683fe709%2FScreenshot_2024-03-04_at_1.55.34_PM.png?table=block&amp;amp;id=8215ca69-c7ba-4aa2-a9ea-4e3566736122&amp;amp;spaceId=c6a62786-f859-45a8-8419-fae4370cf6f4&amp;amp;width=1420&amp;amp;userId=&amp;amp;cache=v2&#34; 
    alt=&#34;image&#34; 
     /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-the-meaning-of-life&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#on-the-meaning-of-life&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg class=&#34;icon&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; focusable=&#34;false&#34; height=&#34;16&#34; version=&#34;1.1&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 16 16&#34; width=&#34;16&#34;&gt;
            &lt;path fill-rule=&#34;evenodd&#34;
                d=&#34;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&#34;&gt;
            &lt;/path&gt;
        &lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    On the Meaning of Life
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
    src=&#34;https://axiomatic-diver-1c4.notion.site/image/https%3A%2F%2Fprod-files-secure.s3.us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2Fc6a62786-f859-45a8-8419-fae4370cf6f4%2Fc21473de-2ceb-4040-abd2-ce42ac35fe8a%2FScreenshot_2024-03-04_at_1.57.04_PM.png?table=block&amp;amp;id=10a3acfd-e78d-4f40-9207-4f704651480a&amp;amp;spaceId=c6a62786-f859-45a8-8419-fae4370cf6f4&amp;amp;width=1420&amp;amp;userId=&amp;amp;cache=v2&#34; 
    alt=&#34;image&#34; 
     /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
    src=&#34;https://axiomatic-diver-1c4.notion.site/image/https%3A%2F%2Fprod-files-secure.s3.us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2Fc6a62786-f859-45a8-8419-fae4370cf6f4%2F1f014a78-636f-4dd9-aa9d-7102f32b84da%2FScreenshot_2024-03-04_at_1.57.25_PM.png?table=block&amp;amp;id=00597784-2457-4d49-b556-c56fe86cac23&amp;amp;spaceId=c6a62786-f859-45a8-8419-fae4370cf6f4&amp;amp;width=1420&amp;amp;userId=&amp;amp;cache=v2&#34; 
    alt=&#34;Screenshot 2024-03-04 at 1.57.25 PM.png&#34; 
     /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Pausing Monthly Reads</title>
    <link>/posts/pausing-monthy-reads/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/pausing-monthy-reads/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;I tried to share the best of what I read each month through my previous posts. While it helped me to push myself write a post each month, it was coming in the way of meditating on what I read. I will try to write (reming me if I don’t) a post on what meditation on what you’ve read means, but it definitely does not mean completing your reading backlog for the sake of it. I will be pausing these monthly posts, and will instead try to share a list of interesting reads once I have meditated over them.&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>ID by amoamo Breakdown</title>
    <link>/posts/id-by-amoamo-breakdown/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/id-by-amoamo-breakdown/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;I’ve been keeping track of the new app in town ID by amoamo and found its onboarding and user experience really refreshing as compared to most other social media apps. I even Tweeted about it which was caught up by some of their team members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;This was quite innovative by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/amoamoamo?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@amoamoamo&lt;/a&gt;  app. Explaining why you should invite your friends while humanising the experience . Felt refreshing &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/MqwuzeIwWF&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/MqwuzeIwWF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; @roohchill (@roohchill) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/roohchill/status/1746512527213965704?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;January 14, 2024&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;You can see the breakdown here&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three things stood out for me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explaining their users why they need to do something in a very creative way such as the above video
The use of haptic touch wherever necessary to make the experience active instead of passive progression
Using refreshing colors and copy to keep the users engaged while not doing it too much. They restrict their users across most touchpoints to take one action at a time&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>What I Read in January</title>
    <link>/posts/what-i-read-in-january/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/what-i-read-in-january/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lennysnewsletter.com/p/what-to-do-if-your-product-isnt-taking&#34;&gt;What to do if your product isn’t taking off&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lennysnewsletter.com/p/how-gong-builds-product&#34;&gt;How Gong builds product&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lennysnewsletter.com/p/adding-a-work-trial-to-your-interview&#34;&gt;Adding a work trial to your interview process&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-pulse-75&#34;&gt;The Pulse #75: Will US companies hire fewer engineers due to Section 174?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-pulse-77-will-ems-and-pms-take&#34;&gt;The Pulse #77: Will EMs and PMs take over TPM roles in a post-ZIRP world?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/zirp-software-engineers&#34;&gt;The end of 0% interest rates: what the new normal means for software engineers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-pulse-79-is-it-fair-for-profitable&#34;&gt;The Pulse #79: Is it fair for profitable companies to fire staff to make more money?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://governance.substack.com/p/this-week-in-governance-feb-1-community&#34;&gt;This Week in Governance - Feb 1: Community, Collaboration, and Financial Frontiers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dydx.forum/t/drc-dydx-foundation-fundraising-proposal/2152&#34;&gt;dYdX Foundation Fundraising Proposal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://stratechery.com/2024/intels-humbling/&#34;&gt;Intel’s Humbling&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://stratechery.com/2024/the-apple-vision-pros-missing-apps/&#34;&gt;The Apple Vision Pro’s Missing Apps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://stratechery.com/2024/the-new-york-times-ai-opportunity/&#34;&gt;The New York Times’ AI Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://notboring.mirror.xyz/XxQuGjzusNj8uVs6louEkOYBxps4GlRLzEwSIFKwQhU&#34;&gt;Framing the Future of the Internet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.decentralised.co/p/the-solana-ecosystem&#34;&gt;The Solana Ecosystem&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Podcast&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.latent.space/p/dec-2023-audio&#34;&gt;The Four Wars of the AI Stack (Dec 2023 Audio Recap)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.latent.space/p/tldraw&#34;&gt;The Accidental AI Canvas - with Steve Ruiz of tldraw&lt;/a&gt; (Very Interesting Indeed)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.latent.space/p/idefics&#34;&gt;How to train your own Large Multimodal Model — with Hugo Laurençon &amp;amp; Leo Tronchon of HuggingFace M4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.latent.space/p/rlhf-201&#34;&gt;RLHF 201 - with Nathan Lambert of AI2 and Interconnects&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://zeroknowledge.fm/306-2/&#34;&gt;Predictions: ZK in 2024&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://zeroknowledge.fm/307-2/&#34;&gt;The Evolution of Aleo with Howard Wu &amp;amp; Alex Pruden&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://zeroknowledge.fm/308-2/&#34;&gt;Avail’s Approach to DA with Prabal Banerjee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://zeroknowledge.fm/309-2/&#34;&gt;ZK Jargon Decoder with Nico Mohnblatt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YXAW1cXb380&amp;amp;list=PLySrw1Nvf-srh6ZnJ033Jb440VKUjVNgX&amp;amp;index=4&#34;&gt;Why Hack the SEC? - The Chopping Block&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4TF_BiExkGk&amp;amp;list=PLySrw1Nvf-srh6ZnJ033Jb440VKUjVNgX&amp;amp;index=3&#34;&gt;When Will the ETF Hype End? The Chopping Block&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KWWwRvlciY8&amp;amp;list=PLySrw1Nvf-srh6ZnJ033Jb440VKUjVNgX&amp;amp;index=2&#34;&gt;Data Availability &amp;amp; Why It’s Important&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tOdd2FPzwzQ&amp;amp;list=PLySrw1Nvf-srh6ZnJ033Jb440VKUjVNgX&amp;amp;index=1&#34;&gt;Points vs. Airdrops - Post Jupiter Airdrop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Book&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dilbert_(TV_series)&#34;&gt;Dilbert 1991 all strips&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Opportunity Spotters vs Squatters</title>
    <link>/posts/opportunity-spotters-vs-squatters/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/opportunity-spotters-vs-squatters/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;In my experience working across various sectors and stages of startups, I’ve learned that successful companies need a balance of visionaries who can conceive new ideas and track industry trends, as well as doers who can execute these ideas. Have too many visionaries who think of imaginative ideas every hour, you’ll end up with a company that has a longer list of ideas than the number of users for a long time. Conversely, a team dominated by executors might find itself fixated on a minor or irrelevant problem for an extended period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Individuals typically possess innate skills that allow them to excel as either visionaries or executors. Recognizing one’s strengths is crucial. While opportunity spotters are indeed rare and often struggle with execution, over-indexing on them will adversely affect the company. A blend of both skill sets is essential. It’s challenging to find a Product Manager who excels equally in both areas. Opportunity spotting demands a free and creative mindset, distinct from the hyper-productive gurus on Twitter. One way could be to leverage your strengths while addressing your weaknesses. If you’re an opportunity spotter, take the time to personally validate your ideas before delegating. If you’re an execution expert, occasionally step back to see the bigger picture. A team that combines these two types of individuals, supported by engineers and designers, is formidable. These roles should work together and appreciate each other’s strengths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I ever run a company, I would assemble teams comprising both these types of individuals to pursue and achieve user-centric goals. The opportunity spotter would envision the possibilities, while the executor, would bring these visions to life. Both personas complement each other’s strength and need to respect the value they bring to the table. One needs to zoom in more to zoom out. The other needs to zoom out more to zoom in.&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Perplexity Initial Thoughts</title>
    <link>/posts/perplexity-initial-thoughts/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/perplexity-initial-thoughts/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;I recently tried out the Perplexity app and was quite impressed with the results. While I’ve not spent enough time to come to a conclusion yet, what really delighted me was the time it took to answer my question. Searching through Perplextiy felt like speaking to a friend who knows what exactly you are looking for and spoon feeding the response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I searched for &lt;em&gt;how should I select an uploaded image on Notability&lt;/em&gt; inside Perplexity &lt;em&gt;search&lt;/em&gt;. Without clicking a single link, Perplexity walked me through the image selection process whereas Google showed an answer to a different question altogether. Perplexity not only understood this simple question correctly, it shared a step by step process to resolve my query instead of an incorrect response as a summary. See screenshots below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
    src=&#34;https://axiomatic-diver-1c4.notion.site/image/https%3A%2F%2Fprod-files-secure.s3.us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2Fc6a62786-f859-45a8-8419-fae4370cf6f4%2Fe6887343-bec9-4dad-a03f-28f70d57fc1e%2FIMG_1953.png?table=block&amp;amp;id=158af74f-4aa2-4b85-80d0-e6174cb6a926&amp;amp;spaceId=c6a62786-f859-45a8-8419-fae4370cf6f4&amp;amp;width=1420&amp;amp;userId=&amp;amp;cache=v2&#34; 
    alt=&#34;img&#34; 
     /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
    src=&#34;https://axiomatic-diver-1c4.notion.site/image/https%3A%2F%2Fprod-files-secure.s3.us-west-2.amazonaws.com%2Fc6a62786-f859-45a8-8419-fae4370cf6f4%2Fc6892b0b-01dd-4cec-873f-17e2e81bb511%2FIMG_1956.jpeg?table=block&amp;amp;id=890f32da-87e4-4f10-96e5-beab300d2ee8&amp;amp;spaceId=c6a62786-f859-45a8-8419-fae4370cf6f4&amp;amp;width=1420&amp;amp;userId=&amp;amp;cache=v2&#34; 
    alt=&#34;img&#34; 
     /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the AI competition intensifies, the key to success will be a product’s ability to understand and quickly answer user queries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently experimented with the Perplexity app and found myself quite taken with its performance. Although I haven’t used it extensively enough to form a definitive opinion, what stood out to me was its rapid response time. Interacting with Perplexity felt akin to conversing with a knowledgeable friend who intuitively grasps what you need and promptly provides the answer. For instance, when I looked up how to select an image in Notability using Perplexity’s search feature, it guided me through the process seamlessly. In contrast, a similar search on Google yielded an entirely unrelated answer. Perplexity not only comprehended my straightforward query accurately but also offered a detailed, step-by-step solution, avoiding the kind of irrelevant summaries other search engines might provide. Below are some screenshots showcasing this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the competition in AI technology intensifies, the key to success will be a product’s ability to understand and quickly answer user queries.&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>On Writing Well and Writing More</title>
    <link>/posts/on-writing-well-and-writing-more/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/on-writing-well-and-writing-more/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;I have written the most in 2023 as compared to the previous years. While I’m proud of my consistency in 2023, the journey from “On writing more” to “On writing well” is indeed a long one. My goal for 2024 is to improve the quality and depth of my writings. If my writing resonates with even just one person (apart from myself), helping them in their personal or professional journey, I’ll consider it a great achievement.&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>What I Read in December</title>
    <link>/posts/what-i-read-in-december/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/what-i-read-in-december/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lennysnewsletter.com/p/lessons-from-going-freemium-a-decision&#34;&gt;Lessons from going freemium: a decision that broke our business&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/inside-openai-how-does-chatgpt-ship&#34;&gt;Inside OpenAI: How does ChatGPT Ship So Quickly?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-pulse-71-the-tech-behind-stripes&#34;&gt;The Pulse #71: The Tech Behind Stripe’s Realtime Cyber Monday Dashboard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://every.to/p/how-to-build-a-better-social-network&#34;&gt;How to Build a Better Social Network&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://every.to/p/how-to-mourn-omegle&#34;&gt;How to Mourn Omegle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-pulse-74&#34;&gt;The Pulse #74: Adobe Can’t buy Figma: the Impact of this on the Tech Industry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lennysnewsletter.com/p/first-principles-thinking&#34;&gt;First-principles thinking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://every.to/p/why-you-should-build-in-deep-tech&#34;&gt;Why You Should Build in Deep Tech&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://governance.substack.com/p/this-week-in-governance-december-bf0&#34;&gt;This Week in Governance - December 14: Distributed Robustness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Podcast&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/episode/0hZnn7rEmWTxLaB4l5xWXg?si=a69a959254224f43&#34;&gt;Control Pain and Heal Faster with your Brain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/episode/0xTNW1QaM50FFiSVlcPLDP?si=b69a356827c44bf0&#34;&gt;Sam Altman Back at OpenAI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/episode/4i4lKsKevNSGEUnuu7Jzn6?si=31f55ec92b644183&#34;&gt;Satya Nadella on OpenAI Debacle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2BfMuHDfGJI&#34;&gt;Elon Musk Dealbook Summit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://zeroknowledge.fm/302-2/&#34;&gt;Episode 302: ZK for web2 interop with zkLogin &amp;amp; ZK Email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.latent.space/p/sourcegraph&#34;&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Normsky&amp;rdquo; architecture for AI coding agents — with Beyang Liu + Steve Yegge of SourceGraph&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.latent.space/p/suhail-doshi&#34;&gt;The AI-First Graphics Editor - with Suhail Doshi of Playground AI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://zeroknowledge.fm/304-2/&#34;&gt;Episode 304: Exploring FRI, LogUp and using M31 for STARKs with Ulrich Haböck&lt;/a&gt; (Did not get a lot of this one, need to listen and decode this alteast three times)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://zeroknowledge.fm/305-2/&#34;&gt;Episode 305: ZK Rewind: A Look Back at 2023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Book&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://fs.blog/clear/&#34;&gt;Clear Thinking by Shane Parrish&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/4069.Man_s_Search_for_Meaning&#34;&gt;Man’s Search for Meaning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/19384965-dilbert-2-0?ref=nav_sb_ss_1_15&#34;&gt;Dilbert 2.0: The Dot-Com Bubble, 1998-2000&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Truth Seekers Win</title>
    <link>/posts/truth-seekers-win/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/truth-seekers-win/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;In a World full of influencers, and wannabe influencers begging for people’s attention (nothing wrong with that), I was questioning myself who wins in the long run. I am defining winning as companies that not only survive, but thrive for over atleast 5 - 10 decades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on my conversation with multiple friends, I’ve observed that most early stage company founders’, employees’ fall into the trap of celebrating milestones that do not contribute to revenue, or creating shareholder’s value. Especially for VC funded companies, a company needs to grow fast to give an exit to its early backers. It surprises me when people in the driving seat of the company push for reaching or celebrating milestones that have nothing to do with revenue growth. I do not know of any business that has survived over a decade and has not earned a substantial market share and revenue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure, small wins are necessary to be celebrated to keep the momentum going. But sometimes, continuous focus on pushing for smaller milestones without facing the reality of growing revenue just delays the inevitable. Narratives also play a big part in it. They possess the power to change the reality in the listener’s mind only for them to realise it later that the narrative did not play out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, you may hold the point of view and believe that Sun revolves around the Earth or gravity does not exist. But when you have to bet your life on it based on a scientific experiment, you’ll die. Not testing your beliefs only keeps you delusional. The same goes for the fate of one’s company. Not focussing on metrics that lead to or increase the odds of increasing shareholder’s value will lead to the death of the company. No question about that. Sometimes, the runway in your company’s bank is the fuel that powers your delusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Founders who are aware of this truth have a strong chance of building a decade old company.&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Learnings from 2023</title>
    <link>/posts/learnings-from-2023/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/learnings-from-2023/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;2023 has been a relatively good year for me as compared to 2022. As we step into 2024, I want to share some of the most impactful lessons I’ve learned, some of which date back even further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.&lt;strong&gt;Remove things as much as you can aka &lt;em&gt;focus is critical for success&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I dabbled in too many things before 2023 with a generalist mindset and couldn’t really find time to double down on what is needed from me at a particular time or what I want from myself. In 2023, I cut down a lot of things even when I wanted to do them badly to prioritise top level company and personal goals. Till date, this has been one of my best decisions. The takeaway? Directly pursue what you genuinely want, not just what others suggest. The direct route is often the fastest route. Focus on that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.&lt;strong&gt;Understand Your Limits&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building on my first point, I’ve realized that taking on everything, even if it seems possible, isn’t always the best option. I have taken multiple roles and positions in our company and have grinded everyday for three years to learn and deliver as much as I can. But as the company has started to scale and add new product lines, I have decided to build an expertise in one key area (growth) and do it well. That area can be what the company wants from you at that moment, but restricting it to just one or max two is the best for you and the company. Trust me! Do not spread yourselves too thin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3.&lt;strong&gt;Early stage is way different than mid or late stage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was the first employee at CreatorOS (parent company of Questbook and Reclaim). I had joined Questbook after working with the founders of mid to large stage companies at Kalaari and in the product team at Blinkit, a couple of years before Blinkit’s got acquired to Zomato. The key lesson I learned is the importance of prioritizing emotional and insight-driven approach over rigid processes, especially in early stages. Very few people are trained in emotion first/insight first thinking. Most of us think about setting up analytics, writing events, writing detailed docs even before thinking through how the user would feel. When was the last time you discussed your customer’s emotions in a professional setup? Humans are emotional beings including your customers. They don’t care about funnels, CTAs, retention. If they feel your product adds value to their life at a given price point, they’ll pay. Finding and validating this value and price is a significant jump. Rest is just optimisation. Avoid the temptation for perfection in the initial stages to sound intelligent. Conserve energy on the most important stuff!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4.&lt;strong&gt;You can add a lot of value to an early stage company as a generalist&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of my friends who are MBAs, non tech undergrads want to get into tech, but do not know how to. Not denying that PMing is (not sure about now) the hottest job, but getting yourself into a very early stage startup is the best thing that you can do to yourself. The caveat being betting on the right people. It will be atleast a two - five year journey and unless you feel that you are surrounded by people who will transform your startup into a rocket ship, don’t join. Even the smartest VCs do not know what’s in store. Coming back to the point. I am reminded by Brian Balfour’s presentation in which he says that the best way to build influence and create impact inside an organisation i&lt;strong&gt;s to do things no one else is willing to do. Everyone wants the new shiny project.&lt;/strong&gt; If you want to go deeper and grow fast, take the opposite route. Take projects from 5% - 80% consistently. Then hire someone to replace yourself. &lt;strong&gt;A CEO needs someone who can do this job day in and day out for him/her to focus on the next big bet. Being that person can be really rewarding.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To quote Dan Romero while he was reflecting back on his days at Coinbase “You want to be a weapon that your CEO can point at a problem and you get it done. I tried being as high leverage as possible and believed no work was “beneath me””&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5.&lt;strong&gt;Embrace change and accept reality&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, leading 2-3 KPIs at the same time is hard. I signed up for it the day I decided to be the employee #1. But it is okay to accept that there are people who can do your job better than you can once the strong foundations have been laid out. You need to set your ego aside and make yourself less important in order for the experienced folks to do their job well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a company shareholder, startup’s success should come first, not your personal ego. As things scale fast and start to get more technical, the company needs people who are experts. People who have been there done that! But these people don’t want to come in and work for someone just because that person was early. They know their game. Get them onboard and GTFO. Founders and CEO breed is really good at this art. Acceptance is hard!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A related instance that comes to my mind is my post JEE depression. I had gone to Kota for preparing for JEE and had really high expectations from myself. While I could not make it, my BITSAT score was decent and I could’ve got the non coveted disciplines at the Pilani campus (Finance, IS or one of the dual degrees). I had absolutely zero idea about which discipline to choose at that time and based on the advice of my uncle who believed that one should opt in for core branches such as Mechanical or Chemical, I ended up choosing Chemical at the Goa campus despite having the deserved opportunity to get better disciplines from an outcome perspective at all three campuses. For the longest time, I could not make peace with this fact. I had studied really hard for two years and squandered a good opportunity to start the race as an equal because of lack of awareness and listening to my uncle’s advice. I was even mocked by my to be peers on the registration day for my choice when I told them my score . They recommended me to see if there’s away to change things. Of course, there wasn’t unless I scored a really high CGA in my first year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I vividly recall a train journey where an aunty asked about my campus. After revealing I was at BITS, her reaction only added to my frustration. Since that day, I was really annoyed at such people who asked this question. People often jumped to conclusions about my abilities, IQ score, family upbringing (yes someone called that out too) without knowing my background or score/story. At times, I would give random, evasive responses about my campus (including Dubai). It’s interesting how some folks are always looking for some sort of institutional reputation or authority to judge the other person. Some can go to any extreme to know it. Everytime I introduce myself, or write/Tweet, I put myself out there. But I chose not to for those who I feel have the intention to constantly compare and show that they belong to a superior category. I’ve worked as a Consultant, PM, VC, PM, Growth and Sales exec (soon to be a developer) and it boggles my mind that people still actively look for institutional validation. I’m not a fan of basing one’s worth on one’s institutional associations. Anonymous individuals produce high quality work and make millions of dollars. Everyone deserves an equaly opportunity on internet. Gatekeepers should look for an alternate career option. Nonetheless, I have to terms with my decision and no longer feel hesitant discussing it. Although technically, BITS doesn’t specify the campus name on the degree. Reality has been a hard pill to swalow. I’ve learned to embrace my journey and the choices I have made and presented by life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6.&lt;strong&gt;No zero days&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest mistake that I made during my college days was to think that I had made it. Only to realise it later that one never does. Call it lack of awareness or the opposite of growth mindset, since my days at Kalaari, I have made it a point to have zero zero days. Be it a rainy day, a day when I’m unwell, or a holiday, I make it a point to work on my personal goals created for myself by myself. Our education system handicaps our ability to think independently. Every syllabus, book, lecture slide is handed to us on a platter year after year. The closest analogy being that of a box on a conveyor belt that gets shipped to the industry around the age of 22. Kids do not know that they can make their own goals too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7.&lt;strong&gt;Think through why you need a lot of money&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chasing a lot of money doesn’t come naturally to me. Not denying that money is important, but why is different for all of us. Some of us want to go on multiple vacations, retire, buy expensive stuff. Without answering the why, you’ll keep mimicking others and be stuck with how. To me, money gives me the opportunity to own my time, work on the problems that I want to with the people who I want to work alongside with. It gives you the freedom to take on problems you enjoy working on and most importantly, multiple shots at failure. One needs that to be successful in whatever domain they are working in. There are a lot of smart people out there. But chose wisely who do you want to work with. Money gives you that choice!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8.&lt;strong&gt;Health is as important as others tell you&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Till I was 28, I used to consume Redbull, coffee like water. This is an image from my room in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
    src=&#34;https://axiomatic-diver-1c4.notion.site/image/https%3A%2F%2Fi.ibb.co%2FbznXnvD%2FIMG-1878.jpg?table=block&amp;amp;id=e725c51c-7043-4bbf-ab00-4b1ce728f894&amp;amp;spaceId=c6a62786-f859-45a8-8419-fae4370cf6f4&amp;amp;width=2000&amp;amp;userId=&amp;amp;cache=v2&#34; 
    alt=&#34;Image&#34; 
     /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But as I’ve gotten older, I’ve realised that I produce high quality work when I feel the best physically. One of my friends at Kalaari had told me that while I may not see the fatigue symptoms back then, I will see them later on and change my habits. I have no shame in accepting that he was right and that 2022 was the worst year for me physically. I had neck aches, back aches, head aches almost everyday for three months and kept ignoring them. It was only when the pain become really severe and when I was diagnosed as borderline pre-diabetic that I started hitting the gym and restarted playing football. This was again, one of the best decisions of 2023. I was definitely quite late to the workout party, but getting up early and hitting the gym is probably the best thing you can do to yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9.&lt;strong&gt;Ignore most advices&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have almost stopped reading all self help books and blogs as they are of no help to me in my day to day life. Everyone’s life is unique and telling people to do 10 things that will solve every life problem is a futile attempt. Hence, I have started adding “for me” at the end of each sentence and then put a filter of my current life situation to the merit of the advice/content. If it does not add any value which in most cases it does not, I am quick to turn the page without procrastinating much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note : I will keep adding additional pointers to this post.&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Starting up vs Formal Degree</title>
    <link>/posts/starting-up-vs-formal-degree/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/starting-up-vs-formal-degree/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;Recently, I had this discussion with a friend that brought to light the old age dilemma: the choice between pursuing a college degree, and the path of entrepreneurship or joining an early-stage startup. Traditionally, society, &lt;strong&gt;including my own family&lt;/strong&gt;, has leaned heavily towards academic glory, valuing the potential for increased earnings and the prestige it brings. In contrast, the entrepreneurial route, while riskier and with uncertain success rates, offers great learning opportunities and a chance to go deep into the real-world challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The odds of success increase when an entrepreneur targets a niche or a large &lt;strong&gt;growing&lt;/strong&gt; industry. In my experience, I would always prefer collaborating with someone who has hands-on experience in creating a product that resonates with customers within an industry, over someone who possesses theoretical knowledge gained through academic courses or degrees. Gaining deep industry insights is challenging, often not achievable without direct customer interaction and understanding their pain. An entrepreneur invests years in this process, unlike a university student whose focus is often on achieving a high GPA and creating a shiny CV (nothing bad about it).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past decade, the mindset in India has shifted remarkably. Entrepreneurship is now celebrated, partly thanks to popular shows like &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shark_Tank_India&#34;&gt;Shark Tank India&lt;/a&gt;. My own beliefs have undergone significant change through my experience working in different startups. I doubt such a drastic change in perspective would have been possible had I been enrolled in a Master’s program. I am not debating the fact that someone’s entrepreneurial journey can also start post-college degree. What I am trying to evaluate are two different options at a given time with industry understanding, learning as the core metrics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite this evolving mindset, there’s still a long journey ahead . In my case, if the opportunity arises again to work on a challenging problem with a good team in the future, I would seize it without any hesitation.&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>What I Read in November</title>
    <link>/posts/what-i-read-in-november/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/what-i-read-in-november/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;h3 id=&#34;read&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#read&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg class=&#34;icon&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; focusable=&#34;false&#34; height=&#34;16&#34; version=&#34;1.1&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 16 16&#34; width=&#34;16&#34;&gt;
            &lt;path fill-rule=&#34;evenodd&#34;
                d=&#34;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&#34;&gt;
            &lt;/path&gt;
        &lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Read&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lennysnewsletter.com/p/lessons-from-going-freemium-a-decision&#34;&gt;Lessons from going freemium: a decision that broke our business&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/inside-openai-how-does-chatgpt-ship&#34;&gt;Inside OpenAI: How does ChatGPT Ship So Quickly?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-pulse-71-the-tech-behind-stripes&#34;&gt;The Pulse #71: The Tech Behind Stripe’s Realtime Cyber Monday Dashboard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://every.to/p/how-to-build-a-better-social-network&#34;&gt;How to Build a Better Social Network&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://every.to/p/how-to-mourn-omegle&#34;&gt;How to Mourn Omegle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;podcast&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#podcast&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg class=&#34;icon&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; focusable=&#34;false&#34; height=&#34;16&#34; version=&#34;1.1&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 16 16&#34; width=&#34;16&#34;&gt;
            &lt;path fill-rule=&#34;evenodd&#34;
                d=&#34;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&#34;&gt;
            &lt;/path&gt;
        &lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Podcast&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/episode/0hZnn7rEmWTxLaB4l5xWXg?si=a69a959254224f43&#34;&gt;Control Pain and Heal Faster with your Brain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/episode/0xTNW1QaM50FFiSVlcPLDP?si=b69a356827c44bf0&#34;&gt;Sam Altman Back at OpenAI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/episode/4i4lKsKevNSGEUnuu7Jzn6?si=31f55ec92b644183&#34;&gt;Satya Nadella on OpenAI Debacle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2BfMuHDfGJI&#34;&gt;Elon Musk Dealbook Summit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;book&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#book&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg class=&#34;icon&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; focusable=&#34;false&#34; height=&#34;16&#34; version=&#34;1.1&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 16 16&#34; width=&#34;16&#34;&gt;
            &lt;path fill-rule=&#34;evenodd&#34;
                d=&#34;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&#34;&gt;
            &lt;/path&gt;
        &lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Book&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://fs.blog/clear/&#34;&gt;Clear Thinking by Shane Parrish&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>What I Read in October</title>
    <link>/posts/what-i-read-in-october/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/what-i-read-in-october/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/stacked-diffs&#34;&gt;Stacked Diffs (and why you should know about them)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lennysnewsletter.com/p/how-to-build-a-killer-sales-pitch&#34;&gt;How to build a killer sales pitch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lennysnewsletter.com/p/how-to-validate-your-b2b-startup?utm_source=%2Fsearch%2Fb2b&amp;amp;utm_medium=reader2&#34;&gt;How to validate your B2B startup idea&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://every.to/no-small-plans/the-power-of-designing-for-a-single-user&#34;&gt;The Power of Designing for a Single User&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://governance.substack.com/p/this-week-in-governance-october-5&#34;&gt;This Week in Governance - October 5: Councils, Gardeners, and Robots&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://governance.substack.com/p/this-week-in-governance-october-12&#34;&gt;This Week in Governance - October 12: Grants, Loans, and Longevity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://every.to/superorganizers/how-to-make-yourself-into-a-learning-machine&#34;&gt;How to Make Yourself Into a Learning Machine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lennysnewsletter.com/p/how-to-win-your-first-10-b2b-customers&#34;&gt;How to win and find your first 10 B2B Customers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/manu&#34;&gt;The Man Behind the Big Tech Comics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gov.optimism.io/t/draft-proposed-grants-council-charter-season-5/6942&#34;&gt;DRAFT: Proposed Grants Council Charter - Season 5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>I&#39;ve Started Shipping Code</title>
    <link>/posts/ive-started-shipping-code/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/ive-started-shipping-code/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;h3 id=&#34;ive-started-shipping-codeoctober-2-2023-2-minutes-projectshttpswwwruchilsharmacomcategoriesprojects&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#ive-started-shipping-codeoctober-2-2023-2-minutes-projectshttpswwwruchilsharmacomcategoriesprojects&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg class=&#34;icon&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34; focusable=&#34;false&#34; height=&#34;16&#34; version=&#34;1.1&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 16 16&#34; width=&#34;16&#34;&gt;
            &lt;path fill-rule=&#34;evenodd&#34;
                d=&#34;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&#34;&gt;
            &lt;/path&gt;
        &lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve started shipping code&lt;/strong&gt;October 2, 2023 | 2 minutes | &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ruchilsharma.com/categories/projects&#34;&gt;Projects&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not too long ago, I used to introduce myself as someone who didn’t write code. Well, things have changed! With the rise of AI, especially since the introduction of ChatGPT, I am absolutely amazed by the capabilities of AI in assisting me with coding and building projects. I had a strong desire to create my own website after successfully launching one using Jekyll in 2020, but I was struggling with customizing it to my liking. Scouring through endless Google search results was not only time-consuming but also incredibly frustrating. This led me to postpone working on my blog post, repeatedly putting it off until I had enough time to dedicate to it. But with the advent of ChatGPT, I came to a realization – I didn’t need more time; I simply needed to ask questions, and it would provide me with the precise answers I required to customize my blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since then, I’ve managed to complete two projects with the assistance of GPT, all while ensuring that I comprehend and can personally understand every code line of my projects. The first project I built this year was this very blog post, which demanded significant adjustments and customizations – tasks that would have taken me an incredibly long time in a world without GPT. Recently, I also successfully launched another application: a comprehensive quiz app built using JavaScript, HTML, and CSS. This app performs several functions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It displays a list of questions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It accepts user responses as input.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It verifies whether the answers provided are correct.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It calculates and displays the final quiz score.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It showcases the high scores achieved by various attempts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It provides an option to reset the quiz.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can play around with the app &lt;a href=&#34;https://firstquizproject.vercel.app/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inspired by the journey of &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/mckaywrigley&#34;&gt;Mckay Wrigley&lt;/a&gt;, who began coding just four years ago and managed to produce some of the most talked-about apps on Twitter consistently, I have now started on a path to ship a few projects myself. To keep track of all the projects I ship, you can visit the “Projects” section on my blog under the categories section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy shipping!&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>What I Read in September</title>
    <link>/posts/what-i-read-in-september/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/what-i-read-in-september/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hivemind.vc/nostr/&#34;&gt;Why I’m Betting Big on Nostr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-pulse-63&#34;&gt;The Pulse #63: Working at a Startup vs in Big Tech&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://forum.arbitrum.foundation/t/arbitrums-short-term-incentive-program-arbitrum-improvement-proposal/16131/1&#34;&gt;Arbitrum’s Short-Term Incentive Program&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://every.to/napkin-math/the-double-bind-theory-or-why-sensationalism-unfortunately-works&#34;&gt;The Double Bind Theory—Or Why Sensationalism Works&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lennysnewsletter.com/p/how-to-identify-your-ideal-customer&#34;&gt;How the most successful B2B startups came up with their original idea&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Books&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.in/Alchemist-Paulo-Coelho/dp/8172234988&#34;&gt;The Alchemist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Videos&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Dg-rKXi9XYg&#34;&gt;AI SAFETY PANEL | Elon Musk, Max Tegmark, Greg Brockman, Benjamin Netanyahu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MVYrJJNdrEg&#34;&gt;Mark Zuckerberg: First Interview in the Metaverse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ykY69lSpDdo&#34;&gt;Ray Kurzweil: Singularity, Superintelligence, and Immortality&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>What I Read in August</title>
    <link>/posts/what-i-read-in-august/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/what-i-read-in-august/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-pulse-60-tech-ipos-are-back&#34;&gt;The Pulse #60: Tech IPOs are back!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-pulse-58-zoom-an-rto-turning&#34;&gt;The Pulse #58: Zoom; An RTO Turning Point?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://every.to/chain-of-thought/how-to-develop-your-taste-for-new-technologies&#34;&gt;How to Develop Your Taste for New Technologies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://digitalnative.substack.com/p/follow-the-money-categories-of-consumer?utm_source=www.homescreen.news&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_campaign=meta-s-fresh-ai-heat&#34;&gt;Follow the Money: Categories of Consumer Spend&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lennysnewsletter.com/p/how-to-identify-your-ideal-customer&#34;&gt;How to identify your ideal customer profile (ICP)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Books&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.in/Obviously-Awesome-Product-Positioning-Customers/dp/1999023005&#34;&gt;Obviously Awesome: How to Nail Product Positioning so Customers Get It, Buy It, Love It&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.in/Cant-Hurt-Me-Master-Your/dp/1544512287&#34;&gt;Can’t Hurt Me: Master Your Mind and Defy the Odds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Videos&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0oEqVIPd008&#34;&gt;Design and make money with Vision Pro! | Spatial Design EP 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=K5kZPb8faEs&amp;amp;t=2534s&#34;&gt;Critiquing Startup Mobile Apps with Glide CEO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5tSTk1083VY&#34;&gt;Joe Rogan Experience - David Goggins&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Why I was too early to Shark Tank?</title>
    <link>/posts/why-i-was-too-early-to-shark-tank/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/why-i-was-too-early-to-shark-tank/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;In my final year of college, a friend recommended Shark Tank US to me, and from the moment I watched the first episode, I was completely hooked. I binge-watched the first 5 seasons that year and quickly caught up on the remaining ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During my final year internship in Mumbai, I couldn’t help but wonder why there wasn’t something like Shark Tank in India. With a population of over a billion, I was convinced that it could be a huge success. I’ve always been passionate about celebrating entrepreneurs and shifting the spotlight away from Bollywood stars. Visuals of Indian entrepreneurs pitching their ideas to Lakshmi Mittal kept me up at night. Determined to take action, I approached one of the popular Indian TV series directors via Facebook DM, and to my surprise, he responded after a few follow-ups. He invited us (my room mate joined me) to his flat in Mumbai, where I presented my idea of launching Shark Tank in India. My roommate also saw the potential and joined me. Looking back, our Prezi presentation was far from perfect, but we went ahead and pitched the idea to our potential business partner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After our pitch, he expressed concerns about the cost, as it seemed like a significant investment. Back in 2015, startup success stories were rare in India, and the lack of media coverage for startups made the journey even more daunting. As 21-year-olds, his doubts were discouraging, but the pressure of securing a job after college weighed heavily on us. So, for the time being, we put the idea on hold and got absorbed in our day-to-day struggles. The fate of another similar show, &lt;a href=&#34;https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/magazines/panache/the-vault-will-give-budding-entrepreneurs-major-motivation-jatin-goel/articleshow/54730010.cms?from=mdr&#34;&gt;The Vault&lt;/a&gt;, made me doubt whether Shark Tank would work in India, a country where safety often takes precedence over taking risks. After going through multiple episodes of The Vault on Youtube, I let go of the concept, hoping that someone else might pick it up someday. Little did I know that Sony would be the one to bring it to life. Interestingly, the director I had reached out to in 2015 also produced shows for Sony, and their success with Shark Tank India is now history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come next time, I hope it’ll be me and not another Sony.&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>What I Read in June and July</title>
    <link>/posts/what-i-read-in-june-and-july/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/what-i-read-in-june-and-july/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.decentralised.co/p/after-the-merge&#34;&gt;After The Merge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eugenewei.com/blog/2023/7/6/how-to-blow-up-a-timeline&#34;&gt;How to blow up a timeline&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.paulgraham.com/greatwork.html&#34;&gt;How to do great work&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gitcoin.co/blog/successful-grants-programs-in-web3-history&#34;&gt;Successful grants program in Web 3 history&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://stack.optimism.io/&#34;&gt;OP Stack Docs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.swyx.io/create-luck/&#34;&gt;How to create luck&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.matthewball.vc/all/bigtechbiggestbets&#34;&gt;Big Tech Biggest Bets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.notion.so/Blog-d52017d7b1d04567955c89605e7e88d1?pvs=21&#34;&gt;Fundraising Advice&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I religiously read and listen to Stratechery, The Daily Gwei, The Pragmatic Engineer, The Chopping Block Podcast, Lenny’s Newsletter, and Every on a daily/weekly basis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Podcast and Books&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sharptech.fm/member/episode/the-threads-episode-how-we-got-here-meta-obstacles-and-advantages-everyone-hates-twitter-and-uses-it-every-day&#34;&gt;The Threads Episode: How We Got Here, Meta Obstacles and Advantages, Everyone Hates Twitter (And Uses It Every Day)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://growth.eladgil.com/&#34;&gt;High Growth Handbook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.in/Never-Split-Difference-Negotiating-Depended/dp/0062407805&#34;&gt;Never Split The Difference&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Why Talented Tech Players Need to Stay in the Game</title>
    <link>/posts/why-talented-tech-players-need-to-stay-in-the-gamejune-11-2023-2-minutes-copy-2/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/why-talented-tech-players-need-to-stay-in-the-gamejune-11-2023-2-minutes-copy-2/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;Every week, big tech and startups produce something remarkable that takes everyone by surprise. These remarkable advancements quickly become the household talks and spark discussions among tech pundits who are eager to delve into the intricacies of these technologies and launches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in 2006, when I was in 6th grade, I loved watching &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/b007t9y1&#34;&gt;Match of The Day&lt;/a&gt;, a show where all football pundits got together and talked about managerial decisions, controversial moments in the game, and transfers. It’s fascinating to observe a similar phenomenon emerging within the realm of Big Tech and startups, albeit with different players and pundits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team Captain —&amp;gt; Founders and CEOs, who lead the team from the front&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Players and Subs —&amp;gt; Senior Leaders along with other employees and the players, actively contributing to the game&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Football Pundits —&amp;gt; Tech Pundits, offering expert analysis and insights.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coaches and Team Captains&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
    src=&#34;https://axiomatic-diver-1c4.notion.site/image/https%3A%2F%2Fimg.etimg.com%2Fthumb%2Fmsid-80891859%2Cwidth-650%2Cheight-488%2Cimgsize-83476%2C%2Cresizemode-75%2Fselena-gomez-big-tech.jpg?table=block&amp;amp;id=8507e0c3-1558-4104-a2c1-efdc4efad47e&amp;amp;spaceId=c6a62786-f859-45a8-8419-fae4370cf6f4&amp;amp;width=2000&amp;amp;userId=&amp;amp;cache=v2&#34; 
    alt=&#34;image&#34; 
     /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Team Players (minus the founders)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
    src=&#34;https://axiomatic-diver-1c4.notion.site/image/https%3A%2F%2Fphotos5.appleinsider.com%2Fgallery%2Fproduct_pages%2F299-hero.jpg%3F%3D1686548746?table=block&amp;amp;id=0ebb33b5-3a32-4016-b68d-cdcd20770ee5&amp;amp;spaceId=c6a62786-f859-45a8-8419-fae4370cf6f4&amp;amp;width=2000&amp;amp;userId=&amp;amp;cache=v2&#34; 
    alt=&#34;image&#34; 
     /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pundits&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
    src=&#34;https://axiomatic-diver-1c4.notion.site/image/https%3A%2F%2Fcompote.slate.com%2Fimages%2Fc79e8c73-708d-4f66-894d-0d68a1aca85f.jpeg%3Fcrop%3D1560%252C1040%252Cx0%252Cy0%26width%3D840?table=block&amp;amp;id=8626cf18-b303-489a-a437-667aa85a22b8&amp;amp;spaceId=c6a62786-f859-45a8-8419-fae4370cf6f4&amp;amp;width=2000&amp;amp;userId=&amp;amp;cache=v2&#34; 
    alt=&#34;image&#34; 
     /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it is great to see technology ecosystem transforming itself into a entertainment and sporting arena, true innovation happens when exceptional players remain actively involved on the field. It is crucial that these exceptional individuals resist the temptation to retire early and instead take on new challenges, creating their own teams and scouting for talented players to nurture and mentor. It is through the efforts of these great players that the boundaries of innovation are pushed. It would be a shame if these young talented players simply observe the game from the sidelines, relinquishing their potential to contribute and hunting for little heart shaped likes.&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>What I Read in May</title>
    <link>/posts/what-i-read-in-may/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/what-i-read-in-may/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://messari.io/report/state-of-dao-funding&#34;&gt;State of DAO Funding&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://research.lido.fi/t/ldo-steth-dual-governance/2382&#34;&gt;LIDO Dual Governance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://forum.makerdao.com/t/the-5-phases-of-endgame/20830&#34;&gt;5 Phases of End Game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.pragmaticengineer.com/an-educational-side-project/&#34;&gt;An Education Side Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scaling solutions on &lt;a href=&#34;http://ethereum.org/&#34;&gt;Ethereum.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://stonecoldpat.substack.com/p/how-proof-of-stake-ethereum-works&#34;&gt;Ethereum PoS Series&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://investors.spotify.com/financials/default.aspx&#34;&gt;Spotify Financial Reports&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pyo50QGmH_s&#34;&gt;Shreyas Doshi’s Product Sense Workshop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/nathanbarry/status/1659566137179537408?s=20&#34;&gt;Scaling to $100k MRR by Nathan Barry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.in/Banker-Poor-Micro-Lending-Against-Poverty/dp/1586481983&#34;&gt;Book - Banker to the Poor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://stevejobsarchive.com/book&#34;&gt;Book - Make Something Wonderful&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>What’s wrong with voting only decision making in DAO&#39;s</title>
    <link>/posts/whats-wrong-with-voting-only-decision-making-in-daos/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/whats-wrong-with-voting-only-decision-making-in-daos/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;Grant programs are one of the best ways to attract high-quality contributors to your ecosystem. There’s no denying their potential impact. However, many ecosystems fail to realize that if not implemented well, these programs can lead to the loss of key contributors. In an attention scare World, where abundant opportunities exist, it is crucial for ecosystems to provide the best experience in order to attract and retain high-quality contributors. I’ve personally faced the following problems as a DAO contributor:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lack of Accountability&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently submitted a grant proposal to a well-known ecosystem, but unfortunately, it was turned down. While I fully respect the community’s decision, I took the initiative to reach out to the all the members, especially those who voted against the proposal, seeking their valuable thoughts and feedback. However, it was discouraging to read their response considering the amount of time a proposer has to spend while writing the proposal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This might be something that could be taken into account for the future but currently there is no mechanism in this DAO for feedback like that”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every voter in the DAO possesses the power to support or reject a proposal, but with that power comes the responsibility of being accountable for their decisions. It is essential for every voter and delegate in the DAO to publicly declare their mission statement and provide a rationale for each of their votes on proposals. This transparency would empower community members to assess whether they should continue delegating their votes or consider undelagating them. Flipside Crypto’s initiative to mention rationale on each vote is highly commendable. 👏&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not to brag 🙈, we at Questbook, have also advocated for reviewers to setup their domain specific evaluation rubrics in order to give actionable feedback to proposers and help them incorporate their feedback in a transparent manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;The White House has announced VP &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/KamalaHarris?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@KamalaHarris&lt;/a&gt; as the AI czar 📢&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/DavidSacks?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@DavidSacks&lt;/a&gt; breaks down the issues we face with AI and the implications of Harris’ appointment to address these concerns on &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/theallinpod?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@theallinpod&lt;/a&gt; 👇 &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/4xdAjreMUK&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/4xdAjreMUK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; ALL-IN TOK (@all_in_tok) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/all_in_tok/status/1660676897510916099?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;May 22, 2023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Lack of Expertise&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another crucial aspect for DAO’s is to identify or group delegates into their area of expertise. It is unrealistic to assume that every delegate possesses expertise across all focus areas relevant to ecosystem’s growth. Discussing and evaluating proposals outside of one’s area of expertise can be challenging and inefficient, potentially resulting in missed opportunities. Delegating responsibilities/Grouping delegates based on their expertise fixes this. 🚀&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, most reputed folks do not advocate for Kamala Harris as the AI czar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current state of DAO voting brings to mind a well-known quote, which I’ve modified below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me hold the bags of a nation, and I care not who writes its proposals.&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Deep Dives - Maker DAO</title>
    <link>/posts/deep-dives---maker-dao-copy/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/deep-dives---maker-dao-copy/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dabblish.substack.com/p/deep-dives-maker-dao&#34;&gt;Deep Dives - Maker DAO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Deep Dives - Spotify</title>
    <link>/posts/deep-dives---spotify/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/deep-dives---spotify/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dabblish.substack.com/p/turn-up-the-music-spotifys-teardown&#34;&gt;Deep Dives - Spotify&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Balaji is right, but he may lose the bet</title>
    <link>/posts/balaji-is-right-but-he-may-lose-the-bet/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/balaji-is-right-but-he-may-lose-the-bet/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;I will take that bet.&lt;br&gt;You buy 1 BTC.&lt;br&gt;I will send $1M USD.&lt;br&gt;This is ~40:1 odds as 1 BTC is worth ~$26k.&lt;br&gt;The term is 90 days.&lt;br&gt;All we need is a mutually agreed custodian who will still be there to settle this in the event of digital dollar devaluation.&lt;br&gt;If someone knows how to do this… &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/hhPr522PQu&#34;&gt;https://t.co/hhPr522PQu&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/6Aav9KeJpe&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/6Aav9KeJpe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Balaji (@balajis) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/balajis/status/1636797265317867520?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;March 17, 2023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
 &lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
 

&lt;p&gt;Having reviewed this tweet’s contents in detail, I find Balaji’s argument about inflation being a significant threat to the American economy quite persuasive. However, I remain unconvinced that the average citizien has the time to go into these complex details and subsequently exit to Bitcoin. The majority of people will likely accept the Federal Reserve’s explanation, which will be disseminated through various channels, and will continue to invest their money in the fiat system. Although the average American may have lost faith in the Fed, they are yet to reach the point of taking their hard-earned dollars out of the fiat system. They may have exited their trust, they will not exit thier $$’s right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To quote Jean-Claude Juncker: “When it becomes serious, you have to lie”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think most people will believe that lie for a little longer.&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Revamping My Blog Post Theme</title>
    <link>/posts/revamping-my-blog-post-theme-copy/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/revamping-my-blog-post-theme-copy/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;I am currently working on migrating and enhancing my blog’s theme and will not be posting for sometime. I intent to start posting again next year and port all the previous posts as soon as the new theme design and migration is done. Till then, you can reach out to me on Twitter(pinned above) DM. Have a great year ahead! 🤝&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Personal OKRs 2022</title>
    <link>/posts/personal-okrs-2022/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/personal-okrs-2022/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://axiomatic-diver-1c4.notion.site/6506f40d988e426590ee8abe5ae12bea?v=e5de44c28ea540f6a45c98fea43a80e3&#34;&gt;Personal OKRs 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>The Magic of Airdrops : Earn While Your Learn</title>
    <link>/posts/the-magic-of-airdrops--earn-while-your-learn/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/the-magic-of-airdrops--earn-while-your-learn/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;Airdrops, in my opinion, are the fastest way to educate users about your product and get user adoption. For me, the starting point was ENS. Seeing my close friends earning ~ $10k through the ENS airdrop piqued my interest into ENS and that eventually led me to buying my own ENS domain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply put, an airdrop is a distribution of a crypto token or coin, usually for free, to numerous wallet addresses. But it is not as trivial as it sounds. The caveat here is that an airdrop comes with the price. For one to be eligible for receiving an airdrop, one needs to use a protocol and interact with it in a manner prescribed by the protocol. Hence, as a user, you might end up spending at least the gas price in order to be eligible for a token airdrop. As I did not own an ENS domain when ENS announced the airdrop, I was not eligible for the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
    src=&#34;https://axiomatic-diver-1c4.notion.site/image/https%3A%2F%2Fimages.mirror-media.xyz%2Fpublication-images%2FUr8NGD1r88Og_SZdobelO.png%3Fheight%3D926%255cu0026width%3D1164?table=block&amp;amp;id=16423d0e-a249-4c36-b7b4-ea87517a7cbe&amp;amp;spaceId=c6a62786-f859-45a8-8419-fae4370cf6f4&amp;amp;width=2000&amp;amp;userId=&amp;amp;cache=v2&#34; 
    alt=&#34;image&#34; 
     /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what I saw when I tried connecting my wallet to earn the airdrop This is what I saw when I tried connecting my wallet to earn the airdrop While I was initially hesitant spending $50 - $100 as gas fees to use a protocol, I am a lot more comfortable doing so now. If you are someone who is full time into crypto and whose primary source of income depends on understanding different crypto ecosystems, gas fees is the cost you pay to educate yourself. After buying my ENS domain, I have used several other protocols and have paid more than a $1,000 (might be insignificant for a lot of you) in gas fees to educate myself about different protocols and ecosystems while prioritising those who have a high likelihood of announcing an airdrop soon. You can find them here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To conclude, if you are someone who is getting started with Web 3.0 and is not undergoing financial crisis, don’t let gas fee be a blocker to use a protocol and understand its nuances. The value that you derive from going deeper into the rabbit hole, ecosystem understanding, friends that you make along the way and the value of the potential airdrops far outweighs the amount that you will spend as gas fees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a side-note, I strongly believe that till the point L2 scaling solutions are not widely adopted, all Web 3 companies that require their employees/community members to have a deep understanding of the Web 3.0 ecosystem should set aside funds dedicated towards protocols/Dapps usage and gas fees. This can be a great differentiator and incentive to lure talented folks into your ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Identify Your Echochamber</title>
    <link>/posts/identify-your-echochamber/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/identify-your-echochamber/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;After 4 years, I have started using Social Media platforms again. While I had no difficulties posting (except stories on Instagram), there are certain observations and patterns that I have started to come across different social media platforms. Detailing them out here :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.&lt;strong&gt;Twitter&lt;/strong&gt; Tagline from a user&amp;rsquo;s perspective : I am smart and &amp;ldquo;intellectual&amp;rdquo; as well. Please koi
meri bhi sun lo. From replying on Elon Musk&amp;rsquo;s and Balajis Tweets to posting random threads on why you should
switch to Signal, Twitter is an echo - chamber of wanna be &amp;ldquo;intellectuals&amp;rdquo;. While Twitter does
help one get deep insights into any topic from some of the most credible individuals, it is also
an echo - chamber of people who are &amp;ldquo;faking&amp;rdquo; it till they make it. There&amp;rsquo;s nothing right/wrong in
this. Well, who doesn&amp;rsquo;t like to have a million followers! But what I&amp;rsquo;ll really appreciate is a following built on one&amp;rsquo;s substance, skills and not copy pasted Tweets, or networking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.&lt;strong&gt;Instagram&lt;/strong&gt; Tagline from a user&amp;rsquo;s perspective : I can post, apply filters, travel to Thailand and
Dubai. Mein bhi fake Picasso. Scrolling through some of the posts on Instagram is a sheer delight as it is one of the biggest echo chambers. Same is the case with Facebook. A snapshot of the post. I would appreciate if people can bring some innovation to their replies and not copy/paste &amp;ldquo;great&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;wow&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are the smartest individual and get validated from others all the time, you are doing more harm than good to yourself. It is time to leave the table and join a new one when you stop getting pushback from your inner circle/ community. You are just fooling yourself and hiding your insecurities otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be a philosophical king, one needs to become a king first. So, moving forward, I&amp;rsquo;ll avoid posting generic stuff unless I am really tempted to.&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>So You Want to Form New Habits?</title>
    <link>/posts/so-you-want-to-form-new-habits/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/so-you-want-to-form-new-habits/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;Creating positive habits takes more than just willpower. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen by itself as it is more science than art. It requires constant re-evaluation of where you are spending time, people whom you are spending time with and your environment. Last year, I spent significant amount of time researching this and stumbled upon different books, bootcamps and blog posts that have proven to be really helpful in planning my day and subsequently, my week. This blog post is to detail out my learnings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.in/dp/B07R6VQBSZ/ref=dp-kindle-redirect?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;btkr=1&#34;&gt;1. Tiny Habits by BJ Fogg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prof. B.J. Fogg is the founder of the Behaviour Design Lab at Stanford University and teaches industry
innovators how behaviour really works. Kevin Systrom (founder of Instagram) was one of BJ Fogg’s
students and as in the case with any other product, habit formation is one of the core elements of Instagram (stories being one of them).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to BJ Fogg, any behaviour can be broken down into three elements :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Motivation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prompt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Behaviour = MAP&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Motivation&lt;/strong&gt; :  The least effective strategy to form new habits as one feels highly motivated during the day and less as the day goes by.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ability&lt;/strong&gt;: Make the action so tiny that your ability to do it increases significantly. Want to lose 10 kgs in 3 months? Just visit the gym and come out for the first three days. Want to start your own blog?
Great, open any notepad and start jotting down your thoughts. We overestimate what we can achieve in the short run and underestimate what we can in the long run. Consistency &amp;raquo; Magnitude of Work Done&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prompt&lt;/strong&gt; : This is the easiest to manage among all three. Your environment speaks volumes about how serious you are about getting the job done. Designing the environment that is conducive to successful
completion of a behaviour is often underestimated. A few examples would be setting up the alarm to go for a run, turning off social media notifications (prompt removal) while focussing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
    src=&#34;https://behaviormodel.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Fogg-Behavior-Model.jpg&#34; 
    alt=&#34;image&#34; 
     /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other hacks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Habit Chain : Any of the following factors can act as a friction to form new habits successfully :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Money&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Physical Effort&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mental Effort&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Routine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pinpoint the exact root cause and try to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fear and self - doubt decrease the likelihood of habit formation whereas hope increases the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.in/Atomic-Habits-James-Clear/dp/1847941834/ref=sr_1_2?dchild=1&amp;amp;keywords=atomic+habits&amp;amp;qid=1610539028&amp;amp;sr=8-2&#34;&gt;2. Atomic Habits by James Clear&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make the habit an obvious thing to do&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make it attractive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make it easy (by increasing the ability)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make it satisfying : By enjoying the process and celebrating after the successful completion of the desired behaviour.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
    src=&#34;https://expertprogrammanagement.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Atomic-Habits_-Plateau-of-Latent-Potential.png&#34; 
    alt=&#34;image&#34; 
     /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other Hacks&lt;/strong&gt; :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Batching&lt;/strong&gt; : Club similar habits together to get things done. One example could be listening to podcast while going for a walk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Embracing Boredom&lt;/strong&gt; : It takes a long time to successfully build and sustain new habits, so embrace boredom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Process over Outcomes&lt;/strong&gt; : Focus on completing the habit rather than achieving the goal. It takes a while to realise the power of compounding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Role of friends and family&lt;/strong&gt; : Choose your peers wisely. Peers who will contribute towards the successful change in habits. Everything else is secondary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Change the content of self - talk&lt;/strong&gt; : If you want to read more, do not tell yourself : “I want to read more&amp;quot;; instead say &amp;ldquo;I am a reader”. The key to building lasting habits is focusing on creating a new identity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other resources that you may refer to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.in/Power-Habit-Why-What-Change/dp/1847946240/ref=sr_1_3?crid=3OG16L8DTKU74&amp;amp;dchild=1&amp;amp;keywords=power+of+habit+charles+duhigg&amp;amp;qid=1610533836&amp;amp;sprefix=power+of+habit+Charles+%2Caps%2C289&amp;amp;sr=8-3&#34;&gt;Power of habit by Charles Duhigg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.in/Hooked-How-Build-Habit-Forming-Products/dp/0241184835/ref=sr_1_1?dchild=1&amp;amp;keywords=hooked+nir+eyal&amp;amp;qid=1610533881&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34;&gt;Hooked by Nir Eyal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/show/7BQZHMsYPInemu2GMVSYNH&#34;&gt;Jim Kwik Podcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bjfogg.com/bootcamp&#34;&gt;Tiny Habits Bootcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.habitify.me&#34;&gt;Habit tracking apps such as Habitify, Checklist+&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Making your goals public to ensure accountability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the goals that I have this year is to get at least one blog post out each week using the above framework.&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>What am I Reading These Days</title>
    <link>/posts/what-am-i-reading-these-days/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/what-am-i-reading-these-days/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;With ~ 21 more books in the bag, the lockdown has turned out to be quite productive. Although I have tried to maintain variety in the kind of books and content that I read, a couple of books that have stood out for me are : Courage To Be Disliked by Ichiro Ishimi and Atomic Habits by James Clear. Going candid on this one:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stating the names and description of the books that I liked and have read thus far:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/18656827-hatching-twitter&#34;&gt;Hatching Twitter&lt;/a&gt; : Politics, betrayal and loads of money. The only thing missing in
this one is infidelity (wait, shayad wo bhi hai), for it to become a superhit movie. Have started stalking Jack Dorsey after this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/34466963-why-we-sleep&#34;&gt;Why We Sleep?&lt;/a&gt;: I&amp;rsquo;m mostly sleep deprived and have been sleeping for less than 6 hours
for quite sometime now, but this book has come across as a  lightning bolt. Never in my life have I recommended someone to rest and sleep properly, but now I do. An eye opener and a must read!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/40499078-let-s-talk-money&#34;&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s Talk Money&lt;/a&gt;: A great starter for those looking for investment advice and save a
few bucks to check off that bucket list. I was already practicing most of the things mentioned in the book and will share the summary soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/40121378-atomic-habits&#34;&gt;Atomic Habits&lt;/a&gt;: One of the best books on habit formation and how we make decisions.
This one is an ultimate guide to become aware about your bad habits and replace them with the good ones. Iska to itna bada fan ban gaya hun k physical copy saath lekar h sota hun.
Next One : B.J. Fogg&amp;rsquo;s : Tiny Habits. Although I&amp;rsquo;ve seen most of his videos&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/50772888-no-filter&#34;&gt;No Filter : The Inside Story of Instagram&lt;/a&gt;: Although I am not a big fan of Instagram
as a product, this book describes how two passionate founders with complementary skill sets decided to
take on Benchmark backed portfolio company. Although the initial vision of Instagram was very different from what it has become now (Zuckerbro taking over again), I just love the fact that both Kevin and Mike left facebook when Zuck tried to take over and dominate the vision of the company. (Kevin Systrom made ~ 800M in the process)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/52346729-big-billion-startup&#34;&gt;Big Billion Startup : The Flipkart Story&lt;/a&gt; : Isme bhi, Twitter level politics, but at
a much smaller scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/8034188-where-good-ideas-come-from&#34;&gt;Steven Johnson : Where Good Ideas Come From&lt;/a&gt;: Well, shower and an evening walk. Hahah. On
a serious note, this goes deeper into how we think and how ideas shape up in our heads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/900.The_Game&#34;&gt;The Game : Neil Strauss&lt;/a&gt;: Welcome to the community of pickup artists. Isn&amp;rsquo;t
this enough to make you read the book?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/44573628-super-pumped&#34;&gt;Super Pumped : The Battle of Uber&lt;/a&gt;: Well, no matter how much all of us criticize/
ridicule Travis Kalanick, he has revolutionized the entire transportation industry through Uber. Iska bhi fan ban gaya hun. Do watch some of his talks on Youtube!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/18197267-don-t-make-me-think-revisited&#34;&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t Make Me Think&lt;/a&gt;: This one made me think a lot. A brief read on how things are
designed on web and mobile in general and best practices that one should follow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/25416321-actionable-gamification&#34;&gt;Gamification&lt;/a&gt;: I was fascinated by how gamification can be used to
influence consumer psychology. Ended up completing a course on Coursera on the same!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/840.The_Design_of_Everyday_Things?ac=1&amp;amp;from_search=true&amp;amp;qid=lZCtNNKZy6&amp;amp;rank=1&#34;&gt;Design of Everyday Things&lt;/a&gt;: The next time you are unable to open that annoying door,
curse its designer, but do not blame yourself. Loved reading this one. Summary coming out soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/44428950-that-will-never-work&#34;&gt;That Will Never Work : Birth of Netflix&lt;/a&gt;: Well, it worked. Netflix par hai.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/368593.The_4_Hour_Workweek&#34;&gt;4-Hour Workweek&lt;/a&gt;: I wish ye jaldi h ho jaye. This suggests you to earn your living by
building specific knowledge (Naval Ravikant&amp;rsquo;s framework) across different domains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/43306206-the-courage-to-be-disliked&#34;&gt;Courage To Be Disliked&lt;/a&gt;: Last, but this one tops the lot. Unlike its name, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t
tell you to do things that make others dislike you, but the fact that others dislike you makes you free. Kaafi deep hai. A must read for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/user/show/54195959-ruchil&#34;&gt;the list&lt;/a&gt; of all the books that I&amp;rsquo;ve read this year. For the remaining half of this year, I intend to read a lot on technology, design, food and health, personal finance, investing and politics (ye zyada nahi). Along with this, I intend to read all the publicly available reports on different industries published by BCG, Mckinsey, CB Insights, VC funds, and create my own personal models and frameworks.&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Getting Your Time Back</title>
    <link>/posts/getting-your-time-back/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/getting-your-time-back/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;A few things that I have started doing to get back my time:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setting an agenda for the meeting with the meeting invite. Agenda less meetings create confusion and
lead to people talking about random things.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;30 mins meeting by default as a calendar invite. This has helped me to close the open points quickly to
free up time for important things.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Putting slots on my calendar when I want to get work done without any distraction. I cancel/
reschedule all meetings if they clash during that time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ending meetings early or declining to attend those that do not provide any insight/actionable. I also
make sure that one of the attendees or I share the actionables from a meeting with all the relevant    stakeholders within 24 hours of the meeting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not attending calls/meetings just because they are on my calendar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While talking feedback and ideas from relevant stakeholders is important, executing low impact ideas may
not be the best use of your time. To avoid this, I try to make the person who proposes an idea think.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;End meetings early if you are done discussing the action items. No point extending the meeting for an
hour just because the calendar invite was for one hour.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You may wish to choose &lt;a href=&#34;https://asana.com/resources/eisenhower-matrix#:~:text=The%20Eisenhower%20Matrix%20is%20a,the%20tasks%20you&#39;ll%20delete.&#34;&gt;Eisenhover Matrix&lt;/a&gt; to prioritise your work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Strong Opinions Loosely Held - 2021</title>
    <link>/posts/strong-opinions-loosely-held---2021/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/strong-opinions-loosely-held---2021/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bobsutton.typepad.com/my_weblog/2006/07/strong_opinions.html&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Strong opinions, weakly held&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; is one of the frameworks used to deal with an uncertain future and yet, still move forward. It is one of the tools to become aware and have the courage to act on your knowledge, but also have the humility to doubt what we know. It is a framework that I use to prevent myself from seeing and hearing only the things that I like and discard others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Being ruthlessly honest with yourself&lt;/strong&gt; : Whenever we feel disappointed or despondent in life, we
tend to blame either the triggers or the circumstances or both (if they are one and the same thing). But while building our hypothesis about why we feel the way we do, we forget about our actions. Example that comes to my mind right now is &amp;ldquo;I could not do X, because of Y&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;I did X, because of Y&amp;rdquo;. Rarely does the Y in this statement involve us. Being self - critical and self - aware is as important as caring about oneself.
This pertains to a long held debate between Freudian and Adlerian psychology. Freud&amp;rsquo;s idea is that a person&amp;rsquo;s psychic wounds, disappointments, feelings cause his/her present unhappiness whereas Adler&amp;rsquo;s view states that we are not determined by our experiences, but by the meaning we give them . Read more about this &lt;a href=&#34;https://sipreads.com/the-courage-to-be-disliked/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. To quote Elon Musk : &amp;ldquo;A well thought out critique of whatever you are doing is as valuable as gold&amp;rdquo;. Hence, seeking constant feedback about your skills, behaviour, and conduct from your friends, acquaintance and family members is a great way to identify the area of improvements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;What&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;How&amp;rdquo; are equally important&lt;/strong&gt; : This will come really handy while implementing the first
point. More often than not, we come across situations when we have to work with someone we do not like or when we are required to give feedback to someone. Imagine working with that one colleague of yours whom you absolutely despise or rehearsing a difficult conversation you have been planning to have with your close friend (about a thing that he/she annoys you with).In such situations, the one thing that I make sure of is communicating my feedback while keeping a check on how I communicate the same.
Knowing that &amp;ldquo;what&amp;rdquo; is something that the other person might not like, working on the &amp;ldquo;how&amp;rdquo; helps soften the blow. The intention here should not be to hurt the other person, but to communicate your feedback and help the other person improve on those areas. If he/she takes the feedback in a positive spirit and is willing to change, you have helped someone to grow personally/professionally. If he/she is not willing to budge and is not self - aware about his/her strengths/weaknesses, see how he/she reacts to point 1. You might be able to change someone&amp;rsquo;s World view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Giving and Seeking Advice&lt;/strong&gt; : Reject most advice. As per &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ScottAdamsSays?ref_src=twsrc%5Egoogle%7Ctwcamp%5Eserp%7Ctwgr%5Eauthor&#34;&gt;Scott Adams&lt;/a&gt;, follow systems
and not goals. Most people (including your friends and family members) are sharing their lottery numbers, which were applicable to them, but may not be applicable to you. There is definitely something to be learnt from them, but we can&amp;rsquo;t take the exact same advice and map it onto our circumstances. That may turn out to be detrimental. The best people that I&amp;rsquo;ve known and worked with read everything, listen to everyone, and ignore all of it. Seeking a 360 degree feedback helps them to clarify the problem, but not the solution. These folks already have their personal model of how to apply things to their situation and they do not hesitate to discard all information. People will always offer advice if you seek one (on topics they have absolutely no idea about such as career,investments,and even relationships), but it is you who has to face the consequences. Start asking people to put some amount of money on the line or have some skin in the game, and see how their advice changes. One great book to read on this topic : &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/36064445-skin-in-the-game?from_search=true&amp;amp;from_srp=true&amp;amp;qid=XW6mDhxbYM&amp;amp;rank=1&#34;&gt;Skin in the Game&lt;/a&gt;. You can choose to discard whatever I&amp;rsquo;ve written in this blog post if my advice does not align with your model (have one if you already don&amp;rsquo;t).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Questioning More&lt;/strong&gt;: Our Worldview is formed mainly from what others have told us. Most things that we
identify as true have been told to us by our parents, friends and media. We never bother to question them and form our worldview around these. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Five_whys&#34;&gt;&amp;lsquo;Five Whys&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt; is one of the frameworks that one can use to question things. You will stop at one of the three things when you keep questioning a particular statement or belief:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Endless series of Why&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Circular reasoning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An axiom&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am really looking forward to read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/44245196-the-great-mental-models&#34;&gt;The Great Mental Models&lt;/a&gt; to go deeper into this topic&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The abundance problem&lt;/strong&gt; : Ancient struggles involved scarcity. Modern struggles are struggles that
involve abundance. People in previous generations were always looking out for food, entertainment, and resources which are abundant in the modern economy. In the modern economy, we are over - exposed to almost everything and a human brain is not designed to take the click bait headline news at the current rate. Teams of statisticians and programmers are working out of Silicon Valley to make sure that you spend more time on these social media and news platforms. The most powerful people of this generation are not politicians, but the developers who are writing the algorithms for social media platforms such as Facebook, Instagram, Twitter, TikTok and Snapchat. One great tool that I&amp;rsquo;ve found to better handle this problem is &lt;a href=&#34;https://freedom.to&#34;&gt;Freedom&lt;/a&gt;. Do check it out! Additionally, saying &amp;ldquo;no&amp;rdquo; as a default response and putting a price to my time has also been very helpful to navigate the abundance issue.Too much socialising might turn out to be the biggest problem of this generation(transitioning one). The next generation IMO will learn to deal with these click bait platforms and ads way better than the current one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Words from the man himself : &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=J54k7WrbfMg&#34;&gt;Chamath Palihapitiya&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Embracing Boredom&lt;/strong&gt; : Mastery is never an accident. You can win the lottery and become rich
overnight, but no one has ever mastered their craft by chance. Whether we are talking about athletes, artists, or academics, the story is the same. If you want to fulfill your potential then you must practice a specific skill for a long time with remarkable consistency. Of course, whenever “experts” share stories about successful people they often leave out a key ingredient of the story. How, exactly, do top performers fall in love with boredom? Perhaps more importantly, how can you fall in love with boredom when you&amp;rsquo;re trying to build a habit that you know you should do, but you don&amp;rsquo;t really want to do. Success is often found by practicing the fundamentals that everyone knows they should be doing, but they find too boring or basic to practice routinely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Valuing friends and relationships&lt;/strong&gt; : The answers to all great questions are paradoxical in nature.
Believing that life is a single player game is okay, but having friends and relationships (and valuing them) to help you navigate difficult circumstances in life is extremely important (while keeping point 3 in mind). Asking the meaning of life and &amp;ldquo;Why am I here&amp;rdquo; is something that we all do. The real beauty lies not in the answer, but in the question itself. Each one of us should look to complete this sentence &amp;ldquo;I exist because&amp;hellip;.&amp;rdquo; instead of asking &amp;ldquo;Why do I exist?&amp;rdquo;. Ask &amp;ldquo;where can I contribute&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;what excites me&amp;rdquo; instead of &amp;ldquo;what is the meaning of life&amp;rdquo;. Do watch this &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3qHkcs3kG44&#34;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; if you want to dig deeper into this topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: I will keep expanding this list.&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Launching a Course on Venture Capital 101</title>
    <link>/posts/a-course-on-venture-capital-copy/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/a-course-on-venture-capital-copy/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;VC is a black box. It is a tightly knit community and this makes it really hard to know the inner workings of a VC fund. It is one thing to know about VC through blogs and books and another through a group of people who have been there, done that!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are some of the most common remarks that I&amp;rsquo;ve come across when speaking to most folks who aspire to break into Venture capital. From those in B - schools to those working in corporates, getting into a Venture Capital firm seems a far fetched dream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I entered Venture Capital with the expectation of helping founders build scalable products, but was given a reality check once I got to know the inner workings of the fund. Why would a founder who has spent somewhere between 2 - 10 years take my advice in building the product?  The best way to know how to build a scalable product is to build one yourself. I exited the world of Venture Capital to be a part of product building myself and with the expectation to make a return after gaining foundational skillsets in my arsenal so that I can be of enough value to the founders later in my career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that being said, a stint at a VC fund teaches you a number of things. The first and most important one being selfless. One needs to be selfless while reaching out to the founders and empathise with them. While there are enough smart folks around, founders are the ones with courage. They are the ones who dream big; who provide employment to millions of individuals. VCs cannot exist without such founders, but founders can thrive without VCs! Some of the other skills that one picks during a stint at a VC firm are structured thinking, discipline, relationship building (networking being a fancy word used for this), and building, refining intuition pertaining to different sectors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To ensure that more folks do not repeat the mistakes that we&amp;rsquo;ve made, we are launching a course on Venture Capital 101. The objective of this course is to familiarise VC aspirants with how a VC firm functions and help them get a stint at one. We do not guarantee a job out of this course and hence, are only interested in speaking those who wish to learn about Venture Capital. You can find the details about the course &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.notion.so/Course-Structure-VC-101-0ba0ab2cc7164295b0cba7691c4b6a26&#34;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we may not have a large investment portfolio , we have ambition. If you are working in a VC firm or on ex - VC who would like to contribute in teaching, get in touch with us. We need more hands!&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Habit Stacking Tools</title>
    <link>/posts/habit-stacking-tools/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/habit-stacking-tools/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;Some of my friends asked me to detail out the tools/platforms that I use to form and stick to my daily habits. Listing some of them down here :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A. &lt;strong&gt;Note - Taking&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://evernote.com/&#34;&gt;Evernote&lt;/a&gt; : Everything new that I come across goes into Evernote. I use 7 - 10 different accounts with each account having a different purpose such as writing, online learning, book summaries, designing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.notion.so/&#34;&gt;Notion&lt;/a&gt; : While some of the notebooks are same as that on Evernote, I use Notion when I’m using Desktop or on web. Notion is a place where all my notes are structured so that I can pull info. on any topic anytime.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gingerlabs.com/&#34;&gt;Notability&lt;/a&gt; : One of the best apps for taking notes. The experience of writing on a paper using a pen/pencil is unbeatable. I use Notability on iPad and iPhone along with Apple Pencil and compile all of my notes on Notion at the end of each week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.google.android.keep&amp;amp;hl=en_IN&amp;amp;gl=US&#34;&gt;Google Keep&lt;/a&gt; : Everything high level/strategic goals here&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.whatsapp.com/?lang=en&#34;&gt;Whatsapp&lt;/a&gt; : The best note - taking app out there. I have 15 - 20 different groups where I share notes to myself and subsequently, put it all on Notion at the end of each week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B. Reading&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://outreadapp.com/&#34;&gt;Outread&lt;/a&gt; : This is one of the best apps that can help you read at 500 wpm with quality retention. Highly recommend this one.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://speechify.com/&#34;&gt;Speechify&lt;/a&gt; : I use Speechify to read articles that I find online at 400wpm - 500wpm. Not the best product out there as it does not help one to bucketize the articles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.amazon.kindle&amp;amp;hl=en_IN&amp;amp;gl=US&#34;&gt;Kindle&lt;/a&gt; : I use Kindle on rare occasions as it does not have speed reading tracker built into it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/&#34;&gt;GoodReads&lt;/a&gt; : I summarise all my books on Goodreads so that others can go through my summaries if they do not have enough time to read the book. In addition to this, Goodreads is one of my go - to book discovery platforms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C. &lt;strong&gt;Focus and Time Tracking&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.forestapp.cc/&#34;&gt;Forest&lt;/a&gt; : The best app out there to implement the Pomodoro technique. Unfortunately, it is not available for Mac&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://flowapp.info/&#34;&gt;Flow&lt;/a&gt; : Use this to implement Pomodoro while working on the Mac&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://freedom.to/&#34;&gt;Freedom&lt;/a&gt; : One of the best investments I’ve ever made this year. Freedom disconnects you from the internet for as long as you want.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/calendar/about/&#34;&gt;Google Calendar&lt;/a&gt; : I put everything on Google calendar and ensure that I review it every week. The objective is to know where you are spending your time and maximise productivity. You’d be surprised to know how conveniently you end up wasting your time on things that you despise.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;D. &lt;strong&gt;Habit Tracking&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.habitify.me/&#34;&gt;Habitify&lt;/a&gt; : List down all the habits that you want to implement. Habitify will make sure that you get atleast one notification stating “0/10 habits completed today”. That notification is a game changer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/momentum/laookkfknpbbblfpciffpaejjkokdgca?hl=en&#34;&gt;Mometum&lt;/a&gt; : Momentum is a Google Chrome extension that replaces new tab page with a personal dashboard featuring to-do, weather, and inspiration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;E. &lt;strong&gt;Health and Fitness&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.pepkit.ssg&amp;amp;hl=en_IN&amp;amp;gl=US&#34;&gt;Step Set Go&lt;/a&gt; : I review the number of steps walked on SSG everyday&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.googleadservices.com/pagead/aclk?sa=L&amp;amp;ai=DChcSEwiEyOn_94vvAhWUMysKHUUHB8EYABAIGgJzZg&amp;amp;ohost=www.google.com&amp;amp;cid=CAESQOD2KY7U0HT8nt4tmqEfXbn6V3OTTuG8kPiJY-7avVbAY8VlPgo_rUFC3SdWYwP49anX7XQJS5OU-MWcXFB3mRs&amp;amp;sig=AOD64_1ZRqdPtVAEysTOlSdCVdNwga6u7A&amp;amp;q&amp;amp;adurl&amp;amp;ved=2ahUKEwiOt9__94vvAhVReH0KHQ3jDMkQ0Qx6BAgaEAE&#34;&gt;Fibit Versa 2&lt;/a&gt; : Getting a Fitbit health tracker today. I hope it does justice to its hype&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wakingup.com/&#34;&gt;Waking Up&lt;/a&gt; : In terms of content, Waking Up »» Headspace. Peace! The coolest part is that you get access to all its premium features without paying. How? Just write an email to their team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;F. &lt;strong&gt;Design&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://procreate.art/&#34;&gt;Procreate&lt;/a&gt; : I’m still a noob at Procreate; the objective is to be great by the end of this year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.figma.com/&#34;&gt;Figma&lt;/a&gt; : Still early in my journey to master Figma. Figma is one of the most used and talked about tools within the design community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tool for writing a Comic book&lt;/strong&gt; : Still in the exploration mode. Any suggestion will be appreciated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;G. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://23ruchil.github.io/Blog/&#34;&gt;This Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than anything else, this blog is a reminder to myself. A reminder to re-read my notes and share my learnings with others over the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Personal OKRs 2021</title>
    <link>/posts/personal-okrs-2021/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/personal-okrs-2021/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://axiomatic-diver-1c4.notion.site/e7ea574ebafd492fa927b9beb3256766?v=5627b3e927104714a69351d36e303194&#34; title=&#34;Personal OKRs 2021&#34;&gt;Personal OKRs 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Everything is a Product</title>
    <link>/posts/everything-is-a-product/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/everything-is-a-product/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;This realisation came to me after reading the biographies of Michael Jordan and Leonardo Da Vinci. Some of the VCs and Product Folks in Silicon Valley also subscribe to this thought. They treat themselves and their careers as that of professional athletes. According to them, the way you conduct yourself, the way you eat, your personal journal or as a matter of fact, your fingernails are nothing but mini - products. They see these attributes as features and a part of a bigger product i.e. themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stripe employees treat documentation as a part of their product development process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next question that one should ask : What does it mean for anything to be a product? Well, it means that it can be broken down into smaller chunks conceptually. Each detail can be worked upon and can be made better so that when all the pieces are reconnected, the picture looks significantly better than what it was. A few examples :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A. Treating reading as a product&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Objectives :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To increase the reading speed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To retain the read material better&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KPIs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reading Speed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Performance on a retention test&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Processes that affect the KPIs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Device used while reading i.e. Kindle/Mobile/Tablet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Background music (if any)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Environment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Posture . . . Countless other details&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B. Treating your diet as a product&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Objectives : To eat healthy and ensure that you do not gain weight because of your diet&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KPIs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Calorie intake&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other quantifiable metrics that I am not aware of&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Processes that affect the KPIs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A diet chart&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time of the day when the meal is consumed . . . Countless other details&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From your Instagram page to how you mentor someone, everything is a product. You are a professional athlete who’s a product!&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Delhi Rant</title>
    <link>/posts/delhi-rant/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/delhi-rant/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;I’ve stayed in Delhi - NCR for ~ 1.5 years now (since September 2019) and came back to Delhi after 14 years (after 2005). Now that I look back, there are certain observations that worry me about Delhi - Gurgaon culture. Listing them down here :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overt celebration of &lt;strong&gt;eat-sleep-repeat&lt;/strong&gt; culture : The common phrase that I hear most people use is : “ I don’t want to think too much and just chill”. While it is perfectly fine to do so, you have lost the right to complain about your problems. Every third person here has an opinion on some of the most pressing issues such as education, poverty and pollution, but I wonder what they are doing about it. These issues will not be solved by &lt;strong&gt;eat-sleep-repeat&lt;/strong&gt; culture. Put in the effort first to form an opinion and do your bit towards solving the problem. If you are not doing so, please stop complaining.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Forming World views through Bollywood movies and TV shows such as Friends&lt;/strong&gt; : While I agree that some of the shows (such as Friends) and movies are a delight to watch, doesn’t mean that you expect the same things to happen in your life. One needs to have the lens of objectivity on while watching such content. It is a script written by a professional whose end goal is to either increase the TRP or sales of subscription. Bollywood is one of the biggest ceilings of this country IMO. More on this &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/balajis/status/1350065743035985922&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; .“Let me make the songs of a nation, and I care not who makes its laws”. Song writers and movie directors are doing their job, we need to do ours. This &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.in/Amusing-Ourselves-Death-Discourse-Business/dp/014303653X&#34;&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; might come handy if you want to dig deeper into this topic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fluff over substance :&lt;/strong&gt; Most folks that I’ve met here come across as extremely pretentious and unauthentic. North Star for such people is to play the status game while forgetting that they do not have substance. You can only go so far with “fake it till you make it” attitude. Self - awareness as a trait is limited in supply in this part of this country .&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that being said, there are some good things about Delhi such as food, which I will miss. The above pointers are based on my personal experiences and opinions of some of my close friends. You may choose to disagree and form your opinion/experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>What Does It Take to Build a Successful Consumer Brand in India?</title>
    <link>/posts/what-does-it-take-to-build-a-successful-consumer-brand-in-india/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/what-does-it-take-to-build-a-successful-consumer-brand-in-india/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://firesideventures.com&#34;&gt;Fireside Ventures&lt;/a&gt; (a consumer focussed fund) closed their second fund worth $118 Million three days ago. This comes at a time when people in India (my parents included) are willing to try out new products and give challenger brands a try. As India&amp;rsquo;s retail market evolves, modern trade (likes of LeMarche) is set to account for 15% (from 8%) of the overall distribution whereas online retail is expected to account for 5% (currently at ~ 3%). A few questions that I had in mind while observing this upsurge were why now? What has changed? Why is it so easy to start a consumer brand? I read a number of reports and spoke to 60+ founders in my quest to find the answers. This blog post is to detail out my findings :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.&lt;strong&gt;Rise of the &amp;lsquo;Millennials&amp;rsquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;India will have 500M+ millennial consumers (age 22-37) by 2021 with a total consumption expenditure of $350B+. Millennials bring strong brand affinity, seek instant gratification, are not averse to change and are risk takers while purchasing. They want new experiences, a sense of individualism and nonconformity. They spend an average of 17 hours per week online across various mediums. Majority of millenials are first time employees and are more financially independent than their predecessor generation. With significant shift towards millennials, the consumer brand landscape is expected to change in favour of new-age challenger brands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.&lt;strong&gt;Rising Aspirations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As millennials do not wish to commit and own things, they are spending the residual income to try out newer brands, seek new experiences. The desire to get that &amp;rsquo;like&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;comment&amp;rsquo; on Facebook, Instagram and be amongst the early adopters is one of the strongest driving forces behind this behaviour. &amp;lsquo;Access trumps ownership&amp;rsquo; - this seems to be the motto of millennials and Gen - Z.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3.&lt;strong&gt;Distribution Channels&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Channels such as e-commerce, modern trade, assisted commerce, direct-to-consumer are providing more power to the consumers who are now able to access goods &amp;amp; services from remote locations. With a reach of more than 19,000 pincodes in India, most large consumer brands have adopted online distribution. I remember speaking to an ambitious founder who is currently running 100+ Cr apparel business along with his wife and most of their sales come from E - commerce platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4.&lt;strong&gt;Ease of Getting the Product Manufactured&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While building the sectoral thesis, I was so fascinated by the concept of building brands that I strongly considered building one on my own in the footwear category. One of my friends is a huge fan of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vibram&#34;&gt;Vibram Furoshiki&lt;/a&gt; shoes and we both wanted to make more people try it out. Upon locking the concept, finding contract manufacturers who could build the product out was extremely easy. Indiamart was the answer! It has a huge database of manufacturers who can manufacture the product based on your specifications. The hardest part was negotiating for MOQs as most manufacturers were looking at 10,000 units as the first lot size and this required a significant upfront investment :(&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking back, I&amp;rsquo;m glad that we did not decide to go forward and didn&amp;rsquo;t give into our naivety as we were not aware about certain challenges within this segment. You can read more about them &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.notion.so/Rise-of-Indian-D2C-Brands-a75d57e92a17472c89fa103263576f5a&#34;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5.&lt;strong&gt;Building a Brand Story&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of all the vanilla parameters, one that stood out in majority of the brands was their story. Brands such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/tailorandcircus/?hl=en&#34;&gt;Tailor and Circus&lt;/a&gt;  and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/sleepyowlcoffee/?hl=en&#34;&gt;Sleepy Owl&lt;/a&gt;  have done a phenomenal job at building a story around their products. They have a story that they communicate to their fans and make sure that they stick to it across all communication channels. How do they communicate these stories?
Social Media! Nobody could have imagined getting such a loyal following and quantifying it a decade ago. But because of the adoption of social media platforms (especially Instagram), the new age brands have arrived!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brand Categories&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.&lt;strong&gt;Fashion and Apparel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three most important things that customers prefer while selecting any apparel product are :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Style/ Design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quality of the material used&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.&lt;strong&gt;Food and Beverage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taste&lt;/strong&gt; remains to be the strongest differentiator when it comes to customer preference within the F&amp;amp;B category. No matter how well packaged your product is and who endorses the product, if it tastes bad, the expectation to have your customer buy the product again is unfair. Some of the categories that are currently being disrupted are :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Healthy Snacking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Babyfood (Brand sensitivity being one of the biggest challenges as one instance of a bad press can ruin the brand image)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pet food&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time/Convenience as a value proposition. e.g. Instant coffee mix&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3.&lt;strong&gt;Personal Care&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do not have a strong thesis for this sector, but if you are looking to start your own brand within this category, you may refer to this &lt;a href=&#34;https://yourstory.com/smbstory/personal-care-indian-brands-entrepreneurs-soap-shampoo-kimrica-bare-anatomy-medimix-natures-essence-sacred-salts&#34;&gt;link.&lt;/a&gt; One category that has seen quite an upsurge is men&amp;rsquo;s grooming. Companies such as The Man Company and Ustraa have become the &amp;ldquo;poster brands&amp;rdquo; of Indian personal care space. With that being said, dental care still remains to be an ignored category and has seen no disruption since years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Challenges and Opportunities for Disruption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.&lt;strong&gt;High MOQs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As most manufacturers ask for MOQs of about 5,000 - 10,000 units, testing the product out without raising/investing a significant capital still remains the biggest challenge for building a consumer brand in India. There will be a proliferation in the number of brands coming out of India if the founders are able to create an MVP as easily as running an experiment online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.&lt;strong&gt;Unorganised Distribution&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because modern trade contributes a significantly lower % of the overall retail, distribution remains the toughest task that lies ahead of any founder venturing out in the consumer segment. It takes ~ 2 years to ensure that your product reaches the popular outlets (modern and general trade) of major cities in India. Setting up distribution also requires you to pay upfront costs to the Modern Trade outlets and it is in general a very capital intensive game. While it is convenient to use jargons such as &amp;lsquo;D2C&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;online brand building&amp;rsquo;, the true value cannot be unlocked without streamlining distribution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3.&lt;strong&gt;Data and Personalisation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While most brands do take customer feedback during the product development process, they have no way to identify the end consumer (for offline segment) and hence, can&amp;rsquo;t personalise the product as per the user needs. As of today, Pepsi doesn&amp;rsquo;t know the details of the customers who opened the cap of its bottle. Imagine if Pepsi/Coke could know this and offer a personalised drink as per your needs that you could order from its website. This is where the true disruption lies according to me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Personal Take&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unless the time to distribution and personalisation is solved (as mentioned in the challenges above), I do not intend to venture out in the consumer brand category.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kalaari Capital&amp;rsquo;s report : T20 consumerism. I contributed to this report and you can buy it on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scribd.com/document/407597572/Consumer-Brands-1-Kalaari-Document&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; link&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The New Indian : One of the best reports I&amp;rsquo;ve read till date : &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bcg.com/en-in/publications/2017/marketing-sales-globalization-new-indian-changing-consumer&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reimagining FMCG in India : &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bcg.com/en-in/publications/2017/marketing-sales-globalization-new-indian-changing-consumer&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Acknowledgments&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Founders of all the brands who took the time out to speak with me&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My colleagues and mentors at Kalaari&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Getting Rich Without Getting Lucky</title>
    <link>/posts/getting-rich-without-getting-lucky/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/getting-rich-without-getting-lucky/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;This is a summary of the framework used by Naval Ravikant to create order in chaos. Summarizing everything that I have learnt from his blogposts and podcasts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wealth vs Money vs Status&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seek wealth, not money or status. Wealth is having assets that earn while you sleep. Money is how we transfer time and wealth. Status is your place in the social hierarchy. Status is a zero sum game so,   ignore those who enjoy playing this game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Investing and Owning a Piece of a Business&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Invest in equity through public markets or through angel investment or by owning some equity in your
company. The likelihood of becoming insanely rich (net worth greater than Rs. 100 Cr.) by trading your time or by earning salary is extremely low. You must own equity — a piece of a business — to gain financial freedom. A few mediums to get started with investing : &lt;a href=&#34;https://angel.co&#34;&gt;AngelList&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.crowdcube.com&#34;&gt;Crowdcube&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mutual_fund&#34;&gt;Mutual Funds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monika Halal&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.in/s?k=lets+talk+money&amp;amp;adgrpid=58389672949&amp;amp;ext_vrnc=hi&amp;amp;gclid=EAIaIQobChMIzdb25v_76gIVDSQrCh2PSAQoEAAYAiAAEgLqNPD_BwE&amp;amp;hvadid=426078221670&amp;amp;hvdev=c&amp;amp;hvlocphy=1007765&amp;amp;hvnetw=g&amp;amp;hvqmt=e&amp;amp;hvrand=5468676216733939630&amp;amp;hvtargid=kwd-330135955363&amp;amp;hydadcr=23639_1979266&amp;amp;tag=googinhydr1-21&amp;amp;ref=pd_sl_7uqirjrj4i_e&#34;&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s Talk Money&lt;/a&gt; is a good starting point. Having an active and diversified portfolio is the key to success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Building Specific Knowledge&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specific knowledge is the knowledge that you cannot be trained for. If society can train you, it can train someone else, and replace you. Specific knowledge is found by pursuing your genuine curiosity and passion rather than whatever is hot right now. Building specific knowledge will feel like play to you but will look like work to others. When specific knowledge is taught, it’s through apprenticeships, not schools. Specific knowledge is often highly technical or creative. It cannot be outsourced or automated. Arming yourself with specific knowledge gives you &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;leverage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; and building a fortune requires leverage. Which takes me to the next point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Building Leverage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Business leverage comes from capital, people, and products with no marginal cost of replication (code and media).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Capital: Capital means money. To raise money, apply your specific knowledge, with accountability, and show resulting good judgment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People: Labor means people working for you. It’s the oldest and most fought-over form of leverage. Labor leverage will impress your parents, but don’t waste your life chasing it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Products: Code &amp;amp; Media. The Internet has massively broadened the possible space of careers. Most people haven’t figured this out yet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Types of Leverage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Permissioned Leverage: Capital and labor are permissioned leverage. Everyone is chasing capital, but someone has to give it to you. Everyone is trying to lead, but someone has to follow you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Permissionless Leverage: Product (Code and media) are permissionless leverage. They’re the leverage behind the newly rich. You can create software and media that works for you while you sleep. An army of robots is freely available — it’s just packed in data centers for heat and space efficiency. Use it. If you can’t code, write books and blogs, record videos and podcasts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Set and enforce an &lt;strong&gt;aspirational personal&lt;/strong&gt; hourly rate. If fixing a problem will save less than your
hourly rate, ignore it. If outsourcing a task will cost less than your hourly rate, outsource it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Know when you are lucky&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More often than not, we attribute things beyond our control to &amp;ldquo;being lucky&amp;rdquo;. Naval Ravikant has bucketised luck into four different types:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blind Luck/Dumb Luck : Well, this is sheer dumb luck.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Luck that comes to you through persistence – “fortune favors the bold”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spotted luck – “chance favors the prepared mind”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Luck that finds you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last three types of luck come from building specific knowledge. One will enjoy a greater share of dumb luck if he/she possesses specific knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it for now!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Best of Masters of Scale</title>
    <link>/posts/best-of-masters-of-scale/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/best-of-masters-of-scale/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;Below is the list of podcasts from Masters of Scale series that I found the most engaging and insightful. I finished listening to all its episodes last year. This is for those who are short on time and wondering where to start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mastersofscale.com/luis-von-ahn/&#34;&gt;A Masterclass in Outsourcing with Luis von Ahn&lt;/a&gt;  (Duolingo)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/open-or-closed-answer-is-both-w-joi-ito-mit-media-lab/id1227971746?i=1000436867368&#34;&gt;Open or closed with Joe Ito :&lt;/a&gt; A podcast on community building&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mastersofscale.com/ben-chestnut-the-case-for-bootstrapping/&#34;&gt;The case for Bootstrapping with Ben Chestnut&lt;/a&gt; (Mailchimp)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mastersofscale.com/tobi-lutke-be-a-platform/&#34;&gt;Be a platform with Tobi Lütke&lt;/a&gt; (Shopify)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mastersofscale.com/peter-thiel-escape-the-competition/&#34;&gt;Escape the competition with Peter Thiel&lt;/a&gt; (Needs no introduction)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mastersofscale.com/reed-hastings-culture-shock/&#34;&gt;Why culture matters with Reid Hastings&lt;/a&gt; (Netflix)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/bonus-10-new-rules-for-big-career-changes-graduation/id1227971746?i=1000442249696&#34;&gt;New rules for big career changes with Jordan Harbinger&lt;/a&gt; : The best podcast that I found on mapping your career trajectory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mastersofscale.com/eric-ries/&#34;&gt;Build, Measure, Learn with non other than Eric Ries&lt;/a&gt; (Lean Startup)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/id1227971746?i=1000456865058&#34;&gt;How to set the drumbeat with Jeff Weiner&lt;/a&gt; (LinkedIn - LinkedIn)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mastersofscale.com/mark-zuckerberg-imperfect-is-perfect/&#34;&gt;Imperfect is perfect with Mark Zuckerberg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mastersofscale.com/reid-hoffman-make-everyone-a-hero-part-two/&#34;&gt;Reid Hoffman Story : Part 2 - Make everyone a hero&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mastersofscale.com/mariam-naficy-the-money-episode/&#34;&gt;Raise more than you need with Mariam Naficy&lt;/a&gt; (Minted)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mastersofscale.com/ellen-kullman/&#34;&gt;4 core principles of crisis management&lt;/a&gt; (Ellen Kullman)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/ray-dalio-how-to-embrace-conflict/id1227971746?i=1000457863860&#34;&gt;How to embrace conflict with Ray Dalio&lt;/a&gt; : This is my personal favourite&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mastersofscale.com/aneel-bhusri-the-elusive-formula-for-great-hiring/&#34;&gt;The elusive formula for great hiring with Aneel Bhusri&lt;/a&gt; (Workday)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/79-how-to-master-your-emotions-w-sam-harris/id1227971746?i=1000506611995&#34;&gt;How to Master Emotion with Sam Harris&lt;/a&gt;. He also has an amazing app called &lt;a href=&#34;https://wakingup.com&#34;&gt;Waking Up&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/building-bridges-to-scale-w-kinds-daniel-lubetzky/id1227971746?i=1000500934868&#34;&gt;Building bridges to scale with Daniel Lubetzky&lt;/a&gt; (Kind)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/73-wikipedias-jimmy-wales-to-scale-find-the-right-values/id1227971746?i=1000494572313&#34;&gt;To scale find the right values with Jimmy Wales&lt;/a&gt; (Wikipedia)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mastersofscale.com/john-foley/&#34;&gt;How to turn sceptics into fans with John Foley&lt;/a&gt; (Peloton)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Speed Reading</title>
    <link>/posts/speed-reading/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/speed-reading/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;Back in January, 2019, I came across a technique called “Speed Reading” on one of Tim Ferris’ videos. I was so intrigued by it that not only did I start “reading about speed reading” a lot, I also started practicing the same tirelessly. Since then, I have almost doubled my reading speed with increased retention and have started to summarise all the books that I read on Evernote (Will share them all and make it accessible to everyone by the end of this year). The next question that should come to your mind is what the hell is “speed reading” and how do I use it to increase my reading speed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us get ourselves acquainted with a few terminologies to get started and know more:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purpose&lt;/strong&gt; : Defining the purpose about why you are reading a book helps you to focus and keep you persistent in order to finish the book. Purpose is valuable because it helps us determine what we want to get out of reading. Once we know, we can inspect the text to see if it will meet our goal. If it does not, a great deal of time has been saved right off the bat. So, what is a good way to inspect a written piece to see if it meets a given purpose? Tell yourself this while reading a book : “I am reading this book to learn money-saving strategies that will help me grow my business.” “I am reading this novel to prepare for tomorrow’s literature discussion”. Sure, developing a purpose takes time, but very little time. It shouldn’t take longer than a few seconds to one minute to state a clear, meaningful objective. The short time that is spent will, in turn, help you get more from the reading, which will, ultimately, save considerably more time in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Power of Preview&lt;/strong&gt; : Preview is one of the most important steps you can take to improve your reading speed and the type of comprehension. That’s because previewing gives the mind a framework of what will be discussed. This helps the mind understand information that will be presented and how it will be organized. Humans are by no means perfect. Countless quotes speak of our erroneous nature, such as “To err is human”. One reason is that the mind doesn’t necessarily respond to what is happening in real time but to what it thinks is going to happen. In other words, the mind is continually making predictions about the future.To remember all this, use the acronym T.H.I.E.V.E.S: • Title • Headings • Introduction • Every word in bold, underline, quote, and italics • Visuals Aids • End of Chapter Questions • Summary/Conclusion. Therefore, spend no more than 45 seconds to 5 minutes on this step. Typically, this means 45 seconds to 1 minute for shorter items like articles and reports, and 3 to 5 minutes for lengthier ones, such as books and manuals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Change Styles&lt;/strong&gt; : Don’t assume that all written works must be read in the same manner or at the same speed. It is okay to vary reading approach based on the material.Let’s start with technical manuals, which often present detailed instructions and procedures that must be carefully followed. This makes each line of text extremely important.The same approach applies to legal documents, annual reports, write-ups, and policies. These types of documents are better read in their entirety and given full attention and focus. Similarly, it’s sensible to slow down if you have to teach the material to someone else. Even a love letter or poem might be worth slowing down for, so you can enjoy the prose in the way the writer intended. It goes without saying that the more detailed and complete awareness you seek, the slower and more attentively you should read. If the text is challenging, read slowly. The same applies if the topic is new, unfamiliar, or if it is something you really want or need to remember. On the other hand, if the content proves boring, familiar, or easy to read, process, and digest, feel free to increase speed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Space Reading&lt;/strong&gt; : The eye has the ability to process an image or object both as a whole and as a collection of individual parts.When looking at a friend’s face, for example, the eyes and mind process the face as a whole rather than looking at individual parts, such as eyes, mouth, nose, and all the other minute features. This allows you to recognize the friend immediately. At the same time, if you wanted to focus on the individual features, you could do that as well.Though, what would happen if you did focus on a single feature of your friend, such as an eyelash, nostril, or dimple? Narrowing vision to such a minute detail would hinder the ability to recognize the person. Such a restricted focus would require scanning other parts of the face and then putting all those parts together in order to recognize that individual. This is how most of us read; we narrow our focus to each word or letter.This is not an effective way to read since, as you now know, the eyes and mind have the ability to see and process much more in a single glance. The solution, therefore, is to not focus on single words but rather to expand visual awareness and see groups of words at one time. This is the natural way the mind absorbs information from sight.There are two ways to look at groups of words. The first method, called space reading which directs you to avoid looking at the words you are reading, but rather at the spaces in between the words. That’s right—at the spaces between words!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chunking&lt;/strong&gt; : The second technique to look at a group of words rather than single ones is called “chunking”. Chunking opens line sight to capture more words in a single glance. The eyes are not set on a single word of a sentence, but instead, on a block, or of chunk, of words in that sentence. You look at a chunk, move to another chunk, then another, and so on. The key to this technique is not to grab words at random but to grab combinations that form a phrase.You might like both, finding that space reading works better with certain types of material, while chunking works better with others, which is perfectly acceptable. Whichever you prefer, refrain from using both techniques at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Removing Subvocalization&lt;/strong&gt; : Subvocalization is the act of pronouncing every word that is read. When subvocalizing, you either say words out loud, hear them spoken in your mind, or move your lips to their pronunciation. Any one of these acts is subvocalizing. Subvocalization greatly reduces the speed at which you read by adding an unnecessary step, or steps, to your reading. In addition to seeing the word, you are also hearing and/or speaking it. We might assume the material we were reading was causing that boredom, but in reality, the cause was simply the sound of our inner voice!Subvocalization is a behavior that starts when we first learn to read, because we are taught (blame the teachers) to read phonetically. We read out loud to connect the right sound to the right word. This is necessary for the brain to learn the words and develop associations with those words. Once we become fluent, we stop reading out loud but continue the phonetic process. We either start whispering these sounds in our mind or begin moving our lips so others can’t hear us. Most people continue reading this way for the rest of their lives, hearing the little voice in the back of their mind and moving their lips to that voice.As beneficial as it is to silence the inner narrator though, it’s not easy. As you learned, it takes time and effort to break long-lasting habits. Nonetheless, the following suggestions reduce the difficulty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Close your mouth when reading : Keeping the mouth closed disengages these processes, thus preventing you from saying the words you urge to verbalize.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read faster than speech : Read at a fast-enough pace where you simply cannot pronounce words or think about their sounds. Humans speak one word at a time and not three or four.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hum : Another option involves humming. Hum a tune, a song, or a basic melody. Humming works because it preoccupies the vocal cords, so that you can’t speak or whisper any words. Humming also drowns out the voice in your head, along with any distracting noise in the immediate environment. If, for example, you are reading around noisy neighbors or loud machinery, humming can replace those annoying sounds with something more soothing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Music : The last and most popular option to break the subvocalization habit is to listen to music. Play it loud enough so that you can’t hear yourself think, because if you can’t hear yourself think, you won’t be able to hear yourself.Research shows that music without words or lyrics, such as classical, instrumental, or electronic music, are the best options for reading. Lyrics in a song compete with words in a text for the mind’s attention. Without lyrics, extraneous words aren’t getting in the way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fixation&lt;/strong&gt; : Though fixation sounds like a complex psychological disorder, it is simply the length of time the eyes stop and rest on a subject. Anytime we look at something, our eyes still themselves. This pause, called fixation, is the eyes’ ability to stop moving so they can focus. If they didn’t do this, everything in life would be a blur. Fixation occurs during reading as well. When we read, our eyes stop and fix on words to see them clearly. They don’t stop for long, but they do, indeed, stop with each and every word. This quick pause gives the eyes an opportunity to pick up the text. As the eyes look at a word, they fixate. To look at the next word, they jump. Fixation also reduces reading comprehension. Meaning is easier to pull from groups of words than from individual words or even single letters. We falsely assume that slower reading means better comprehension. This may be true in some cases, but in most cases, the factors causing slower reading also cause lower comprehension. If you read slowly and still struggle with comprehension, you are likely to fixate too much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The question that now arises is how to reduce fixations. The answer : Space reading and chunking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Regression&lt;/strong&gt; : Regression is the act of reading the same text multiple times. Regression reduces comprehension. Our minds take meaning from what we just read to help us understand what we are about to read. By skipping back to a previous sentence,paragraph, or section, we can’t help but lose track of the point that was being currently made. So, returning to a passage after regression, you may have forgotten what was just read, making it difficult to understand what you are about to read.Most importantly, regression breaks flow, and speed reading is all about flow. It’s about syncing the pace of the eyes to the rhythm of the mind. As the eyes see words, the mind processes them. As soon as the mind finishes processing one set of words, the eyes pick up a new set. Overall, regression doubles, or even triples, reading time and may even result in better comprehension.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Visual Range&lt;/strong&gt; : Visual range is the ability to see objects beyond your direct line of focus. When looking at something in front of you, it’s easy to see that object because the eyes are set directly on it. It’s difficult to capture details on either side of the object unless you move your eyes.We use peripherals more often than you might think. Whenever we try to look at someone without them knowing, we employ peripheral vision.If you’ve never worked on expanding peripheral range, chances are that it isn’t very wide. Therefore, the number of extra words it can capture is limited. If that’s the case, then in addition to training yourself to use the peripheral while reading, you also want to widen it. Widening the peripheral vision further increases the eyes’ capacity to capture words from both the left and right corners. Developing this is a key to developing the skill of speed reading. You can widen your peripheral vision through Schultz table. Look at the number in the middle of your screen and write all the numbers in the square down to practice widening your peripheral vision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m almost on the verge of completing 21 books (will share summaries of each one of them on my blog soon) till June, 2020 using the techniques mentioned above. It’s your time to put the information and techniques to use!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy reading!&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>What is your superpower?</title>
    <link>/posts/what-is-your-superpower-copy/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/what-is-your-superpower-copy/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
    src=&#34;https://manassaloi.com/assets/img/no_filter.png&#34; 
    alt=&#34;image&#34; 
     /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In one of the excerpt from the book No Filter: The Inside Story of Instagram, Kevin Systorm explains to Ashton Kutcher why Instagram blew up. It was not because of network effects. There were no network effects on day 1. It was not because of celebrity users. It was not because they rode on Twitter and Facebook graph of users. All of these happened later. Like most B2C products, it started as a single player use case: &lt;strong&gt;How to make your photos more beautiful, and shareable&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To quote one of my seniors, &amp;ldquo;I have been thinking about the concept of superpowers a lot. Brian Norgard is known for talking about giving your users superpowers. The ability to super like a person on a dating app is a superpower. And Norgard’s advice is to monetize by charging for these super powers, which is what most dating apps do. But I think the superpower concept can be extended even further. Instead of a normal feature vs monetizable superpower feature, think of how you can give ordinary users super powers though your product&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listed below are other superpowers that I think can make you a superhero in the 21st century. Perhaps, a few business ideas for future entrepreneurs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speedreading : Helping users read 500 - 1000 wpm with ~ 90% retention&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to learn and write code quickly (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/44770129-ultralearning&#34;&gt;Ultralearning model by Scott H. Young&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to understand and create design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to let users network (Different from LinkedIn in the sense that the network is a community
rather than just a number)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apps that let users meditate deeply&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saying &amp;ldquo;no&amp;rdquo; without feeling guilty&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Critical reasoning : Thinking from first priciples&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Financial literacy and maximizing ROI through investments in equities and public markets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The most important skill of the 21 st century : &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/learn/learning-how-to-learn&#34;&gt;Learning how to learn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Personal OKRs 2020</title>
    <link>/posts/personal-okrs-2020/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/personal-okrs-2020/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://axiomatic-diver-1c4.notion.site/3acaabebd8e04c899e32b9da6c0a5e76?v=0510c7d736ef4aba9a6cd2e0c52e2c5a&#34; title=&#34;Personl OKRs 2020&#34;&gt;Personal OKRs 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Seek to Understand Before Trying to be Understood</title>
    <link>/posts/seek-to-understand-before-trying-to-be-understood/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/seek-to-understand-before-trying-to-be-understood/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;People are just either not that interested in what you&amp;rsquo;re saying, or they are too focused on their own agenda. It&amp;rsquo;s ridiculous to see two people acting like they can’t really hear each other — by choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &amp;ldquo;The Significance Principle,&amp;rdquo; authors Les Carter and Jim Underwood posit that we should listen past where the other person has finished. We should even pause before answering. Let them get their point, their story, their compliment, and even their criticism out. Completely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, before preparing your response, ask more about what they said. Get engaged. Understand what and why.
Seeking real understanding affirms the other person and what they have to say. That&amp;rsquo;s what they want. That&amp;rsquo;s what we all want — to be understood, valued and affirmed. What if you seek to understand but others don&amp;rsquo;t? Two things come to mind. One person truly listening is generally better than none. More important, one person listening generally leads to two people listening. Let’s be honest, if I honor you with my ears, you’ll be more likely to reciprocate. Others learn the habit through our example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ability to hear is a gift. The willingness to listen is a choice. Putting yourself in others&amp;rsquo; shoes and being empathetic is a very important life skill (a critical part of my job as a part of the product community). I&amp;rsquo;ve failed at doing this multiple times and have pestered my friends when I should have just tried to understand the other person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contextualizing this to dating and relationships (The hardest part)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hardest thing in a conflict is to separate the person and the points he/she is making.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is easier said than done and I have failed many times in the past to make this separation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we are engaged in a heated discussion with someone we tend to listen more with the intent of replying, than to understand his/her point of view. We bring things from the past and use them to fight in the present&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We let our preconceived notions about the person cloud our judgement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best thing to do in such a situation is to take a pause and ask yourself whether you are fighting the person or the points he/she is making. And respond to his/her points than his/her behavior (be it past or present). If you have been hurt by his/her way of speaking, something he/she did in the past, you can always bring that up later when the main discussion has ended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this way you will prevent fights from getting dragged on and on, and also take the decision which is best for your relationship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some resources that might come handy while dealing with such situations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Books: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/71730.Nonviolent_Communication&#34;&gt;Nonviolent Communication: A Language of Life&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/15014.Crucial_Conversations&#34;&gt;Crucial Conversations: Tools for Talking When Stakes Are High&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Articles: &lt;a href=&#34;https://firstround.com/review/our-6-must-reads-for-cutting-through-conflict-and-tough-conversations/&#34;&gt;Best reads on Firstround to deal with conflicts&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/the-year-of-the-looking-glass/5-hard-questions-to-ask-yourself-during-a-conflict-f4a91bab347a&#34;&gt;5 hard questions to ask yourself during a conflict&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@ameet/the-5-principles-of-good-argument-63d394ca3051&#34;&gt;How to make a good argument&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@joulee/5-steps-for-disagreeing-effectively-9d745ce0dbb4&#34;&gt;5 steps for Disagreeing Effectively&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Thinking in Pomodoros</title>
    <link>/posts/thinking-in-pomodoros-copy/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/thinking-in-pomodoros-copy/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;Last week (week from 24th May - 31st May) has turned out to be the most productive week in my life. Not that I have cut down on my side gigs or changed my priorities, but a simple addition of an age old technique called Pomodoro has changed the way I have started to think about time. Here’s how I see the difference :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Old Me&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me list down what I am supposed to do today and complete today’s To - Dos. I’ll go through the list one by one and then reward myself at the end of the day with an episode of “House of Lies” or reply to some of my Whatsapp messages. But there is something inherently evil with this strategy which is “not defining your stop losses”. As soon as I find my flow in one of the activities in my To - Do list, I lose track of time and can only complete ~ 50% of the assigned tasks on any given day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The New Me&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Defining the activities on and outside my To - Do list as Pomodoros.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grocery Shopping - 1 Pomodoro&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reading Books - 5 Pomodoros&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Having a chat with my family : 1 Pomodoro&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Office Work : 22 Pomodoros&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interacting with my family and friends over the weekend : 2 Pomodoros&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only has thinking in Pomodoros made me more productive, but also helped me do a lot more work in a lot less time. The reason for this is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;25 mins of focussed attention that makes me much more productive as compared to dragging things for hours with decreasing productivity. This leads to nothing, but an increased production of Adenosine in my body.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Doing more activities and putting a hard stop to a particular activity after completing the assigned Pomodoros.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Taking 7 minute breaks in which I practice playing Harmonica (Well, it makes me feel relaxed and obsess over my Harmonica tunes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
    <title>Differentiating Yourself Through Social Media</title>
    <link>/posts/differeniating-yourself-through-social-media/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <guid>/posts/differeniating-yourself-through-social-media/</guid>
    <description>
        &lt;p&gt;Increasing number of users are spending their time online and are using social media tools to express themselves. Amidst this, can the activities (posts/likes/comments) performed by people on social media be used to hire candidates for different job profiles? I see this as a great way to differentiate candidates from others in cases where they have similar educational backgrounds, skill sets, and resumes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We put ourselves out there whenever we post something, like/comment on a post, or update our Goodreads account with the latest book that we’ve read. Every activity that we perform online conveys some or the other aspect about us. I feel that the reliance on social media to filter applicants will increase with time and will be used to differentiate similar candidates, especially to determine cultural fit (something on the lines of Klout Score, but more focussed towards determining cultural fit instead of influence) . Not limiting to jobs, activities on social media will also be used to filter university applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, some of the platforms and parameters that these institutions(universities, corporate firms, insurance companies, etc.) will use to determine the quality of the candidates are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GoodReads : Number of books, subject/discipline the candidate is interested in&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twitter : Tweets posted by the user, relevance of the Tweets to the job, relevance of the people followed by the applicant to the job&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LinkedIn : Frequency of articles posted by the users, relevance of the post to the job, relevance of the people followed by the applicant to the job&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instagram : Pages liked, relevance of the people followed by the applicant to the job, relevance of pictures posted by the applicant to know his/her interests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Especially during these unprecedented times, when jobs for some of the major sectors have disappeared and when most of us are liking those cat videos, differentiating yourself and posting stuff relevant to your professional interests might come handy for securing your dream job in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To conclude, I’ll turn up the volume by saying that choosing the right social media platform is similar to chosing your peers. If done right, it can do wonders!&lt;/p&gt;

    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
