<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Productivity on Ruchil Sharma</title>
    <link>/categories/productivity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Productivity on Ruchil Sharma</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/productivity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>So You Want to Form New Habits?</title>
      <link>/posts/so-you-want-to-form-new-habits/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/so-you-want-to-form-new-habits/</guid>
      <description>Creating positive habits takes more than just willpower. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen by itself as it is more science than art. It requires constant re-evaluation of where you are spending time, people whom you are spending time with and your environment. Last year, I spent significant amount of time researching this and stumbled upon different books, bootcamps and blog posts that have proven to be really helpful in planning my day and subsequently, my week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Your Time Back</title>
      <link>/posts/getting-your-time-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/getting-your-time-back/</guid>
      <description>A few things that I have started doing to get back my time:
Setting an agenda for the meeting with the meeting invite. Agenda less meetings create confusion and lead to people talking about random things. 30 mins meeting by default as a calendar invite. This has helped me to close the open points quickly to free up time for important things. Putting slots on my calendar when I want to get work done without any distraction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Your Time Back</title>
      <link>/posts/revamping-my-blog-post-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/revamping-my-blog-post-theme/</guid>
      <description>A few things that I have started doing to get back my time:
Setting an agenda for the meeting with the meeting invite. Agenda less meetings create confusion and lead to people talking about random things. 30 mins meeting by default as a calendar invite. This has helped me to close the open points quickly to free up time for important things. Putting slots on my calendar when I want to get work done without any distraction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Habit Stacking Tools</title>
      <link>/posts/habit-stacking-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/habit-stacking-tools/</guid>
      <description>Some of my friends asked me to detail out the tools/platforms that I use to form and stick to my daily habits. Listing some of them down here :
A. Note - Taking
Evernote : Everything new that I come across goes into Evernote. I use 7 - 10 different accounts with each account having a different purpose such as writing, online learning, book summaries, designing. Notion : While some of the notebooks are same as that on Evernote, I use Notion when I’m using Desktop or on web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speed Reading</title>
      <link>/posts/speed-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/speed-reading/</guid>
      <description>Back in January, 2019, I came across a technique called “Speed Reading” on one of Tim Ferris’ videos. I was so intrigued by it that not only did I start “reading about speed reading” a lot, I also started practicing the same tirelessly. Since then, I have almost doubled my reading speed with increased retention and have started to summarise all the books that I read on Evernote (Will share them all and make it accessible to everyone by the end of this year).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking in Pomodoros</title>
      <link>/posts/thinking-in-pomodoros-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/thinking-in-pomodoros-copy/</guid>
      <description>Last week (week from 24th May - 31st May) has turned out to be the most productive week in my life. Not that I have cut down on my side gigs or changed my priorities, but a simple addition of an age old technique called Pomodoro has changed the way I have started to think about time. Here’s how I see the difference :
The Old Me
Let me list down what I am supposed to do today and complete today’s To - Dos.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
