<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>To-Self on Ruchil Sharma</title>
    <link>/tags/to-self/</link>
    <description>Recent content in To-Self on Ruchil Sharma</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/to-self/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Identify Your Echochamber</title>
      <link>/posts/identify-your-echochamber/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/identify-your-echochamber/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After 4 years, I have started using Social Media platforms again. While I had no difficulties posting (except stories on Instagram), there are certain observations and patterns that I have started to come across different social media platforms. Detailing them out here :&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1.&lt;strong&gt;Twitter&lt;/strong&gt; Tagline from a user&amp;rsquo;s perspective : I am smart and &amp;ldquo;intellectual&amp;rdquo; as well. Please koi&#xA;meri bhi sun lo. From replying on Elon Musk&amp;rsquo;s and Balajis Tweets to posting random threads on why you should&#xA;switch to Signal, Twitter is an echo - chamber of wanna be &amp;ldquo;intellectuals&amp;rdquo;. While Twitter does&#xA;help one get deep insights into any topic from some of the most credible individuals, it is also&#xA;an echo - chamber of people who are &amp;ldquo;faking&amp;rdquo; it till they make it. There&amp;rsquo;s nothing right/wrong in&#xA;this. Well, who doesn&amp;rsquo;t like to have a million followers! But what I&amp;rsquo;ll really appreciate is a following built on one&amp;rsquo;s substance, skills and not copy pasted Tweets, or networking.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strong Opinions Loosely Held</title>
      <link>/posts/strong-opinions-loosely-held-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/strong-opinions-loosely-held-copy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bobsutton.typepad.com/my_weblog/2006/07/strong_opinions.html&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Strong opinions, weakly held&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; is one of the frameworks used to deal with an uncertain future and yet, still move forward. It is one of the tools to become aware and have the courage to act on your knowledge, but also have the humility to doubt what we know. It is a framework that I use to prevent myself from seeing and hearing only the things that I like and discard others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Everything is a Product</title>
      <link>/posts/everything-is-a-product/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/everything-is-a-product/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This realisation came to me after reading the biographies of Michael Jordan and Leonardo Da Vinci. Some of the VCs and Product Folks in Silicon Valley also subscribe to this thought. They treat themselves and their careers as that of professional athletes. According to them, the way you conduct yourself, the way you eat, your personal journal or as a matter of fact, your fingernails are nothing but mini - products. They see these attributes as features and a part of a bigger product i.e. themselves.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Delhi Rant</title>
      <link>/posts/delhi-rant/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/delhi-rant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve stayed in Delhi - NCR for ~ 1.5 years now (since September 2019) and came back to Delhi after 14 years (after 2005). Now that I look back, there are certain observations that worry me about Delhi - Gurgaon culture. Listing them down here :&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Overt celebration of &lt;strong&gt;eat-sleep-repeat&lt;/strong&gt; culture : The common phrase that I hear most people use is : “ I don’t want to think too much and just chill”. While it is perfectly fine to do so, you have lost the right to complain about your problems. Every third person here has an opinion on some of the most pressing issues such as education, poverty and pollution, but I wonder what they are doing about it. These issues will not be solved by &lt;strong&gt;eat-sleep-repeat&lt;/strong&gt; culture. Put in the effort first to form an opinion and do your bit towards solving the problem. If you are not doing so, please stop complaining.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Forming World views through Bollywood movies and TV shows such as Friends&lt;/strong&gt; : While I agree that some of the shows (such as Friends) and movies are a delight to watch, doesn’t mean that you expect the same things to happen in your life. One needs to have the lens of objectivity on while watching such content. It is a script written by a professional whose end goal is to either increase the TRP or sales of subscription. Bollywood is one of the biggest ceilings of this country IMO. More on this &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/balajis/status/1350065743035985922&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; .“Let me make the songs of a nation, and I care not who makes its laws”. Song writers and movie directors are doing their job, we need to do ours. This &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.in/Amusing-Ourselves-Death-Discourse-Business/dp/014303653X&#34;&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; might come handy if you want to dig deeper into this topic.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fluff over substance :&lt;/strong&gt; Most folks that I’ve met here come across as extremely pretentious and unauthentic. North Star for such people is to play the status game while forgetting that they do not have substance. You can only go so far with “fake it till you make it” attitude. Self - awareness as a trait is limited in supply in this part of this country .&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With that being said, there are some good things about Delhi such as food, which I will miss. The above pointers are based on my personal experiences and opinions of some of my close friends. You may choose to disagree and form your opinion/experiences.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seek to Understand Before Trying to be Understood</title>
      <link>/posts/seek-to-understand-before-trying-to-be-understood/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/seek-to-understand-before-trying-to-be-understood/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;People are just either not that interested in what you&amp;rsquo;re saying, or they are too focused on their own agenda. It&amp;rsquo;s ridiculous to see two people acting like they can’t really hear each other — by choice.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In &amp;ldquo;The Significance Principle,&amp;rdquo; authors Les Carter and Jim Underwood posit that we should listen past where the other person has finished. We should even pause before answering. Let them get their point, their story, their compliment, and even their criticism out. Completely.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
