<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Education on Ruchil Sharma</title>
    <link>/tags/education/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Education on Ruchil Sharma</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/education/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>So you want to setup your own blog</title>
      <link>/posts/so-you-want-to-setup-your-own-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/so-you-want-to-setup-your-own-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If a cool blogpost template is stopping you from writing more, the problem is most definitely not that cool template. Writing more requires writing a lot in the initial phases. Same goes with writing well. It’s about turning on your mental faucet to let the ideas flow freely, which in turn, leads to quality content. If you really think a cool blog website will help you cross your motivation barrier and push you to start writing more, then maybe this post can help. I greatly admire Tomasz Tunguz’s writings , and my website draws inspiration from his. Here’s a breakdown of how I launched my blog:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Launching a Course on Venture Capital 101</title>
      <link>/posts/a-course-on-venture-capital-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/a-course-on-venture-capital-copy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;VC is a black box. It is a tightly knit community and this makes it really hard to know the inner workings of a VC fund. It is one thing to know about VC through blogs and books and another through a group of people who have been there, done that!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These are some of the most common remarks that I&amp;rsquo;ve come across when speaking to most folks who aspire to break into Venture capital. From those in B - schools to those working in corporates, getting into a Venture Capital firm seems a far fetched dream.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
