<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recommendations on Ruchil Sharma</title>
    <link>/tags/recommendations/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Recommendations on Ruchil Sharma</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/recommendations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Excerpts from Man’s Search for Meaning</title>
      <link>/posts/excerpts-from-mans-search-for-meaning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/excerpts-from-mans-search-for-meaning/</guid>
      <description>I recently finished the book Man’s Search for Meaning which was kept for a long time on my digital bookshelf. I found the following timeless excerpts the most interesting that I’ll keep with me. Hope you find them interesting too.
On love On Choosing One’s Attitude On the Meaning of Life </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best of Masters of Scale</title>
      <link>/posts/best-of-masters-of-scale/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/best-of-masters-of-scale/</guid>
      <description>Below is the list of podcasts from Masters of Scale series that I found the most engaging and insightful. I finished listening to all its episodes last year. This is for those who are short on time and wondering where to start.
A Masterclass in Outsourcing with Luis von Ahn (Duolingo) Open or closed with Joe Ito : A podcast on community building The case for Bootstrapping with Ben Chestnut (Mailchimp) Be a platform with Tobi Lütke (Shopify) Escape the competition with Peter Thiel (Needs no introduction) Why culture matters with Reid Hastings (Netflix) New rules for big career changes with Jordan Harbinger : The best podcast that I found on mapping your career trajectory Build, Measure, Learn with non other than Eric Ries (Lean Startup) How to set the drumbeat with Jeff Weiner (LinkedIn - LinkedIn) Imperfect is perfect with Mark Zuckerberg Reid Hoffman Story : Part 2 - Make everyone a hero Raise more than you need with Mariam Naficy (Minted) 4 core principles of crisis management (Ellen Kullman) How to embrace conflict with Ray Dalio : This is my personal favourite The elusive formula for great hiring with Aneel Bhusri (Workday) How to Master Emotion with Sam Harris.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
